
words_deutsch_base = [{'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'der Abend',
  'value_de_noun': 'der Abend',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈaːbnt',
  'value_en': 'evening',
  'value_ru': 'вечер'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'aber',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈaːbɐ',
  'value_en': 'but',
  'value_ru': 'но'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'der Rücken',
  'value_de_noun': 'der Rücken',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈrʏkn',
  'value_en': 'back',
  'value_ru': 'спина'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'allgemein',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈalgəmain',
  'value_en': 'general',
  'value_ru': 'общий'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'der Tisch',
  'value_de_noun': 'der Tisch',
  'value_de_trans': 'tɪʃ',
  'value_en': 'table',
  'value_ru': 'стол'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'also',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈalzo',
  'value_en': 'so',
  'value_ru': 'итак'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'alt',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'alt',
  'value_en': 'old',
  'value_ru': 'старый'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'andere',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈandərə',
  'value_en': 'another',
  'value_ru': 'другой'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Arbeit',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Arbeit',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈarbait',
  'value_en': 'job',
  'value_ru': 'работа'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'arbeiten',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈarbaitn',
  'value_en': 'to work',
  'value_ru': 'работать'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Art',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Art',
  'value_de_trans': 'aːɐt',
  'value_en': 'kind/type',
  'value_ru': 'тип'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'auch',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'aux',
  'value_en': 'also',
  'value_ru': 'также'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'der Flügel',
  'value_de_noun': 'der Flügel',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈflyːgl',
  'value_en': 'wing',
  'value_ru': 'крыло'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'das Auge',
  'value_de_noun': 'das Auge',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈaugə',
  'value_en': 'eye',
  'value_ru': 'глаз'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'der Fuß',
  'value_de_noun': 'der Fuß',
  'value_de_trans': 'fuːs',
  'value_en': 'foot',
  'value_ru': 'ступня'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'beginnen',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'bəˈgɪnən',
  'value_en': 'to begin',
  'value_ru': 'начинать'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Größe',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Größe',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈgrøːsə',
  'value_en': 'size',
  'value_ru': 'размер'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'beide',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈbaidə',
  'value_en': 'both',
  'value_ru': 'оба'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'das Beispiel',
  'value_de_noun': 'das Beispiel',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈbaiʃpiːl',
  'value_en': 'example',
  'value_ru': 'пример'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'bekannt',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'bəˈkant',
  'value_en': 'well-known',
  'value_ru': 'хорошо известный'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'der Geist',
  'value_de_noun': 'der Geist',
  'value_de_trans': 'gaist',
  'value_en': 'spirit',
  'value_ru': 'призрак'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Bereich',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Bereich',
  'value_de_trans': 'bəˈraiç',
  'value_en': 'area/region',
  'value_ru': 'область/район'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'der Wald',
  'value_de_noun': 'der Wald',
  'value_de_trans': 'valt',
  'value_en': 'forest',
  'value_ru': 'лес'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'besonders',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'bəˈzɔndɐs',
  'value_en': 'especially',
  'value_ru': 'особенно'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'besser',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈbεsɐ',
  'value_en': 'better',
  'value_ru': 'лучше'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'das Bild',
  'value_de_noun': 'das Bild',
  'value_de_trans': 'bɪlt',
  'value_en': 'picture',
  'value_ru': 'картина'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Haare',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Haare',
  'value_de_trans': 'ha:rə',
  'value_en': 'hair',
  'value_ru': 'волосы'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'bitte',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈbɪtə',
  'value_en': 'please',
  'value_ru': 'пожалуйста'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'bleiben',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈblaibn',
  'value_en': 'to stay',
  'value_ru': 'оставаться'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'der Blick',
  'value_de_noun': 'der Blick',
  'value_de_trans': 'blɪk',
  'value_en': 'look',
  'value_ru': 'взгляд'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'brauchen',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈbrauxn',
  'value_en': 'to need',
  'value_ru': 'нуждаться'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'bringen',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈbrɪŋən',
  'value_en': 'to bring',
  'value_ru': 'приносить'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'das Buch',
  'value_de_noun': 'das Buch',
  'value_de_trans': 'buːx',
  'value_en': 'book',
  'value_ru': 'книга'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'der Körper',
  'value_de_noun': 'der Körper',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈkœrpɐ',
  'value_en': 'body',
  'value_ru': 'тело'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'danke',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈdaŋkə',
  'value_en': 'thank you',
  'value_ru': 'спасибо'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'dann',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'dan',
  'value_en': 'then',
  'value_ru': 'тогда'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'das Leben',
  'value_de_noun': 'das Leben',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈleːbn',
  'value_en': 'life',
  'value_ru': 'жизнь'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'dass',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'das',
  'value_en': 'that',
  'value_ru': 'что'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'davon',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'daˈfɔn',
  'value_en': 'about it',
  'value_ru': 'об этом'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'denken',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈdεŋkn',
  'value_en': 'to think',
  'value_ru': 'думать'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'denn',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'dεn',
  'value_en': 'because',
  'value_ru': 'потому что'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'der Name',
  'value_de_noun': 'der Name',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈnaːmə',
  'value_en': 'name',
  'value_ru': 'имя'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Hitze',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Hitze',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈhɪtsə',
  'value_en': 'heat',
  'value_ru': 'тепло'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'deutsch',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'dɔytʃ',
  'value_en': 'german',
  'value_ru': 'немецкий'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'dich',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'dɪç',
  'value_en': 'youself',
  'value_ru': 'тебя'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Hand',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Hand',
  'value_de_trans': 'hant',
  'value_en': 'hand',
  'value_ru': 'рука'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'diese',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈdiːzə',
  'value_en': 'these',
  'value_ru': 'эти'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'der Frühling',
  'value_de_noun': 'der Frühling',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈfryːlɪŋ',
  'value_en': 'spring',
  'value_ru': 'весна'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'dort',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'dɔrt',
  'value_en': 'there',
  'value_ru': 'там'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'drei',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'drai',
  'value_en': 'three',
  'value_ru': 'три'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'der Lehrer',
  'value_de_noun': 'der Lehrer',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈleːrɐ',
  'value_en': 'teacher',
  'value_ru': 'учитель'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'durch',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'dʊrç',
  'value_en': 'through',
  'value_ru': 'через/сквозь'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'der Sturm',
  'value_de_noun': 'der Sturm',
  'value_de_trans': 'ʃtʊrm',
  'value_en': 'storm',
  'value_ru': 'буря'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'eben',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈeːbn',
  'value_en': 'just now',
  'value_ru': 'только что'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'eher',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈeːɐ',
  'value_en': 'rather',
  'value_ru': 'скорее'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'eigentlich',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈaigntlɪç',
  'value_en': 'actually',
  'value_ru': 'на самом деле'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'ein',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ain',
  'value_en': 'one',
  'value_ru': 'один'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'einfach',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈainfax',
  'value_en': 'easy',
  'value_ru': 'просто'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'einmal',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈainmaːl',
  'value_en': 'once',
  'value_ru': 'однажды'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'einzeln',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈaintsln',
  'value_en': 'individual',
  'value_ru': 'отде́льный'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'einzig',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈaintsɪç',
  'value_en': 'only',
  'value_ru': 'только'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Eltern',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Eltern',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈεltɐn',
  'value_en': 'parents',
  'value_ru': 'родители'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'das Ende',
  'value_de_noun': 'das Ende',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈεndə',
  'value_en': 'end',
  'value_ru': 'конец'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'entwickeln',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'εntˈvɪkln',
  'value_en': 'to develop',
  'value_ru': 'развивать'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Entwicklung',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Entwicklung',
  'value_de_trans': 'εntˈvɪklʊŋ',
  'value_en': 'development',
  'value_ru': 'разработка'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'er',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'eːɐ',
  'value_en': 'he',
  'value_ru': 'он'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'erhalten',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'εɐˈhaltn',
  'value_en': 'to receive',
  'value_ru': 'получать'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'erkennen',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'εɐˈkεnən',
  'value_en': 'to recognize',
  'value_ru': 'узнавать'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'erklären',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'εɐˈklεːrən',
  'value_en': 'to explain',
  'value_ru': 'объяснять'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'erreichen',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'εɐˈraiçn',
  'value_en': 'to reach',
  'value_ru': 'достигать'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'erscheinen',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'εɐˈʃainən',
  'value_en': 'to appear',
  'value_ru': 'являться'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'erwarten',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'εɐˈvartn',
  'value_en': 'to expect',
  'value_ru': 'ожидать'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'erzählen',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'εɐˈtsεːlən',
  'value_en': 'to tell',
  'value_ru': 'рассказывать'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Sicherheit',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Sicherheit',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈzɪçɐhait',
  'value_en': 'safety',
  'value_ru': 'безопасность'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'etwa',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈεtva',
  'value_en': 'approximately',
  'value_ru': 'приблизительно'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'etwas',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈεtvas',
  'value_en': 'some/something',
  'value_ru': 'что-нибудь'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'fahren',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈfaːrən',
  'value_en': 'to drive',
  'value_ru': 'возить/ездить'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'der Fall',
  'value_de_noun': 'der Fall',
  'value_de_trans': 'fal',
  'value_en': 'case',
  'value_ru': 'случай'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'fallen',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈfalən',
  'value_en': 'to fall',
  'value_ru': 'падать'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Familie',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Familie',
  'value_de_trans': 'faˈmiːliə',
  'value_en': 'family',
  'value_ru': 'семья'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'das Foto',
  'value_de_noun': 'das Foto',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈfoːto',
  'value_en': 'photo',
  'value_ru': 'фото'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'finden',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈfɪndn',
  'value_en': 'to find',
  'value_ru': 'находить'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Folge',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Folge',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈfɔlgə',
  'value_en': 'result',
  'value_ru': 'результат'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'folgen',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈfɔlgn',
  'value_en': 'to follow',
  'value_ru': 'следовать'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Form',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Form',
  'value_de_trans': 'fɔrm',
  'value_en': 'form',
  'value_ru': 'форма'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Frage',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Frage',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈfraːgə',
  'value_en': 'question',
  'value_ru': 'вопрос'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'fragen',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈfraːgn',
  'value_en': 'to ask',
  'value_ru': 'спрашивать'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Frau',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Frau',
  'value_de_trans': 'frau',
  'value_en': 'woman',
  'value_ru': 'женщина'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'frei',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'frai',
  'value_en': 'free',
  'value_ru': 'бесплатный'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'der Freund',
  'value_de_noun': 'der Freund',
  'value_de_trans': 'frɔynt',
  'value_en': 'friend',
  'value_ru': 'друг'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'früh',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'fryː',
  'value_en': 'early',
  'value_ru': 'ранний'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'früher',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈfryːɐ',
  'value_en': 'earlier',
  'value_ru': 'раньше'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'führen',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈfyːrən',
  'value_en': 'to lead',
  'value_ru': 'вести'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'fünf',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'fʏnf',
  'value_en': 'five',
  'value_ru': 'пять'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'für',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'fyːɐ',
  'value_en': 'for',
  'value_ru': 'для'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'ganz',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'gants',
  'value_en': 'whole',
  'value_ru': 'целый'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'gar',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'gaːɐ',
  'value_en': 'at all',
  'value_ru': 'вообще'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Krankenschwester',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Krankenschwester',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈkraŋknʃvεstɐ',
  'value_en': 'nurse',
  'value_ru': 'медсестра'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'gegen',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈgeːgn',
  'value_en': 'against',
  'value_ru': 'против'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'gehen',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈgeːən',
  'value_en': 'to go',
  'value_ru': 'идти'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'das Geld',
  'value_de_noun': 'das Geld',
  'value_de_trans': 'gεlt',
  'value_en': 'money',
  'value_ru': 'деньги'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'gelten',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈgεltn',
  'value_en': 'to be valid',
  'value_ru': 'быть действительным'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'der Tee',
  'value_de_noun': 'der Tee',
  'value_de_trans': 'teː',
  'value_en': 'tea',
  'value_ru': 'чай'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'genau',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'gəˈnau',
  'value_en': 'exact',
  'value_ru': 'точный'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'gerade',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'gəˈraːdə',
  'value_en': 'just',
  'value_ru': 'прямо'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Geschichte',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Geschichte',
  'value_de_trans': 'gəˈʃɪçtə',
  'value_en': 'history',
  'value_ru': 'история'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Gesellschaft',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Gesellschaft',
  'value_de_trans': 'gəˈzεlʃaft',
  'value_en': 'society',
  'value_ru': 'общество'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'das Gesicht',
  'value_de_noun': 'das Gesicht',
  'value_de_trans': 'gəˈzɪçt',
  'value_en': 'face',
  'value_ru': 'лицо'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'glauben',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈglaʊbn',
  'value_en': 'to believe',
  'value_ru': 'верить'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'gleich',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'glaiç',
  'value_en': 'same',
  'value_ru': 'равный'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'der Gott',
  'value_de_noun': 'der Gott',
  'value_de_trans': 'gɔt',
  'value_en': 'God',
  'value_ru': 'Бог'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'groß',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'groːs',
  'value_en': 'big',
  'value_ru': 'большой'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'der Grund',
  'value_de_noun': 'der Grund',
  'value_de_trans': 'grʊnt',
  'value_en': 'reason',
  'value_ru': 'причина'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Gruppe',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Gruppe',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈgrʊpə',
  'value_en': 'group',
  'value_ru': 'группа'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'gut',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'guːt',
  'value_en': 'good',
  'value_ru': 'хорошо'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'haben',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈhaːbn',
  'value_en': 'to have',
  'value_ru': 'иметь'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'halten',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈhaltn',
  'value_en': 'to hold',
  'value_ru': 'держать'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'das Haus',
  'value_de_noun': 'das Haus',
  'value_de_trans': 'haus',
  'value_en': 'house',
  'value_ru': 'дом'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'heißen',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈhaisn',
  'value_en': 'to be called',
  'value_ru': 'называться'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'heute',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈhɔytə',
  'value_en': 'today',
  'value_ru': 'сегодня'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Hilfe',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Hilfe',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈhɪlfə',
  'value_en': 'help',
  'value_ru': 'помощь'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'hier',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'hiːɐ',
  'value_en': 'here',
  'value_ru': 'здесь'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'hinter',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈhɪntɐ',
  'value_en': 'behind',
  'value_ru': 'позади'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'hoch',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'hoːx',
  'value_en': 'high',
  'value_ru': 'высоко'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'ich',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ɪç',
  'value_en': 'I',
  'value_ru': 'я'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Kraft',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Kraft',
  'value_de_trans': 'kraft',
  'value_en': 'force',
  'value_ru': 'сила'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'immer',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈɪmɐ',
  'value_en': 'always',
  'value_ru': 'всегда'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'ja',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'jaː',
  'value_en': 'yes',
  'value_ru': 'да'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'das Jahr',
  'value_de_noun': 'das Jahr',
  'value_de_trans': 'jaːɐ',
  'value_en': 'year',
  'value_ru': 'год'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'jedoch',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'jeˈdɔx',
  'value_en': 'however',
  'value_ru': 'однако'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'jetzt',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'jεtst',
  'value_en': 'now',
  'value_ru': 'сейчас'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'jung',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'jʊŋ',
  'value_en': 'young',
  'value_ru': 'молодой'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'der Osten',
  'value_de_noun': 'der Osten',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈɔstn',
  'value_en': 'east',
  'value_ru': 'восток'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Bevölkerung',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Bevölkerung',
  'value_de_trans': 'bəˈfœlkərʊŋ',
  'value_en': 'population',
  'value_ru': 'население'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'kennen',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈkεnən',
  'value_en': 'to know',
  'value_ru': 'знать'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'das Kind',
  'value_de_noun': 'das Kind',
  'value_de_trans': 'kɪnt',
  'value_en': 'kid',
  'value_ru': 'ребёнок'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'klar',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'klaːɐ',
  'value_en': 'clear',
  'value_ru': 'ясный'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'das Ei',
  'value_de_noun': 'das Ei',
  'value_de_trans': 'ai',
  'value_en': 'egg',
  'value_ru': 'яйцо'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'kommen',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈkɔmən',
  'value_en': 'to come',
  'value_ru': 'приходить'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'das Gras',
  'value_de_noun': 'das Gras',
  'value_de_trans': 'graːs',
  'value_en': 'grass',
  'value_ru': 'трава'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'der Kopf',
  'value_de_noun': 'der Kopf',
  'value_de_trans': 'kɔpf',
  'value_en': 'head',
  'value_ru': 'голова'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'kurz',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'kʊrts',
  'value_en': 'short',
  'value_ru': 'короткий'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'das Land',
  'value_de_noun': 'das Land',
  'value_de_trans': 'lant',
  'value_en': 'country',
  'value_ru': 'страна'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'lang',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'laŋ',
  'value_en': 'long',
  'value_ru': 'длинный'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'lassen',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈlasn',
  'value_en': 'to let/allow',
  'value_ru': 'позволять'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'laufen',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈlaufn',
  'value_en': 'to run',
  'value_ru': 'бежать'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'leicht',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'laiçt',
  'value_en': 'light',
  'value_ru': 'лёгкий'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'lernen',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈlεrnən',
  'value_en': 'to learn',
  'value_ru': 'учиться'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'lesen',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈleːzn',
  'value_en': 'to read',
  'value_ru': 'читать'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Leute',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Leute',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈlɔytə',
  'value_en': 'people',
  'value_ru': 'люди'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'liegen',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈliːgn',
  'value_en': 'to lie',
  'value_ru': 'лежать'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Mauer',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Mauer',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈmauɐ',
  'value_en': 'wall',
  'value_ru': 'стена'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'machen',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈmaxn',
  'value_en': 'to make',
  'value_ru': 'делать'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'der Mann',
  'value_de_noun': 'der Mann',
  'value_de_trans': 'man',
  'value_en': 'man',
  'value_ru': 'мужчина'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'mehr',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'meːɐ',
  'value_en': 'more',
  'value_ru': 'бо́льше'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'mehrere',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'fiːl',
  'value_en': 'several',
  'value_ru': 'несколько'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'das Messer',
  'value_de_noun': 'das Messer',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈmεsɐ',
  'value_en': 'knife',
  'value_ru': 'нож'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'meine',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈmainə',
  'value_en': 'mine',
  'value_ru': 'мой'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'das Rad',
  'value_de_noun': 'das Rad',
  'value_de_trans': 'raːt',
  'value_en': 'wheel',
  'value_ru': 'колесо'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'der Mensch',
  'value_de_noun': 'der Mensch',
  'value_de_trans': 'mεnʃ',
  'value_en': 'person',
  'value_ru': 'человек'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Richtung',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Richtung',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈrɪçtʊŋ',
  'value_en': 'direction',
  'value_ru': 'направление'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Million',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Million',
  'value_de_trans': 'mɪˈlioːn',
  'value_en': 'million',
  'value_ru': 'миллион'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Minute',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Minute',
  'value_de_trans': 'miˈnuːtə',
  'value_en': 'minute',
  'value_ru': 'минута'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'der Rahmen',
  'value_de_noun': 'der Rahmen',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈraːmən',
  'value_en': 'frame',
  'value_ru': 'рамка'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'mit',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'mɪt',
  'value_en': 'with',
  'value_ru': 'с'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'möglich',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈmøːklɪç',
  'value_en': 'possible',
  'value_ru': 'возмо́жный'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Möglichkeit',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Möglichkeit',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈmøːklɪçkait',
  'value_en': 'possibility',
  'value_ru': 'возможность'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'der Monat',
  'value_de_noun': 'der Monat',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈmoːnat',
  'value_en': 'month',
  'value_ru': 'месяц'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'der Morgen',
  'value_de_noun': 'der Morgen',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈmɔrgn',
  'value_en': 'morning',
  'value_ru': 'утро'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'müssen',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈmʏsn',
  'value_en': 'must',
  'value_ru': 'должен'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Mutter',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Mutter',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈmʊtɐ',
  'value_en': 'mother',
  'value_ru': 'мать'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'der Junge',
  'value_de_noun': 'der Junge',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈjʊŋə',
  'value_en': 'boy',
  'value_ru': 'мальчик'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Nacht',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Nacht',
  'value_de_trans': 'naxt',
  'value_en': 'night',
  'value_ru': 'ночь'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'der Schlaf',
  'value_de_noun': 'der Schlaf',
  'value_de_trans': 'ʃlaːf',
  'value_en': 'sleep',
  'value_ru': 'сон'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'neben',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈneːbn',
  'value_en': 'beside',
  'value_ru': 'рядом'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'nehmen',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈneːmən',
  'value_en': 'to take',
  'value_ru': 'брать'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'das Fenster',
  'value_de_noun': 'das Fenster',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈfεnstɐ',
  'value_en': 'window',
  'value_ru': 'окно'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'neu',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'nɔy',
  'value_en': 'new',
  'value_ru': 'новый'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'nicht',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'nɪçt',
  'value_en': 'not',
  'value_ru': 'не'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Meinung',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Meinung',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈmainʊŋ',
  'value_en': 'opinion',
  'value_ru': 'мнение'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Bedeutung',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Bedeutung',
  'value_de_trans': 'bəˈdɔytʊŋ',
  'value_en': 'meaning',
  'value_ru': 'значение'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'noch',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'nɔx',
  'value_en': 'still',
  'value_ru': 'ещё'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Zukunft',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Zukunft',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈtsuːkʊnft',
  'value_en': 'future',
  'value_ru': 'будущее'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Großmutter',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Großmutter',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈgroːsmʊtɐ',
  'value_en': 'grandmother',
  'value_ru': 'бабушка'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'der Anfang',
  'value_de_noun': 'der Anfang',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈanfaŋ',
  'value_en': 'start',
  'value_ru': 'начало'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'das Mädchen',
  'value_de_noun': 'das Mädchen',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈmεːtçən',
  'value_en': 'girl',
  'value_ru': 'девушка'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'obwohl',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ɔpˈvoːl',
  'value_en': 'although',
  'value_ru': 'хотя'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'oder',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈoːdɐ',
  'value_en': 'or',
  'value_ru': 'или'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'offen',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈɔfn',
  'value_en': 'open',
  'value_ru': 'открытый'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'oft',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ɔft',
  'value_en': 'often',
  'value_ru': 'часто'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'das Paar',
  'value_de_noun': 'das Paar',
  'value_de_trans': 'paːɐ',
  'value_en': 'pair',
  'value_ru': 'пара'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'passieren',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'paˈsiːrən',
  'value_en': 'to happen',
  'value_ru': 'случаться'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'politisch',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'poˈliːtɪʃ',
  'value_en': 'political',
  'value_ru': 'политический'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'das Problem',
  'value_de_noun': 'das Problem',
  'value_de_trans': 'proˈbleːm',
  'value_en': 'problem',
  'value_ru': 'проблема'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'das Prozent',
  'value_de_noun': 'das Prozent',
  'value_de_trans': 'proˈtsεnt',
  'value_en': 'percent',
  'value_ru': 'процент'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'der Raum',
  'value_de_noun': 'der Raum',
  'value_de_trans': 'raum',
  'value_en': 'room',
  'value_ru': 'комната'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'das Recht',
  'value_de_noun': 'das Recht',
  'value_de_trans': 'rεçt',
  'value_en': 'law',
  'value_ru': 'закон'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'der Bauch',
  'value_de_noun': 'der Bauch',
  'value_de_trans': 'baux',
  'value_en': 'stomach',
  'value_ru': 'живот'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'richtig',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈrɪçtɪç',
  'value_en': 'right',
  'value_ru': 'правильный'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Rolle',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Rolle',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈrɔlə',
  'value_en': 'role',
  'value_ru': 'роль'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'rot',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'roːt',
  'value_en': 'red',
  'value_ru': 'красный'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Sache',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Sache',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈzaxə',
  'value_en': 'thing',
  'value_ru': 'вещь'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'der Westen',
  'value_de_noun': 'der Westen',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈvεstn',
  'value_en': 'west',
  'value_ru': 'запад'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'schaffen',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈʃafn',
  'value_en': 'to create',
  'value_ru': 'создавать'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'scheinen',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈʃainən',
  'value_en': 'to shine',
  'value_ru': 'светить'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'schlecht',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ʃlεçt',
  'value_en': 'bad',
  'value_ru': 'плохой'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'schließlich',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈʃliːslɪç',
  'value_en': 'in the end',
  'value_ru': 'в конце концов'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'schnell',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ʃnεl',
  'value_en': 'fast',
  'value_ru': 'быстро'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'schon',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ʃoːn',
  'value_en': 'already',
  'value_ru': 'уже'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'schön',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ʃøːn',
  'value_en': 'beautiful',
  'value_ru': 'красивый'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'schreiben',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈʃraibn',
  'value_en': 'to write',
  'value_ru': 'писать'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Schule',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Schule',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈʃuːlə',
  'value_en': 'school',
  'value_ru': 'школа'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'schwer',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ʃveːɐ',
  'value_en': 'difficult',
  'value_ru': 'трудный'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'sehen',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈzeːən',
  'value_en': 'to see',
  'value_ru': 'смотреть'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'sehr',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'zeːɐ',
  'value_en': 'very',
  'value_ru': 'очень'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'der Gast',
  'value_de_noun': 'der Gast',
  'value_de_trans': 'gast',
  'value_en': 'guest',
  'value_ru': 'гость'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Seite',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Seite',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈzaitə',
  'value_en': 'page',
  'value_ru': 'страница'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'sicher',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈzɪçɐ',
  'value_en': 'secure',
  'value_ru': 'безопасный'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Regierung',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Regierung',
  'value_de_trans': 'reˈgiːrʊŋ',
  'value_en': 'government',
  'value_ru': 'правительство'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Nachricht',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Nachricht',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈnaːxrɪçt',
  'value_en': 'message',
  'value_ru': 'сообщение'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'der Sinn',
  'value_de_noun': 'der Sinn',
  'value_de_trans': 'zɪn',
  'value_en': 'sense',
  'value_ru': 'смысл'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'sogar',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'zoˈgaːɐ',
  'value_en': 'even',
  'value_ru': 'даже'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Seele',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Seele',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈzeːlə',
  'value_en': 'soul',
  'value_ru': 'душа'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'sonst',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'zɔnst',
  'value_en': 'otherwise',
  'value_ru': 'в противном случае'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'sowie',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'zoˈviː',
  'value_en': 'as well as',
  'value_ru': 'а так же'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'spät',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ʃpεːt',
  'value_en': 'late',
  'value_ru': 'поздно'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'spielen',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈʃpiːlən',
  'value_en': 'to play',
  'value_ru': 'играть'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Sprache',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Sprache',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈʃpraːxə',
  'value_en': 'language',
  'value_ru': 'язык'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'sprechen',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈʃprεçn',
  'value_en': 'to speak',
  'value_ru': 'говорить'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Stadt',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Stadt',
  'value_de_trans': 'ʃtat',
  'value_en': 'city',
  'value_ru': 'город'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'stark',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ʃtark',
  'value_en': 'strong',
  'value_ru': 'сильный'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'stehen',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈʃteːən',
  'value_en': 'to stand',
  'value_ru': 'стоять'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'das Gehirn',
  'value_de_noun': 'das Gehirn',
  'value_de_trans': 'gəˈhɪrn',
  'value_en': 'brain',
  'value_ru': 'мозг'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'stellen',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈʃtεlən',
  'value_en': 'to place',
  'value_ru': 'ставить'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Straße',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Straße',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈʃtraːsə',
  'value_en': 'street',
  'value_ru': 'улица'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Stunde',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Stunde',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈʃtʊndə',
  'value_en': 'hour',
  'value_ru': 'час'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'suchen',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈzuːxn',
  'value_en': 'to search',
  'value_ru': 'искать'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'das System',
  'value_de_noun': 'das System',
  'value_de_trans': 'zʏsˈteːm',
  'value_en': 'system',
  'value_ru': 'система'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'der Tag',
  'value_de_noun': 'der Tag',
  'value_de_trans': 'taːk',
  'value_en': 'day',
  'value_ru': 'день'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'der Teil',
  'value_de_noun': 'der Teil',
  'value_de_trans': 'tail',
  'value_en': 'part',
  'value_ru': 'часть'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'tragen',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈtraːgn',
  'value_en': 'to carry',
  'value_ru': 'носить'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'treffen',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈtrεfn',
  'value_en': 'to meet',
  'value_ru': 'встречаться'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'das Mittagessen',
  'value_de_noun': 'das Mittagessen',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈmɪtaːkεsn',
  'value_en': 'lunch',
  'value_ru': 'обед'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Tür',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Tür',
  'value_de_trans': 'tyːɐ',
  'value_en': 'door',
  'value_ru': 'дверь'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'das Erlebnis',
  'value_de_noun': 'das Erlebnis',
  'value_de_trans': 'εɐˈleːpnɪs',
  'value_en': 'experience',
  'value_ru': 'опыт'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Uhr',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Uhr',
  'value_de_trans': 'uːɐ',
  'value_en': 'clock',
  'value_ru': 'часы'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'und',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ʊnt',
  'value_en': 'and',
  'value_ru': 'и'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Universität',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Universität',
  'value_de_trans': 'univεrziˈtεːt',
  'value_en': 'university',
  'value_ru': 'университет'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'unter',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈʊntɐ',
  'value_en': 'under',
  'value_ru': 'под'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'das Unternehmen',
  'value_de_noun': 'das Unternehmen',
  'value_de_trans': 'ʊntɐˈneːmən',
  'value_en': 'enterprise',
  'value_ru': 'предприятие'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'der Kunststoff',
  'value_de_noun': 'der Kunststoff',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈkʊnst+ʃtɔf',
  'value_en': 'plastic',
  'value_ru': 'пластик'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'der Vater',
  'value_de_noun': 'der Vater',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈfaːtɐ',
  'value_en': 'father',
  'value_ru': 'отец'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'verlieren',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'fεɐˈliːrən',
  'value_en': 'to lose',
  'value_ru': 'терять'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'der Rauch',
  'value_de_noun': 'der Rauch',
  'value_de_trans': 'raux',
  'value_en': 'smoke',
  'value_ru': 'дым'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'verstehen',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'fεɐˈʃteːən',
  'value_en': 'to understand',
  'value_ru': 'понимать'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'versuchen',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'fεɐˈzuːxn',
  'value_en': 'to try',
  'value_ru': 'пробовать'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'der Zusammenhang',
  'value_de_noun': 'der Zusammenhang',
  'value_de_trans': 'tsuˈzamənhaŋ',
  'value_en': 'context',
  'value_ru': 'контекст'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'der Großvater',
  'value_de_noun': 'der Großvater',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈgroːsfaːtɐ',
  'value_en': 'grandfather',
  'value_ru': 'дедушка'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'vier',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'fiːɐ',
  'value_en': 'four',
  'value_ru': 'четыре'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'voll',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'fɔl',
  'value_en': 'full',
  'value_ru': 'полный'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'der Krieg',
  'value_de_noun': 'der Krieg',
  'value_de_trans': 'kriːk',
  'value_en': 'war',
  'value_ru': 'война'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'das Geschenk',
  'value_de_noun': 'das Geschenk',
  'value_de_trans': 'gəˈʃεŋk',
  'value_en': 'gift',
  'value_ru': 'подарок'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'während',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈvεːrənt',
  'value_en': 'during',
  'value_ru': 'в то время как'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'warum',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'vaˈrʊm',
  'value_en': 'why',
  'value_ru': 'почему'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Verfügung',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Verfügung',
  'value_de_trans': 'fεɐˈfyːgʊŋ',
  'value_en': 'disposal',
  'value_ru': 'постановление'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'das Wasser',
  'value_de_noun': 'das Wasser',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈvasɐ',
  'value_en': 'water',
  'value_ru': 'вода'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'der Weg',
  'value_de_noun': 'der Weg',
  'value_de_trans': 'vεk',
  'value_en': 'way',
  'value_ru': 'путь'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Brücke',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Brücke',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈbrʏkə',
  'value_en': 'bridge',
  'value_ru': 'мост'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'weiß',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'vais',
  'value_en': 'white',
  'value_ru': 'белый'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'weit',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'vait',
  'value_en': 'far',
  'value_ru': 'далёкий'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'weiter',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈvaitɐ',
  'value_en': 'further',
  'value_ru': 'далее'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Welt',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Welt',
  'value_de_trans': 'vεlt',
  'value_en': 'world',
  'value_ru': 'мир, вселенная'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'das Geheimnis',
  'value_de_noun': 'das Geheimnis',
  'value_de_trans': 'gəˈhaimnɪs',
  'value_en': 'secret',
  'value_ru': 'тайна'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'wenn',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'vεn',
  'value_en': 'if/when',
  'value_ru': 'если/когда'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Lage',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Lage',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈlaːgə',
  'value_en': 'location',
  'value_ru': 'расположение'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'werden',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈveːɐdn',
  'value_en': 'to become',
  'value_ru': 'становиться'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'der Wert',
  'value_de_noun': 'der Wert',
  'value_de_trans': 'veːɐt',
  'value_en': 'value',
  'value_ru': 'ценность'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'wichtig',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈvɪçtɪç',
  'value_en': 'important',
  'value_ru': 'важный'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'wie',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'viː',
  'value_en': 'how',
  'value_ru': 'как'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'wieder',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈviːdɐ',
  'value_en': 'again',
  'value_ru': 'опять'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Kirche',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Kirche',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈkɪrçə',
  'value_en': 'church',
  'value_ru': 'церковь'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'wir',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'viːɐ',
  'value_en': 'we',
  'value_ru': 'мы'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'das Dach',
  'value_de_noun': 'das Dach',
  'value_de_trans': 'dax',
  'value_en': 'roof',
  'value_ru': 'крыша'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'das Silber',
  'value_de_noun': 'das Silber',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈzɪlbɐ',
  'value_en': 'silver',
  'value_ru': 'серебро'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'wo',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'voː',
  'value_en': 'where',
  'value_ru': 'где'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Woche',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Woche',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈvɔxə',
  'value_en': 'week',
  'value_ru': 'неделя'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'der Knopf',
  'value_de_noun': 'der Knopf',
  'value_de_trans': 'knɔpf',
  'value_en': 'button',
  'value_ru': 'кнопка'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'wohnen',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈvoːnən',
  'value_en': 'to live',
  'value_ru': 'жить'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'wollen',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈvɔlən',
  'value_en': 'to want',
  'value_ru': 'хотеть'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'das Wort',
  'value_de_noun': 'das Wort',
  'value_de_trans': 'vɔrt',
  'value_en': 'word',
  'value_ru': 'слово'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Zahl',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Zahl',
  'value_de_trans': 'tsaːl',
  'value_en': 'number',
  'value_ru': 'число'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'zehn',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'tseːn',
  'value_en': 'ten',
  'value_ru': 'десять'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'zeigen',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈtsaign',
  'value_en': 'to show',
  'value_ru': 'показывать'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Zeit',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Zeit',
  'value_de_trans': 'tsait',
  'value_en': 'time',
  'value_ru': 'время'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'ziehen',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈtsiːən',
  'value_en': 'to pull',
  'value_ru': 'тянуть'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'die Stimme',
  'value_de_noun': 'die Stimme',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈʃtɪmə',
  'value_en': 'voice',
  'value_ru': 'голос'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'das Bett',
  'value_de_noun': 'das Bett',
  'value_de_trans': 'bεt',
  'value_en': 'bed',
  'value_ru': 'кровать'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'der Nachbar',
  'value_de_noun': 'der Nachbar',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈnaxbaːɐ',
  'value_en': 'neighbor',
  'value_ru': 'сосед'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'zwei',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'tsvai',
  'value_en': 'two',
  'value_ru': 'два'},
 {'dict': 0,
  'dict_type': 'base',
  'value_de': 'zwischen',
  'value_de_noun': '',
  'value_de_trans': 'ˈtsvɪʃn',
  'value_en': 'between',
  'value_ru': 'между'}]

words_deutsch_pronouns = [{'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': '[Ich] verstehe nicht.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их ферштее нихт',
  'phrase_ru': '[Я] не понимаю.',
  'value_de': 'ich',
  'value_de_trans': 'их',
  'value_ru': 'я'},
 {'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': '[Du] bist gut.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду бист гут',
  'phrase_ru': '[Ты] хороший.',
  'value_de': 'du',
  'value_de_trans': 'ду',
  'value_ru': 'ты'},
 {'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': '[Er] lernt schnell.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа леант шнелль',
  'phrase_ru': '[Он] учится быстро.',
  'value_de': 'er',
  'value_de_trans': 'иа',
  'value_ru': 'он'},
 {'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': '[Sie] ist schön.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи ист шён',
  'phrase_ru': '[Она] красивая.',
  'value_de': 'sie',
  'value_de_trans': 'зи',
  'value_ru': 'она'},
 {'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': '[Es] ist weiß.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс ист вайс',
  'phrase_ru': '[Оно] белое.',
  'value_de': 'es',
  'value_de_trans': 'эс',
  'value_ru': 'оно'},
 {'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': '[Wir] essen Brot.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа эссен брут',
  'phrase_ru': '[Мы] едим хлеб.',
  'value_de': 'wir',
  'value_de_trans': 'виа',
  'value_ru': 'мы'},
 {'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Versteht [ihr] alles?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ферштейт иа аллес',
  'phrase_ru': '[Вы] всё понимаете? (множественное число)',
  'value_de': 'ihr',
  'value_de_trans': 'иа',
  'value_ru': 'вы'},
 {'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': '[Sie] sind Russen.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи зинд руссен',
  'phrase_ru': '[Они] русские.',
  'value_de': 'sie',
  'value_de_trans': 'зи',
  'value_ru': 'они'},
 {'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Sind [Sie] Deutscher?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зинд зи дойча',
  'phrase_ru': '[Вы] немец? (вежливая форма)',
  'value_de': 'Sie',
  'value_de_trans': 'зи',
  'value_ru': 'Вы'},
 {'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Komm zu [mir].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'комм цу миа',
  'phrase_ru': 'Подойди ко [мне].',
  'value_de': 'mir',
  'value_de_trans': 'миа',
  'value_ru': 'мне'},
 {'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich sage [dir].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их заге диа',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я говорю [тебе].',
  'value_de': 'dir',
  'value_de_trans': 'диа',
  'value_ru': 'тебе'},
 {'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich helfe [ihm].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хельфе им',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я помогаю [ему].',
  'value_de': 'ihm',
  'value_de_trans': 'им',
  'value_ru': 'ему'},
 {'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Wer hilft [ihr]?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хильфт иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'Кто помогает [ей]?',
  'value_de': 'ihr',
  'value_de_trans': 'иа',
  'value_ru': 'ей'},
 {'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Es gehört [uns].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс гехёрт унс',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это принадлежит [нам].',
  'value_de': 'uns',
  'value_de_trans': 'унс',
  'value_ru': 'нам'},
 {'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Kann ich [euch] helfen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'канн их ойх хельфен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Могу я [вам] помочь?',
  'value_de': 'euch',
  'value_de_trans': 'ойх',
  'value_ru': 'вам'},
 {'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich habe [ihnen] alles gesagt.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе инен аллес гезагт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я [им] всё рассказал.',
  'value_de': 'ihnen',
  'value_de_trans': 'инен',
  'value_ru': 'им'},
 {'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich schreibe [Ihnen] morgen.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их шрайбе инен морген',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я напишу [Вам] завтра. (вежливая форма)',
  'value_de': 'Ihnen',
  'value_de_trans': 'инен',
  'value_ru': 'Вам'},
 {'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Liebst du [mich]?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'либст ду мих',
  'phrase_ru': 'Ты любишь [меня]?',
  'value_de': 'mich',
  'value_de_trans': 'мих',
  'value_ru': 'меня'},
 {'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich liebe [dich]!',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их либе дих',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я люблю [тебя]!',
  'value_de': 'dich',
  'value_de_trans': 'дих',
  'value_ru': 'тебя'},
 {'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Kennst du [ihn]?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'кенст ду ин',
  'phrase_ru': 'Ты знаешь [его]?',
  'value_de': 'ihn',
  'value_de_trans': 'ин',
  'value_ru': 'его'},
 {'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich kenne [sie].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их кенне зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я знаю [её].',
  'value_de': 'sie',
  'value_de_trans': 'зи',
  'value_ru': 'её'},
 {'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich sehe [es].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их зие эс',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я вижу [его]. (что-то среднего рода)',
  'value_de': 'es',
  'value_de_trans': 'эс',
  'value_ru': 'его'},
 {'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie verstehen [uns].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи ферштейн унс',
  'phrase_ru': 'Они понимают [нас].',
  'value_de': 'uns',
  'value_de_trans': 'унс',
  'value_ru': 'нас'},
 {'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich grüße [euch].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их грюсе ойх',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я приветствую [вас]. (множественное число)',
  'value_de': 'euch',
  'value_de_trans': 'ойх',
  'value_ru': 'вас'},
 {'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich muss [sie] warnen.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их мусс зи варнен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я должен [их] предупредить. (множественное число)',
  'value_de': 'sie',
  'value_de_trans': 'зи',
  'value_ru': 'их'},
 {'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich suche [Sie].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их зухе зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я ищу [Вас]. (вежливая форма)',
  'value_de': 'Sie',
  'value_de_trans': 'зи',
  'value_ru': 'Вас'},
 {'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Oh [mein] Gott!',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'о майн готт',
  'phrase_ru': 'О, [мой] Бог!',
  'value_de': 'mein',
  'value_de_trans': 'майн',
  'value_ru': 'мой'},
 {'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Wo ist [dein] Vater?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'во ист дайн фата',
  'phrase_ru': 'Где [твой] отец?',
  'value_de': 'dein',
  'value_de_trans': 'дайн',
  'value_ru': 'твой'},
 {'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das ist [sein] Auto.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас ист зайн ауто',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это [его] машина.',
  'value_de': 'sein',
  'value_de_trans': 'зайн',
  'value_ru': 'его'},
 {'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': '[Ihr] Vater ist Künstler.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа фата ист кюнстла',
  'phrase_ru': '[Её] отец - художник.',
  'value_de': 'ihr',
  'value_de_trans': 'иа',
  'value_ru': 'её'},
 {'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das ist [unser] Haus.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас ист унза хаус',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это [наш] дом.',
  'value_de': 'unser',
  'value_de_trans': 'унза',
  'value_ru': 'наш'},
 {'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Er ist [euer] Sohn.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа ист оя зун',
  'phrase_ru': 'Он [ваш] сын. (множественное число)',
  'value_de': 'euer',
  'value_de_trans': 'оя',
  'value_ru': 'ваш'},
 {'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ist das [Ihr] Fahrrad?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ист дас иа фаррад',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это [Ваш] велосипед? (вежливая форма)',
  'value_de': 'Ihr',
  'value_de_trans': 'иа',
  'value_ru': 'Ваш'},
 {'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Es ist [ihr] Recht.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс ист иа рехт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это [их] право.',
  'value_de': 'ihr',
  'value_de_trans': 'иа',
  'value_ru': 'их'},
 {'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': '[Wer] kann mir helfen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа канн миа хельфен',
  'phrase_ru': '[Кто] может мне помочь?',
  'value_de': 'wer',
  'value_de_trans': 'виа',
  'value_ru': 'кто'},
 {'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': '[Was] macht dein Sohn?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вас махт дайн зун',
  'phrase_ru': '[Что] делает твой сын?',
  'value_de': 'was',
  'value_de_trans': 'вас',
  'value_ru': 'что'},
 {'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': '[Welcher] Wochentag ist heute?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вельха вохентаг ист хойте',
  'phrase_ru': '[Какой] день недели сегодня?',
  'value_de': 'welcher',
  'value_de_trans': 'вельха',
  'value_ru': 'какой'},
 {'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': '[Wessen] Haus ist das?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вессен хаус ист дас',
  'phrase_ru': '[Чей] это дом?',
  'value_de': 'wessen',
  'value_de_trans': 'вессен',
  'value_ru': 'чей'},
 {'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': '[Wem] gehört das Buch?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вим гехёрт дас бух',
  'phrase_ru': '[Кому] принадлежит эта книга?',
  'value_de': 'wem',
  'value_de_trans': 'вим',
  'value_ru': 'кому'},
 {'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': '[Wen] liebst du?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вин либст ду',
  'phrase_ru': '[Кого] ты любишь?',
  'value_de': 'wen',
  'value_de_trans': 'вин',
  'value_ru': 'кого'},
 {'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': '[Niemand] kennt die Antwort.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ниманд кент ди антворт',
  'phrase_ru': '[Никто] не знает ответа.',
  'value_de': 'niemand',
  'value_de_trans': 'ниманд',
  'value_ru': 'никто'},
 {'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': '[Nichts] kann mich aufhalten.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'нихтс канн мих ауфхальтен',
  'phrase_ru': '[Ничто] не может меня остановить.',
  'value_de': 'nichts',
  'value_de_trans': 'нихтс',
  'value_ru': 'ничто'},
 {'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich sehe [kein] Bild.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их зие кайн бильт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я не вижу [никакой] картины.',
  'value_de': 'kein',
  'value_de_trans': 'кайн',
  'value_ru': 'никакой'},
 {'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': '[Keiner] weiß, wo er wohnt.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'кайна вайс, во иа вонт',
  'phrase_ru': '[Никто] не знает, где он живёт.',
  'value_de': 'keiner',
  'value_de_trans': 'кайна',
  'value_ru': 'никто'},
 {'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Spricht [jemand] Russisch?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'шприхт еманд руссиш',
  'phrase_ru': 'Говорит [кто-нибудь] по-русски?',
  'value_de': 'jemand',
  'value_de_trans': 'еманд',
  'value_ru': 'кто-нибудь'},
 {'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Hören Sie [etwas]?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хёрен зи этвас',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы [что-нибудь] слышите?',
  'value_de': 'etwas',
  'value_de_trans': 'этвас',
  'value_ru': 'что-нибудь'},
 {'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kann [jeder].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас канн еда',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это может [каждый].',
  'value_de': 'jeder',
  'value_de_trans': 'еда',
  'value_ru': 'каждый'},
 {'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': '[Solch] eine Chance ist selten.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зольх айне шансе ист зельтен',
  'phrase_ru': '[Такой] шанс редок.',
  'value_de': 'solch',
  'value_de_trans': 'зольх',
  'value_ru': 'такой'},
 {'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': '[Alles] ist gut.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'аллес ист гут',
  'phrase_ru': '[Всё] хорошо.',
  'value_de': 'alles',
  'value_de_trans': 'аллес',
  'value_ru': 'всё'},
 {'dict': '1',
  'dict_type': 'pronouns',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': '[Manche] glauben an Gott.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'манхе глаубен ан готт',
  'phrase_ru': '[Некоторые] верят в Бога.',
  'value_de': 'manche',
  'value_de_trans': 'манхе',
  'value_ru': 'некоторые'}]

words_deutsch_verbs = [{'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich kann Deutsch [sprechen].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их канн дойч шпрехен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я могу [говорить] по-немецки.',
  'value_de': 'sprechen',
  'value_de_trans': 'шпрехен',
  'value_ru': 'говорить'},
 {'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich will [schlafen].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их вилль шлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я хочу [спать].',
  'value_de': 'schlafen',
  'value_de_trans': 'шлафен',
  'value_ru': 'спать'},
 {'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Wir wollen Eis [essen].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа воллен айс эссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Мы хотим [кушать] мороженое.',
  'value_de': 'essen',
  'value_de_trans': 'эссен',
  'value_ru': 'кушать'},
 {'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich werde Wasser [trinken].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде васса тринкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я буду [пить] воду.',
  'value_de': 'trinken',
  'value_de_trans': 'тринкен',
  'value_ru': 'пить'},
 {'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Wir müssen schneller [arbeiten].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа мюссен шнелла арбайтен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Мы должны [работать] быстрее.',
  'value_de': 'arbeiten',
  'value_de_trans': 'арбайтен',
  'value_ru': 'работать'},
 {'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich will Deutsch [lernen].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их вилль дойч леанен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я хочу [изучать] немецкий язык.',
  'value_de': 'lernen',
  'value_de_trans': 'леанен',
  'value_ru': 'изучать'},
 {'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Wir wollen die Wahrheit [wissen].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа воллен ди ваахайт виссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Мы хотим [знать] правду.',
  'value_de': 'wissen',
  'value_de_trans': 'виссен',
  'value_ru': 'знать'},
 {'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich werde einen Brief [schreiben].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде айнен бриф шрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я буду [писать] письмо.',
  'value_de': 'schreiben',
  'value_de_trans': 'шрайбен',
  'value_ru': 'писать'},
 {'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich werde ein Buch [lesen].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде айн бух лизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я буду [читать] книгу.',
  'value_de': 'lesen',
  'value_de_trans': 'лизен',
  'value_ru': 'читать'},
 {'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Kinder müssen [spielen].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'кинда мюссен шпилен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Дети должны [играть].',
  'value_de': 'spielen',
  'value_de_trans': 'шпилен',
  'value_ru': 'играть'},
 {'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich muss nach Hause [gehen].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их мусс нах хаузе геен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я должен [идти] домой.',
  'value_de': 'gehen',
  'value_de_trans': 'геен',
  'value_ru': 'идти'},
 {'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Nach dem Weg [fragen].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'нах дим вег фраген',
  'phrase_ru': '[Спрашивать] дорогу.',
  'value_de': 'fragen',
  'value_de_trans': 'фраген',
  'value_ru': 'спрашивать'},
 {'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'einen Apfel [geben]',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'айнен апфель гебен',
  'phrase_ru': '[давать] яблоко',
  'value_de': 'geben',
  'value_de_trans': 'гебен',
  'value_ru': 'давать'},
 {'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'einen Stock [nehmen]',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'айнен шток немен',
  'phrase_ru': '[брать] палку',
  'value_de': 'nehmen',
  'value_de_trans': 'немен',
  'value_ru': 'брать'},
 {'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'einen Witz [hören]',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'айнен виц хёрен',
  'phrase_ru': '[слушать] шутку',
  'value_de': 'hören',
  'value_de_trans': 'хёрен',
  'value_ru': 'слушать'},
 {'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich werde ein Lied [singen].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде айн лид зинген',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я буду [петь] песню.',
  'value_de': 'singen',
  'value_de_trans': 'зинген',
  'value_ru': 'петь'},
 {'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'vor Freude [weinen]',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'фор фройде вайнен',
  'phrase_ru': '[плакать] от радости',
  'value_de': 'weinen',
  'value_de_trans': 'вайнен',
  'value_ru': 'плакать'},
 {'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Du kannst über mich [lachen].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду канст уба мих лахен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Ты можешь надо мной [смеяться].',
  'value_de': 'lachen',
  'value_de_trans': 'лахен',
  'value_ru': 'смеяться'},
 {'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'ein Fenster [öffnen]',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'айн фенста эфнен',
  'phrase_ru': '[открывать] окно',
  'value_de': 'öffnen',
  'value_de_trans': 'эфнен',
  'value_ru': 'открывать'},
 {'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'ein Mädchen [küssen]',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'айн медхен кюссен',
  'phrase_ru': '[целовать] девушку',
  'value_de': 'küssen',
  'value_de_trans': 'кюссен',
  'value_ru': 'целовать'},
 {'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich werde ein Auto [kaufen].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде айн ауто кауфен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я буду [покупать] машину.',
  'value_de': 'kaufen',
  'value_de_trans': 'кауфен',
  'value_ru': 'покупать'},
 {'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Was willst du [machen]?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вас вилльст ду махен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Что ты хочешь [делать]?',
  'value_de': 'machen',
  'value_de_trans': 'махен',
  'value_ru': 'делать'},
 {'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Wir müssen Steuern [zahlen].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа мюссен штойан цален',
  'phrase_ru': 'Мы должны [платить] налоги.',
  'value_de': 'zahlen',
  'value_de_trans': 'цален',
  'value_ru': 'платить'},
 {'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'einen Kuchen [probieren]',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'айнен кухен пробирен',
  'phrase_ru': '[пробовать] пирог (торт)',
  'value_de': 'probieren',
  'value_de_trans': 'пробирен',
  'value_ru': 'пробовать'},
 {'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich will eine Familie [haben].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их вилль айне фамилие хабен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я хочу [иметь] семью.',
  'value_de': 'haben',
  'value_de_trans': 'хабен',
  'value_ru': 'иметь'},
 {'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich will dich [sehen].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их вилль дих зиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я хочу тебя [видеть].',
  'value_de': 'sehen',
  'value_de_trans': 'зиен',
  'value_ru': 'видеть'},
 {'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Du musst mir [glauben].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду муст миа глаубен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Ты должен мне [верить].',
  'value_de': 'glauben',
  'value_de_trans': 'глаубен',
  'value_ru': 'верить'},
 {'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'nach der Arbeit [ruhen]',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'нах диа арбайт руен',
  'phrase_ru': '[отдыхать] после работы',
  'value_de': 'ruhen',
  'value_de_trans': 'руен',
  'value_ru': 'отдыхать'},
 {'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich will im Ausland [studieren].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их вилль им аусланд штудирен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я хочу [учиться] за границей.',
  'value_de': 'studieren',
  'value_de_trans': 'штудирен',
  'value_ru': 'учиться'},
 {'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Du darfst nicht [rauchen].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду дарфст нихт раухен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Ты не можешь (не позволено) [курить].',
  'value_de': 'rauchen',
  'value_de_trans': 'раухен',
  'value_ru': 'курить'},
 {'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Er kann schnell [rennen].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа канн шнелль реннен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Он может быстро [бегать].',
  'value_de': 'rennen',
  'value_de_trans': 'реннен',
  'value_ru': 'бегать'},
 {'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'das Licht [einzuschalten]',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас лихт айнцушальтен',
  'phrase_ru': '[включать] свет',
  'value_de': 'einzuschalten',
  'value_de_trans': 'айнцушальтен',
  'value_ru': 'включать'},
 {'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'das Radio [ausschalten]',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас радио аусшальтен',
  'phrase_ru': '[выключать] радио',
  'value_de': 'ausschalten',
  'value_de_trans': 'аусшальтен',
  'value_ru': 'выключать'},
 {'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'einen Anzug [anziehen]',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'айнен анцуг анциэн',
  'phrase_ru': '[надевать] костюм',
  'value_de': 'anziehen',
  'value_de_trans': 'анциэн',
  'value_ru': 'надевать'},
 {'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'die Schuhe [ausziehen]',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ди шуе аусциэн',
  'phrase_ru': '[снимать] туфли (обувь)',
  'value_de': 'ausziehen',
  'value_de_trans': 'аусциэн',
  'value_ru': 'снимать'},
 {'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Heute Abend gehen wir [tanzen].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хойте абенд геен виа танцен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Сегодня вечером мы идем [танцевать].',
  'value_de': 'tanzen',
  'value_de_trans': 'танцен',
  'value_ru': 'танцевать'},
 {'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich will in der Stadt [wohnen].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их вилль ин диа штат вонен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я хочу [жить] в городе.',
  'value_de': 'wohnen',
  'value_de_trans': 'вонен',
  'value_ru': 'жить'},
 {'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'den Frieden [wollen]',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дин фриден воллен',
  'phrase_ru': '[хотеть] мира',
  'value_de': 'wollen',
  'value_de_trans': 'воллен',
  'value_ru': 'хотеть'},
 {'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Wir müssen einander [lieben].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа мюссен айнанда либен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Мы должны [любить] друг друга.',
  'value_de': 'lieben',
  'value_de_trans': 'либен',
  'value_ru': 'любить'},
 {'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'an Gesundheit [denken]',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ан гезундхайт денкен',
  'phrase_ru': '[думать] о здоровье',
  'value_de': 'denken',
  'value_de_trans': 'денкен',
  'value_ru': 'думать'},
 {'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'durch die Nase [atmen]',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дуих ди назе атмен',
  'phrase_ru': '[дышать] через нос',
  'value_de': 'atmen',
  'value_de_trans': 'атмен',
  'value_ru': 'дышать'},
 {'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Von eins bis hundert [zählen].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'фон айнс бис хундат целен',
  'phrase_ru': '[Считать] от одного до ста.',
  'value_de': 'zählen',
  'value_de_trans': 'целен',
  'value_ru': 'считать'},
 {'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'eine Fliege [töten]',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'айне флиге тётен',
  'phrase_ru': '[убивать] муху',
  'value_de': 'töten',
  'value_de_trans': 'тётен',
  'value_ru': 'убивать'},
 {'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ein Fisch kann [schwimmen].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'айн фиш канн швиммен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Рыба умеет [плавать].',
  'value_de': 'schwimmen',
  'value_de_trans': 'швиммен',
  'value_ru': 'плавать'},
 {'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'die Hände [waschen]',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ди хенде вашен',
  'phrase_ru': '[мыть] руки',
  'value_de': 'waschen',
  'value_de_trans': 'вашен',
  'value_ru': 'мыть'},
 {'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'in den Himmel [schauen]',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ин дин химмель шауэн',
  'phrase_ru': '[смотреть] на небо',
  'value_de': 'schauen',
  'value_de_trans': 'шауэн',
  'value_ru': 'смотреть'},
 {'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich muss eine Wohnung [suchen].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их мусс айне вонунг зухен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я должен [искать] квартиру.',
  'value_de': 'suchen',
  'value_de_trans': 'зухен',
  'value_ru': 'искать'},
 {'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'die Gefühle [verbergen]',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ди гефюле фёбегн',
  'phrase_ru': '[скрывать] чувства',
  'value_de': 'verbergen',
  'value_de_trans': 'фёбегн',
  'value_ru': 'скрывать'},
 {'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'auf das Bett [springen]',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ауф дас бетт шпринен',
  'phrase_ru': '[прыгать] на кровати',
  'value_de': 'springen',
  'value_de_trans': 'шпринен',
  'value_ru': 'прыгать'},
 {'dict': '2',
  'dict_type': 'verbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'das Obst [verkaufen]',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас обст феркауфен',
  'phrase_ru': '[продавать] фрукты',
  'value_de': 'verkaufen',
  'value_de_trans': 'феркауфен',
  'value_ru': 'продавать'}]

words_deutsch_words = [{'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'союз',
  'phrase_de': 'Name [und] Adresse, bitte.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'наме унд адрессе битте',
  'phrase_ru': 'Имя [и] адрес, пожалуйста.',
  'value_de': 'und',
  'value_de_trans': 'унд',
  'value_ru': 'и'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'предл.',
  'phrase_de': 'Willkommen [in] Deutschland!',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виллькоммен ин дойчланд',
  'phrase_ru': 'Добро пожаловать [в] Германию!',
  'value_de': 'in',
  'value_de_trans': 'ин',
  'value_ru': 'в'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'мест.',
  'phrase_de': '[Was] machen Sie hier?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вас махен зи хиа',
  'phrase_ru': '[Что] Вы здесь делаете?',
  'value_de': 'was',
  'value_de_trans': 'вас',
  'value_ru': 'что'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'предл.',
  'phrase_de': 'Wir leben [auf] der Erde.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа лебен ауф диа эаде',
  'phrase_ru': 'Мы живём [на] Земле.',
  'value_de': 'auf',
  'value_de_trans': 'ауф',
  'value_ru': 'на'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'союз',
  'phrase_de': 'Gut, [dass] du kamst.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'гут дасс ду камст',
  'phrase_ru': 'Хорошо, [что] ты пришел.',
  'value_de': 'dass',
  'value_de_trans': 'дасс',
  'value_ru': 'что'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': 'Alles [hat] ein Ende.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'аллес хат айн энде',
  'phrase_ru': 'Всё [имеет] конец.',
  'value_de': 'hat',
  'value_de_trans': 'хат',
  'value_ru': 'имеет'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'нар.',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich bin [so] glücklich.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их бин зу глюклих',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я [так] счастлив.',
  'value_de': 'so',
  'value_de_trans': 'зу',
  'value_ru': 'так'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'предл.',
  'phrase_de': '[von] Berlin nach München',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'фон берин нах мюнхен',
  'phrase_ru': '[из] Берлина в Мюнхен',
  'value_de': 'von',
  'value_de_trans': 'фон',
  'value_ru': 'из'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': 'Der Film [war] interessant.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'диа фильм ва интерессант',
  'phrase_ru': 'Фильм [был] интересным.',
  'value_de': 'war',
  'value_de_trans': 'ва',
  'value_ru': 'был'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'предл.',
  'phrase_de': 'Das ist [für] meinen Freund.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас ист фюа майнен фройнд',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это [для] моего друга.',
  'value_de': 'für',
  'value_de_trans': 'фюа',
  'value_ru': 'для'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'нар.',
  'phrase_de': 'Hallo! Arbeitest du [hier]?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'халло арбайтест ду хиа',
  'phrase_ru': 'Привет! Ты [здесь] работаешь?',
  'value_de': 'hier',
  'value_de_trans': 'хиа',
  'value_ru': 'здесь'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'предл.',
  'phrase_de': 'Die Karte hängt [an] der Wand.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ди карте хенгт ан диа ванд',
  'phrase_ru': 'Карта висит [на] стене.',
  'value_de': 'an',
  'value_de_trans': 'ан',
  'value_ru': 'на'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'нар.',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich bin [noch] nicht fertig.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их бин нох нихт феатих',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я [ещё] не готов (не закончил).',
  'value_de': 'noch',
  'value_de_trans': 'нох',
  'value_ru': 'ещё'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'нар.',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich spreche [nur] Deutsch.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их шпрехе нуа дойч',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я говорю [только] по-немецки.',
  'value_de': 'nur',
  'value_de_trans': 'нуа',
  'value_ru': 'только'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'нар.',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich wohne [auch] in Köln.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их воне аух ин кёльн',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я [тоже] живу в Кельне.',
  'value_de': 'auch',
  'value_de_trans': 'аух',
  'value_ru': 'тоже'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'предл.',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich komme [aus] Russland.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их комме аус русланд',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я (родом) [из] России.',
  'value_de': 'aus',
  'value_de_trans': 'аус',
  'value_ru': 'из'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'союз',
  'phrase_de': 'Mit Milch, [aber] ohne Zucker.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'мит мильх аба уне цукка',
  'phrase_ru': 'С молоком, [но] без сахара.',
  'value_de': 'aber',
  'value_de_trans': 'аба',
  'value_ru': 'но'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'нар.',
  'phrase_de': 'Es ist [schon] neun Uhr.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс ист шун нойн уа',
  'phrase_ru': '[Уже] девять часов.',
  'value_de': 'schon',
  'value_de_trans': 'шун',
  'value_ru': 'уже'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'союз',
  'phrase_de': 'Jedes Mal, [wenn] ich komme.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'едес маль венн их комме',
  'phrase_ru': 'Каждый раз, [когда] я прихожу.',
  'value_de': 'wenn',
  'value_de_trans': 'венн',
  'value_ru': 'когда'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'союз',
  'phrase_de': 'Korrigiert mich, [wenn] ich mich irre.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'корригирт мих венн их мих ирре',
  'phrase_ru': 'Поправьте меня, [если] я ошибаюсь.',
  'value_de': 'wenn',
  'value_de_trans': 'венн',
  'value_ru': 'если'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': 'Alles [wird] gut!',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'аллес вёд гут',
  'phrase_ru': 'Все [будет] хорошо!',
  'value_de': 'wird',
  'value_de_trans': 'вёд',
  'value_ru': 'будет'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'союз',
  'phrase_de': 'Lieber spät [als] nie.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'либер шпит альц ни',
  'phrase_ru': 'Лучше поздно, [чем] никогда.',
  'value_de': 'als',
  'value_de_trans': 'альц',
  'value_ru': 'чем'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'союз',
  'phrase_de': '[als] ich jung war',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'альц их юнг ва',
  'phrase_ru': '[когда] я был молод',
  'value_de': 'als',
  'value_de_trans': 'альц',
  'value_ru': 'когда'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'сущ. (с.р.)',
  'phrase_de': 'Das erste und das letzte [Mal].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас еасте унд дас лецте маль',
  'phrase_ru': 'Первый и последний [раз].',
  'value_de': 'Mal',
  'value_de_trans': 'маль',
  'value_ru': 'раз'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Er fragte nicht, [doch] der Vater sagte.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа фрагте нихт дох диа фата загте',
  'phrase_ru': 'Он не спрашивал, [однако] отец сказал.',
  'value_de': 'doch',
  'value_de_trans': 'дох',
  'value_ru': 'однако'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'нар.',
  'phrase_de': 'Die Tür ist [jetzt] offen.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ди тюр ист ецт оффен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Дверь [сейчас] открыта.',
  'value_de': 'jetzt',
  'value_de_trans': 'ецт',
  'value_ru': 'сейчас'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'прил.',
  'phrase_de': 'Der Schnee ist [weiß].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'диа шне ист вайс',
  'phrase_ru': 'Снег [белый].',
  'value_de': 'weiß',
  'value_de_trans': 'вайс',
  'value_ru': 'белый'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich [weiß], wo er ist.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их вайс во иа ист',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я [знаю], где он.',
  'value_de': 'weiß',
  'value_de_trans': 'вайс',
  'value_ru': 'знаю'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': 'Wir [werden] tanzen.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн танцен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Мы [будем] танцевать.',
  'value_de': 'werden',
  'value_de_trans': 'веадн',
  'value_ru': 'будем'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': '[Nach] dem Frühling kommt der Sommer.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'нах дем фрюлинг комт диа зомма',
  'phrase_ru': '[После] весны приходит лето.',
  'value_de': 'nach',
  'value_de_trans': 'нах',
  'value_ru': 'после'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': '[nach] dem Süden fahren',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'нах дем зюден фарен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ехать [на] юг',
  'value_de': 'nach',
  'value_de_trans': 'нах',
  'value_ru': 'на'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Willst du das? - [Ja].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вилльст ду дас я',
  'phrase_ru': 'Ты хочешь этого? - [Да].',
  'value_de': 'ja',
  'value_de_trans': 'я',
  'value_ru': 'да'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'союз',
  'phrase_de': 'Alles [oder] nichts.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'аллес ода нихтс',
  'phrase_ru': 'Всё [или] ничего.',
  'value_de': 'oder',
  'value_de_trans': 'ода',
  'value_ru': 'или'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Es ist kalt heute, [oder]?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс ист кальт хойте ода',
  'phrase_ru': 'Холодно сегодня, [не так ли]?',
  'value_de': 'oder',
  'value_de_trans': 'ода',
  'value_ru': 'не так ли'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'нар.',
  'phrase_de': 'erst du, [dann] er',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'еаст ду данн иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'сперва ты, [потом] он',
  'value_de': 'dann',
  'value_de_trans': 'данн',
  'value_ru': 'потом'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich [will] einen Kaffee.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их вилль айнен каффи',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я [хочу] кофе.',
  'value_de': 'will',
  'value_de_trans': 'вилль',
  'value_ru': 'хочу'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Weniger Worte, [mehr] Taten.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'венига ворте миа татен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Меньше слов, [больше] дел.',
  'value_de': 'mehr',
  'value_de_trans': 'миа',
  'value_ru': 'больше'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich [muss] arbeiten.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их мусс арбайтен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я [должен] работать.',
  'value_de': 'muss',
  'value_de_trans': 'мусс',
  'value_ru': 'должен'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'нар.',
  'phrase_de': 'Er sagt [immer] die Wahrheit.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа загт имма ди ваахайт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Он [всегда] говорит правду.',
  'value_de': 'immer',
  'value_de_trans': 'имма',
  'value_ru': 'всегда'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'нар.',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich bin [wieder] hier.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их бин вида хиа',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я [снова] здесь.',
  'value_de': 'wieder',
  'value_de_trans': 'вида',
  'value_ru': 'снова'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'предл.',
  'phrase_de': '[bei] der Tür',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'бай диа тюр',
  'phrase_ru': '[у] двери',
  'value_de': 'bei',
  'value_de_trans': 'бай',
  'value_ru': 'у'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'предл.',
  'phrase_de': 'Ein Kind steht [vor] dem Fenster.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'айн кинд штит фоа дем фенста',
  'phrase_ru': 'Ребенок стоит [перед] окном.',
  'value_de': 'vor',
  'value_de_trans': 'фоа',
  'value_ru': 'перед'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'сущ. (м.р.)',
  'phrase_de': 'Mein [Mann] ist Arzt.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'майн ман ист ацт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Мой [муж] врач.',
  'value_de': 'Mann',
  'value_de_trans': 'ман',
  'value_ru': 'муж'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'сущ. (м.р.)',
  'phrase_de': 'Der [Mann] ist stark.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'диа ман ист штаак',
  'phrase_ru': '[Мужчина] сильный.',
  'value_de': 'Mann',
  'value_de_trans': 'ман',
  'value_ru': 'мужчина'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'нар.',
  'phrase_de': 'Die Wohnung ist [sehr] groß.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ди вонун ист зеа грос',
  'phrase_ru': 'Квартира [очень] большая.',
  'value_de': 'sehr',
  'value_de_trans': 'зеа',
  'value_ru': 'очень'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'мест.',
  'phrase_de': 'Wir sprechen [alle] Englisch.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа шпрехен алле энглиш',
  'phrase_ru': 'Мы [все] говорим по-английски.',
  'value_de': 'alle',
  'value_de_trans': 'алле',
  'value_ru': 'все'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'предл.',
  'phrase_de': 'Wir fliegen [über] den Wolken.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа флиген уба ден волькен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Мы летим [над] облаками.',
  'value_de': 'über',
  'value_de_trans': 'уба',
  'value_ru': 'над'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'нар.',
  'phrase_de': '[über] einen Kilometer',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'уба айнен километа',
  'phrase_ru': '[свыше] одного километра',
  'value_de': 'über',
  'value_de_trans': 'уба',
  'value_ru': 'свыше'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'мест.',
  'phrase_de': 'Wer ist [diese] Frau?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа ист дизе фрау',
  'phrase_ru': 'Кто [эта] женщина?',
  'value_de': 'diese',
  'value_de_trans': 'дизе',
  'value_ru': 'эта'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das ist [einfach] wunderbar!',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас ист айнфах вундеба',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это [просто] замечательно!',
  'value_de': 'einfach',
  'value_de_trans': 'айнфах',
  'value_ru': 'просто'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'нар.',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich mache das [nie].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их махе дас ни',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я [никогда] не делаю этого.',
  'value_de': 'nie',
  'value_de_trans': 'ни',
  'value_ru': 'никогда'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': '[Wo] ist deine Schule?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'во ист дайне шуле',
  'phrase_ru': '[Где] твоя школа?',
  'value_de': 'wo',
  'value_de_trans': 'во',
  'value_ru': 'где'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'сущ. (ж.р.)',
  'phrase_de': 'Die [Zeit] ist gekommen.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ди цайт ист гекоммен',
  'phrase_ru': '[Время] пришло.',
  'value_de': 'Zeit',
  'value_de_trans': 'цайт',
  'value_ru': 'время'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das ist [wirklich] interessant.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас ист вирклих интерессант',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это [действительно] интересно.',
  'value_de': 'wirklich',
  'value_de_trans': 'вирклих',
  'value_ru': 'действительно'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': '[Danke] für das Geschenk.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'данке фюа дас гешенк',
  'phrase_ru': '[Спасибо] за подарок.',
  'value_de': 'danke',
  'value_de_trans': 'данке',
  'value_ru': 'спасибо'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': 'Wer [soll] das machen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа золль дас махен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Кто [должен] это сделать?',
  'value_de': 'soll',
  'value_de_trans': 'золль',
  'value_ru': 'должен'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Die Rechnung, [bitte].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ди рехнун битте',
  'phrase_ru': 'Счет, [пожалуйста].',
  'value_de': 'bitte',
  'value_de_trans': 'битте',
  'value_ru': 'пожалуйста'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': '[Viel] Lärm um nichts.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'филь лерм ум нихтс',
  'phrase_ru': '[Много] шума из ничего.',
  'value_de': 'viel',
  'value_de_trans': 'филь',
  'value_ru': 'много'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich habe alles [gesagt].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе аллес гезагт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я всё [сказал].',
  'value_de': 'gesagt',
  'value_de_trans': 'гезагт',
  'value_ru': 'сказал'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Drei Schritte [zurück].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'драй шритте цурюк',
  'phrase_ru': 'Три шага [назад].',
  'value_de': 'zurück',
  'value_de_trans': 'цурюк',
  'value_ru': 'назад'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich [wollte] Französisch lernen.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их волльте францёзиш леанен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я [хотел] выучить французский.',
  'value_de': 'wollte',
  'value_de_trans': 'волльте',
  'value_ru': 'хотел'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'сущ. (ж.р.)',
  'phrase_de': 'Hast du eine [Frau]?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хаст ду айне фрау',
  'phrase_ru': 'У тебя есть [жена]?',
  'value_de': 'Frau',
  'value_de_trans': 'фрау',
  'value_ru': 'жена'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'сущ. (ж.р.)',
  'phrase_de': 'Was für eine attraktive [Frau]!',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вас фюа айне атрактиве фрау',
  'phrase_ru': 'Какая привлекательная [женщина]!',
  'value_de': 'Frau',
  'value_de_trans': 'фрау',
  'value_ru': 'женщина'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'сущ. (с.р.)',
  'phrase_de': 'Das [Leben] ist schön!',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас лебен ист шун',
  'phrase_ru': '[Жизнь] прекрасна!',
  'value_de': 'Leben',
  'value_de_trans': 'лебен',
  'value_ru': 'жизнь'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'сущ. (м.р.)',
  'phrase_de': 'Mein [Gott]! Was ist das?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'майн готт вас ист дас',
  'phrase_ru': '[Бог] мой! Что это?',
  'value_de': 'Gott',
  'value_de_trans': 'готт',
  'value_ru': 'Бог'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'сущ. (множ.)',
  'phrase_de': 'Was machen diese [Leute]?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вас махен дизе лойте',
  'phrase_ru': 'Что делают эти [люди]?',
  'value_de': 'Leute',
  'value_de_trans': 'лойте',
  'value_ru': 'люди'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': '[Kannst] du mir helfen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'канст ду миа хельфен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Ты [можешь] мне помочь?',
  'value_de': 'kannst',
  'value_de_trans': 'канст',
  'value_ru': 'можешь'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'нар.',
  'phrase_de': '[Heute] ist mein Geburtstag.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хойте ист майн гебуртстаг',
  'phrase_ru': '[Сегодня] мой день рождения.',
  'value_de': 'heute',
  'value_de_trans': 'хойте',
  'value_ru': 'сегодня'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'мест.',
  'phrase_de': 'Willkommen in [dieser] Welt!',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виллькоммен ин диза вельт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Добро пожаловать в [этот] мир!',
  'value_de': 'dieser',
  'value_de_trans': 'диза',
  'value_ru': 'этот'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'мест.',
  'phrase_de': 'Wer ist [dein] Lehrer?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа ист дайн лира',
  'phrase_ru': 'Кто [твой] учитель?',
  'value_de': 'dein',
  'value_de_trans': 'дайн',
  'value_ru': 'твой'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': 'Er [kommt] morgen.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа комт морген',
  'phrase_ru': 'Он [придет] завтра.',
  'value_de': 'kommt',
  'value_de_trans': 'комт',
  'value_ru': 'придет'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': '[Willst] du mich küssen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вилльст ду мих кюссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Ты [хочешь] меня поцеловать?',
  'value_de': 'willst',
  'value_de_trans': 'вилльст',
  'value_ru': 'хочешь'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ja, [sicher]. Warum nicht?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'я зиха варум нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Да, [конечно]. Почему нет?',
  'value_de': 'sicher',
  'value_de_trans': 'зиха',
  'value_ru': 'конечно'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'прил.',
  'phrase_de': 'Ist die Brücke [sicher]?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ист ди брюке зиха',
  'phrase_ru': 'Мост [безопасный]?',
  'value_de': 'sicher',
  'value_de_trans': 'зиха',
  'value_ru': 'безопасный'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'нар.',
  'phrase_de': 'Bist du [ganz] allein?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'бист ду ганц аллайн',
  'phrase_ru': 'Ты [совсем] одна?',
  'value_de': 'ganz',
  'value_de_trans': 'ганц',
  'value_ru': 'совсем'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich denke, [also] bin ich.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их денке альзу бин их',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я мыслю, [следовательно], я существую.',
  'value_de': 'also',
  'value_de_trans': 'альзу',
  'value_ru': 'следовательно'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': 'Du [hast] das Recht.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст дас рехт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Ты [имеешь] право.',
  'value_de': 'hast',
  'value_de_trans': 'хаст',
  'value_ru': 'имеешь'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'союз',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich esse, [weil] ich Hunger habe.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их эссе вайль их хуна хабе',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я ем, [потому что] голоден.',
  'value_de': 'weil',
  'value_de_trans': 'вайль',
  'value_ru': 'потому что'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie weiß, was sie [tut].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вайс вас зи тут',
  'phrase_ru': 'Она знает, что она [делает].',
  'value_de': 'tut',
  'value_de_trans': 'тут',
  'value_ru': 'делает'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': '[Hallo], wie heißt du?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'халло ви хайст ду',
  'phrase_ru': '[Привет], как тебя зовут?',
  'value_de': 'hallo',
  'value_de_trans': 'халло',
  'value_ru': 'привет'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': 'Was [macht] uns zu Menschen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вас махт унс цу меншен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Что [делает] нас людьми?',
  'value_de': 'macht',
  'value_de_trans': 'махт',
  'value_ru': 'делает'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': 'Zwei Plätze [waren] frei.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'цвай плетце варен фрай',
  'phrase_ru': 'Два места [были] свободны.',
  'value_de': 'waren',
  'value_de_trans': 'варен',
  'value_ru': 'были'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Warten Sie [bis] morgen.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вартен зи бис морген',
  'phrase_ru': 'Подождите [до] завтра.',
  'value_de': 'bis',
  'value_de_trans': 'бис',
  'value_ru': 'до'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'нар.',
  'phrase_de': '[Vielleicht] weiß sie die Antwort.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'филяйхт вайс зи ди антворт',
  'phrase_ru': '[Возможно], она знает ответ.',
  'value_de': 'vielleicht',
  'value_de_trans': 'филяйхт',
  'value_ru': 'возможно'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'сущ. (м.р.)',
  'phrase_de': 'Der [Weg] in die Stadt.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'диа вег ин ди штат',
  'phrase_ru': '[Путь] в город.',
  'value_de': 'Weg',
  'value_de_trans': 'вег',
  'value_ru': 'путь'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'нар.',
  'phrase_de': 'Hände [weg] von meiner Tochter.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хенде вег фон майна тохта',
  'phrase_ru': 'Руки [прочь] от моей дочери.',
  'value_de': 'weg',
  'value_de_trans': 'вег',
  'value_ru': 'прочь'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': '[Lassen] Sie mich Ihnen helfen!',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'лассен зи мих инен хельфен',
  'phrase_ru': '[Позвольте] мне Вам помочь.',
  'value_de': 'lassen',
  'value_de_trans': 'лассен',
  'value_ru': 'позволять'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'сущ. (м.р.)',
  'phrase_de': 'Luke, ich bin dein [Vater]!',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'люк их бин дайн фата',
  'phrase_ru': 'Люк, я твой [отец]!',
  'value_de': 'Vater',
  'value_de_trans': 'фата',
  'value_ru': 'отец'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': 'Hast du meine Uhr [gesehen]?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хаст ду майне уа гезиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Ты [видел] мои часы?',
  'value_de': 'gesehen',
  'value_de_trans': 'гезиен',
  'value_ru': 'видел'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': '[Nun] ist mir alles klar!',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'нун ист миа аллес клаа',
  'phrase_ru': '[Теперь] мне всё ясно!',
  'value_de': 'nun',
  'value_de_trans': 'нун',
  'value_ru': 'теперь'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Warum [gerade] ich?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'варум гераде их',
  'phrase_ru': 'Почему [именно] я?',
  'value_de': 'gerade',
  'value_de_trans': 'гераде',
  'value_ru': 'именно'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'прил.',
  'phrase_de': 'eine [gerade] Straße',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'айне гераде штрасе',
  'phrase_ru': '[прямая] улица',
  'value_de': 'gerade',
  'value_de_trans': 'гераде',
  'value_ru': 'прямая'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich [glaube] an dich.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их глаубе ан дих',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я [верю] в тебя.',
  'value_de': 'glaube',
  'value_de_trans': 'глаубе',
  'value_ru': 'верю'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'сущ. (м.р.)',
  'phrase_de': 'Heute ist mein [Tag]!',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хойте ист майн таг',
  'phrase_ru': 'Сегодня мой [день]!',
  'value_de': 'Tag',
  'value_de_trans': 'таг',
  'value_ru': 'день'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'сущ. (с.р.)',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie liebt das [Geld].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи либт дас гельд',
  'phrase_ru': 'Она любит [деньги].',
  'value_de': 'Geld',
  'value_de_trans': 'гельд',
  'value_ru': 'деньги'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': 'Wie hast du das [gemacht]?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ви хаст ду дас гемахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Как ты это [сделал]?',
  'value_de': 'gemacht',
  'value_de_trans': 'гемахт',
  'value_ru': 'сделал'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': '[Nein], ich will nicht.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'найн их вилль нихт',
  'phrase_ru': '[Нет], я не хочу.',
  'value_de': 'nein',
  'value_de_trans': 'найн',
  'value_ru': 'нет'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'предл.',
  'phrase_de': '[durch] den Wald gehen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дуих ден вальд геен',
  'phrase_ru': 'идти [через] лес',
  'value_de': 'durch',
  'value_de_trans': 'дуих',
  'value_ru': 'через'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': 'Das [passiert] jeden Tag.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас пассиат еден таг',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это [происходит] каждый день.',
  'value_de': 'passiert',
  'value_de_trans': 'пассиат',
  'value_ru': 'происходит'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'нар.',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie wird [wohl] kommen.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд воль коммен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Она, [вероятно], придёт.',
  'value_de': 'wohl',
  'value_de_trans': 'воль',
  'value_ru': 'вероятно'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'нар.',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich fühle mich jetzt [wohl].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их фюле мих ецт воль',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я чувствую себя сейчас [хорошо].',
  'value_de': 'wohl',
  'value_de_trans': 'воль',
  'value_ru': 'хорошо'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'сущ. (ж.р.)',
  'phrase_de': 'Meine [Mutter] liebt mich.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'майне мутта либт мих',
  'phrase_ru': 'Моя [мать] любит меня.',
  'value_de': 'Mutter',
  'value_de_trans': 'мутта',
  'value_ru': 'мать'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich kann nicht so schnell [reden].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их канн нихт зу шнелль реден',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я не могу так быстро [говорить].',
  'value_de': 'reden',
  'value_de_trans': 'реден',
  'value_ru': 'говорить'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'прил.',
  'phrase_de': 'Hast du einen [anderen] Plan?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хаст ду айнен андерен план',
  'phrase_ru': 'У тебя есть [другой] план?',
  'value_de': 'anderen',
  'value_de_trans': 'андерен',
  'value_ru': 'другой'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich [dachte] an dich!',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их дахте ан дих',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я [думал] о тебе!',
  'value_de': 'dachte',
  'value_de_trans': 'дахте',
  'value_ru': 'думал'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich [möchte] einen Salat.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их мёхте айнен залат',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я [хотел бы] салат.',
  'value_de': 'möchte',
  'value_de_trans': 'мёхте',
  'value_ru': 'хотел бы'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': 'Du [wirst] mir danken.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст миа данкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Ты [будешь] меня благодарить.',
  'value_de': 'wirst',
  'value_de_trans': 'вирст',
  'value_ru': 'будешь'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': 'Das Buch [gehört] ihm.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас бух гехёат им',
  'phrase_ru': 'Книга [принадлежит] ему.',
  'value_de': 'gehört',
  'value_de_trans': 'гехёат',
  'value_ru': 'принадлежит'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich habe alles [gehört].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе аллес гехёат',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я всё [слышал].',
  'value_de': 'gehört',
  'value_de_trans': 'гехёат',
  'value_ru': 'слышал'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': 'Sag mir, was du [weißt].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'заг миа вас ду вайст',
  'phrase_ru': 'Скажи мне, что ты [знаешь].',
  'value_de': 'weißt',
  'value_de_trans': 'вайст',
  'value_ru': 'знаешь'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Er hat ein [paar] Freunde.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат айн паа фройнде',
  'phrase_ru': 'Он имеет (у него есть) [несколько] друзей.',
  'value_de': 'paar',
  'value_de_trans': 'паа',
  'value_ru': 'несколько'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'сущ. (с.р.)',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie sind ein perfektes [Paar].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи зинд айн перфектес паа',
  'phrase_ru': 'Они идеальная [пара].',
  'value_de': 'Paar',
  'value_de_trans': 'паа',
  'value_ru': 'пара'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'нар.',
  'phrase_de': 'Diese Variante ist [besser].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дизе варианте ист бесса',
  'phrase_ru': 'Этот вариант [лучше].',
  'value_de': 'besser',
  'value_de_trans': 'бесса',
  'value_ru': 'лучше'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'нар.',
  'phrase_de': 'Komm [her] und hilf mir.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'комм хиа унд хильф миа',
  'phrase_ru': 'Иди [сюда] и помоги мне.',
  'value_de': 'her',
  'value_de_trans': 'хиа',
  'value_ru': 'сюда'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': 'Du [musst] das machen.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду муст дас махен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Ты [должен] это сделать.',
  'value_de': 'musst',
  'value_de_trans': 'муст',
  'value_ru': 'должен'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'сущ. (ж.р.)',
  'phrase_de': 'Eine [Ordnung] der Dinge im Universum.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'айне орднун диа дине им униферзум',
  'phrase_ru': '[Порядок] вещей во вселенной.',
  'value_de': 'Ordnung',
  'value_de_trans': 'орднун',
  'value_ru': 'порядок'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich kann [klar] denken.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их канн клаа денкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я могу [ясно] мыслить.',
  'value_de': 'klar',
  'value_de_trans': 'клаа',
  'value_ru': 'ясно'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'нар.',
  'phrase_de': 'Er hat [lange] gewartet.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат лане геваатет',
  'phrase_ru': 'Он [долго] ждал.',
  'value_de': 'lange',
  'value_de_trans': 'лане',
  'value_ru': 'долго'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Komm und sieh [selbst]!',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'комм унд зи зельбст',
  'phrase_ru': 'Иди и смотри [сам]!',
  'value_de': 'selbst',
  'value_de_trans': 'зельбст',
  'value_ru': 'сам'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': 'einen freien Platz [finden]',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'айнен фрайен плац финден',
  'phrase_ru': '[находить] свободное место',
  'value_de': 'finden',
  'value_de_trans': 'финден',
  'value_ru': 'находить'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich [denke] nur an dich.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их денке нуа ан дих',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я [думаю] только о тебе.',
  'value_de': 'denke',
  'value_de_trans': 'денке',
  'value_ru': 'думаю'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'сущ. (ж.р.)',
  'phrase_de': 'Die [Nacht] war kalt.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ди нахт ва кальт',
  'phrase_ru': '[Ночь] была холодной.',
  'value_de': 'Nacht',
  'value_de_trans': 'нахт',
  'value_ru': 'ночь'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'нар.',
  'phrase_de': 'Was [genau] hast du getan?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вас генау хаст ду гетан',
  'phrase_ru': 'Что [именно] ты сделал?',
  'value_de': 'genau',
  'value_de_trans': 'генау',
  'value_ru': 'именно'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'нар.',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich bin [gar] nicht überrascht.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их бин гар нихт уберрашт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я [совсем] не удивлён.',
  'value_de': 'gar',
  'value_de_trans': 'гар',
  'value_ru': 'совсем'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': 'Er [sagt], was er denkt.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа загт вас иа денкт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Он [говорит] (то), что он думает.',
  'value_de': 'sagt',
  'value_de_trans': 'загт',
  'value_ru': 'говорит'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'сущ. (ж.р.)',
  'phrase_de': 'Wir wollen die [Welt] verändern.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа воллен ди вельт фёэндан',
  'phrase_ru': 'Мы хотим изменить [мир].',
  'value_de': 'Welt',
  'value_de_trans': 'вельт',
  'value_ru': 'мир'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'сущ. (с.р.)',
  'phrase_de': 'Du bist das [Mädchen] meiner Träume.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду бист дас медхен майна тройме',
  'phrase_ru': 'Ты [девушка] моей мечты.',
  'value_de': 'Mädchen',
  'value_de_trans': 'медхен',
  'value_ru': 'девушка'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'прил.',
  'phrase_de': 'Die Blume ist [schön].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ди блуме ист шун',
  'phrase_ru': 'Цветок [красивый].',
  'value_de': 'schön',
  'value_de_trans': 'шун',
  'value_ru': 'красивый'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': '[Warum] fragst du mich?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'варум фрагст ду мих',
  'phrase_ru': '[Почему] ты меня спрашиваешь?',
  'value_de': 'warum',
  'value_de_trans': 'варум',
  'value_ru': 'почему'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': '[Ohne] Wasser kein Leben.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'уне васса кайн лебен',
  'phrase_ru': '[Без] воды нет жизни.',
  'value_de': 'ohne',
  'value_de_trans': 'уне',
  'value_ru': 'без'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'сущ. (м.р.)',
  'phrase_de': 'Wir sind [Menschen], nicht Götter.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа зинд меншен нихт гётта',
  'phrase_ru': 'Мы [люди], (а) не боги.',
  'value_de': 'Menschen',
  'value_de_trans': 'меншен',
  'value_ru': 'люди'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': '[Wieso] bist du nicht fertig?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'визо бист ду нихт феатих',
  'phrase_ru': '[Почему] ты не готова?',
  'value_de': 'wieso',
  'value_de_trans': 'визо',
  'value_ru': 'почему'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'нар.',
  'phrase_de': 'Heute hier, morgen [dort].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хойте хиа морген дорт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Сегодня здесь, завтра [там].',
  'value_de': 'dort',
  'value_de_trans': 'дорт',
  'value_ru': 'там'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'сущ. (с.р.)',
  'phrase_de': 'Das [Haus] hat einen Garten.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас хаус хат айнен гартен',
  'phrase_ru': '[Дом] имеет сад.',
  'value_de': 'Haus',
  'value_de_trans': 'хаус',
  'value_ru': 'дом'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Was wissen Sie [davon]?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вас виссен зи дафон',
  'phrase_ru': 'Что Вы знаете [об этом]?',
  'value_de': 'davon',
  'value_de_trans': 'дафон',
  'value_ru': 'об этом'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'нар.',
  'phrase_de': 'Wir werden [zusammen] lernen.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн цузаммен леанен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Мы будем [вместе] учиться.',
  'value_de': 'zusammen',
  'value_de_trans': 'цузаммен',
  'value_ru': 'вместе'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': 'Weil du mich glücklich [machst].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вайль ду мих глюклих махст',
  'phrase_ru': 'Потому что ты [делаешь] меня счастливым.',
  'value_de': 'machst',
  'value_de_trans': 'махст',
  'value_ru': 'делаешь'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'сущ. (м.р.)',
  'phrase_de': 'Er ist mein bester [Freund].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа ист майн беста фройнд',
  'phrase_ru': 'Он мой лучший [друг].',
  'value_de': 'Freund',
  'value_de_trans': 'фройнд',
  'value_ru': 'друг'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'прил.',
  'phrase_de': 'Die Antwort ist [richtig]!',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ди антворт ист рихтих',
  'phrase_ru': 'Ответ [правильный]!',
  'value_de': 'richtig',
  'value_de_trans': 'рихтих',
  'value_ru': 'правильный'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'сущ. (ж.р.)',
  'phrase_de': 'Die [Angst] vor der Dunkelheit.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ди ангст фоа диа дункельхайт',
  'phrase_ru': '[Страх] темноты.',
  'value_de': 'Angst',
  'value_de_trans': 'ангст',
  'value_ru': 'страх'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'предл.',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich spiele [mit] meinen Freunden.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их шпиле мит майнен фройнден',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я играю [с] моими друзьями.',
  'value_de': 'mit',
  'value_de_trans': 'мит',
  'value_ru': 'с'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': 'Der Hund [sieht] die Katze.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'диа хунд зит ди катце',
  'phrase_ru': 'Собака [видит] кошку.',
  'value_de': 'sieht',
  'value_de_trans': 'зит',
  'value_ru': 'видит'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': 'Er hat nichts [getan].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат нихтс гетан',
  'phrase_ru': 'Он ничего не [сделал].',
  'value_de': 'getan',
  'value_de_trans': 'гетан',
  'value_ru': 'сделал'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'прил.',
  'phrase_de': 'Die Luft ist sehr [rein].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ди луфт ист зеа райн',
  'phrase_ru': 'Воздух очень [чистый].',
  'value_de': 'rein',
  'value_de_trans': 'райн',
  'value_ru': 'чистый'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': 'in der Stadt [bleiben]',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ин диа штат блайбен',
  'phrase_ru': '[оставаться] в городе',
  'value_de': 'bleiben',
  'value_de_trans': 'блайбен',
  'value_ru': 'оставаться'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich werde es [brauchen].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде эс браухен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я буду в этом [нуждаться].',
  'value_de': 'brauchen',
  'value_de_trans': 'браухен',
  'value_ru': 'нуждаться'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'сущ. (с.р.)',
  'phrase_de': 'Die [Kinder] verstehen alles.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ди кинда ферштейн аллес',
  'phrase_ru': '[Дети] всё понимают.',
  'value_de': 'Kinder',
  'value_de_trans': 'кинда',
  'value_ru': 'дети'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'предл.',
  'phrase_de': 'Du bist [unter] Freunden.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду бист унта фройнден',
  'phrase_ru': 'Ты [среди] друзей.',
  'value_de': 'unter',
  'value_de_trans': 'унта',
  'value_ru': 'среди'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'предл.',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich stehe [unter] dem Baum.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их штее унта дем баум',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я стою [под] деревом.',
  'value_de': 'unter',
  'value_de_trans': 'унта',
  'value_ru': 'под'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'сущ. (ж.р.)',
  'phrase_de': 'Wie ist die neue [Arbeit]?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ви ист ди нойе арбайт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Как новая [работа]?',
  'value_de': 'Arbeit',
  'value_de_trans': 'арбайт',
  'value_ru': 'работа'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Wir haben [dafür] bezahlt.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен дафюр бецальт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Мы [за это] заплатили.',
  'value_de': 'dafür',
  'value_de_trans': 'дафюр',
  'value_ru': 'за это'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich bin zu alt [dafür].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их бин цу альт дафюр',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я слишком стар [для этого].',
  'value_de': 'dafür',
  'value_de_trans': 'дафюр',
  'value_ru': 'для этого'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'сущ. (м.р.)',
  'phrase_de': 'Guten Tag, [Herr] Krause!',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'гутен таг херр краузе',
  'phrase_ru': 'Добрый день, [господин] Краузе!',
  'value_de': 'Herr',
  'value_de_trans': 'херр',
  'value_ru': 'господин'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'предл.',
  'phrase_de': '[wegen] schlechten Wetters',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веген шлехтен веттас',
  'phrase_ru': '[из-за] плохой погоды',
  'value_de': 'wegen',
  'value_de_trans': 'веген',
  'value_ru': 'из-за'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich [liebe] dich!',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их либе дих',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я [люблю] тебя!',
  'value_de': 'liebe',
  'value_de_trans': 'либе',
  'value_ru': 'люблю'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Danke, das ist [genug].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'данке дас ист генуг',
  'phrase_ru': 'Спасибо, этого [достаточно].',
  'value_de': 'genug',
  'value_de_trans': 'генуг',
  'value_ru': 'достаточно'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': 'eine Zeitung [bringen]',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'айне цайтунг бринен',
  'phrase_ru': '[приносить] газету',
  'value_de': 'bringen',
  'value_de_trans': 'бринен',
  'value_ru': 'приносить'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'предл.',
  'phrase_de': 'Wir sind [gegen] Krieg.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа зинд геген криг',
  'phrase_ru': 'Мы [против] войны.',
  'value_de': 'gegen',
  'value_de_trans': 'геген',
  'value_ru': 'против'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': '[Sag] mir die Wahrheit.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'заг миа ди ваахайт',
  'phrase_ru': '[Скажи] мне правду.',
  'value_de': 'sag',
  'value_de_trans': 'заг',
  'value_ru': 'скажи'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'нар.',
  'phrase_de': 'Er fährt sehr [schnell].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа ферт зеа шнелль',
  'phrase_ru': 'Он ездит (водит машину) очень [быстро].',
  'value_de': 'schnell',
  'value_de_trans': 'шнелль',
  'value_ru': 'быстро'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'сущ. (м.р.)',
  'phrase_de': 'Guten [Abend], meine Damen und Herren!',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'гутен абенд майне дамен унд херрен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Добрый [вечер], дамы и господа!',
  'value_de': 'Abend',
  'value_de_trans': 'абенд',
  'value_ru': 'вечер'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'сущ. (с.р.)',
  'phrase_de': 'Das [Jahr] geht zu Ende.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас йа гет цу энде',
  'phrase_ru': '[Год] подходит к концу.',
  'value_de': 'Jahr',
  'value_de_trans': 'йа',
  'value_ru': 'год'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': '[Mach] es selbst!',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'мах эс зельбст',
  'phrase_ru': '[Сделай] это сам!',
  'value_de': 'mach',
  'value_de_trans': 'мах',
  'value_ru': 'сделай'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'сущ. (м.р.)',
  'phrase_de': 'Er ist mein jüngerer [Bruder].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа ист майн йюнера бруда',
  'phrase_ru': 'Он мой младший [брат].',
  'value_de': 'Bruder',
  'value_de_trans': 'бруда',
  'value_ru': 'брат'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'сущ. (ж.р.)',
  'phrase_de': 'Er versteht seine [Sache]!',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа ферштейт зайне захе',
  'phrase_ru': 'Он знает свое [дело]!',
  'value_de': 'Sache',
  'value_de_trans': 'захе',
  'value_ru': 'дело'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'сущ. (ж.р.)',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich will noch eine [Sache] erwähnen.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их вилль нох айне захе эавенен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я хочу упомянуть еще одну [вещь].',
  'value_de': 'Sache',
  'value_de_trans': 'захе',
  'value_ru': 'вещь'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': '[Komm] zu mir.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'комм цу миа',
  'phrase_ru': '[Иди] ко мне.',
  'value_de': 'komm',
  'value_de_trans': 'комм',
  'value_ru': 'иди'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'сущ. (м.р.)',
  'phrase_de': 'Wie der Vater, so der [Sohn].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ви диа фата зу диа зун',
  'phrase_ru': 'Каков отец, таков (и) [сын].',
  'value_de': 'Sohn',
  'value_de_trans': 'зун',
  'value_ru': 'сын'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich bin [seit] Samstag hier.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их бин зайт замстаг хиа',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я [с] субботы здесь.',
  'value_de': 'seit',
  'value_de_trans': 'зайт',
  'value_ru': 'с'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'сущ. (м.р.)',
  'phrase_de': "Guten [Morgen]! Wie geht's?",
  'phrase_de_trans': 'гутен морген ви гейтс',
  'phrase_ru': 'Доброе [утро]! Как дела?',
  'value_de': 'Morgen',
  'value_de_trans': 'морген',
  'value_ru': 'утро'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': 'Mein Wagen [steht] dort.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'майн ваген штит дорт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Моя машина [стоит] там.',
  'value_de': 'steht',
  'value_de_trans': 'штит',
  'value_ru': 'стоит'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Lies es noch [einmal].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'лис эс нох айнмаль',
  'phrase_ru': 'Прочти это ещё [раз].',
  'value_de': 'einmal',
  'value_de_trans': 'айнмаль',
  'value_ru': 'раз'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'сущ. (м.р.)',
  'phrase_de': 'Der [Kopf] des Philosophen.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'диа копф дес филозофен',
  'phrase_ru': '[Голова] философа.',
  'value_de': 'Kopf',
  'value_de_trans': 'копф',
  'value_ru': 'голова'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'сущ. (ж.р.)',
  'phrase_de': 'Wir brauchen Ihre [Hilfe].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа браухен ире хильфе',
  'phrase_ru': 'Нам нужна Ваша [помощь].',
  'value_de': 'Hilfe',
  'value_de_trans': 'хильфе',
  'value_ru': 'помощь'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'сущ. (ж.р.)',
  'phrase_de': 'Er hat eine große [Familie].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат айне гросе фамилие',
  'phrase_ru': 'У него большая [семья].',
  'value_de': 'Familie',
  'value_de_trans': 'фамилие',
  'value_ru': 'семья'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das war [erst] der Anfang.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас ва еаст диа анфанг',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это было [только] начало.',
  'value_de': 'erst',
  'value_de_trans': 'еаст',
  'value_ru': 'только'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Sprich [erst] mit dem Arzt.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'шприх еаст мит дем ацт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Поговори [сначала] с врачом.',
  'value_de': 'erst',
  'value_de_trans': 'еаст',
  'value_ru': 'сначала'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das Abendessen ist [fertig].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас абендессен ист феатих',
  'phrase_ru': 'Ужин [готов].',
  'value_de': 'fertig',
  'value_de_trans': 'феатих',
  'value_ru': 'готов'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich habe einen Schatz [gefunden].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе айнен шац гефунден',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я [нашёл] сокровище.',
  'value_de': 'gefunden',
  'value_de_trans': 'гефунден',
  'value_ru': 'нашёл'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': '[Seid] meine Gäste!',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зайд майне гесте',
  'phrase_ru': '[Будьте] моими гостями!',
  'value_de': 'seid',
  'value_de_trans': 'зайд',
  'value_ru': 'будьте'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Was machst du [morgen]?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вас махст ду морген',
  'phrase_ru': 'Что ты делаешь [завтра]?',
  'value_de': 'morgen',
  'value_de_trans': 'морген',
  'value_ru': 'завтра'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'нар.',
  'phrase_de': 'Ruf [sofort] einen Arzt.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'руф зуфорт айнен ацт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вызови [немедленно] врача.',
  'value_de': 'sofort',
  'value_de_trans': 'зуфорт',
  'value_ru': 'немедленно'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'сущ. (с.р.)',
  'phrase_de': 'Das [Kind] lernt schnell.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас кинд леант шнелль',
  'phrase_ru': '[Ребёнок] учится быстро.',
  'value_de': 'Kind',
  'value_de_trans': 'кинд',
  'value_ru': 'ребёнок'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'сущ. (м.р.)',
  'phrase_de': 'Du bist ein guter [Junge].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду бист айн гута юне',
  'phrase_ru': 'Ты хороший [мальчик].',
  'value_de': 'Junge',
  'value_de_trans': 'юне',
  'value_ru': 'мальчик'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ziele gut, [bevor] du schießt.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'циле гут бефоа ду шист',
  'phrase_ru': 'Хорошо прицелься, [прежде чем] стрелять.',
  'value_de': 'bevor',
  'value_de_trans': 'бефоа',
  'value_ru': 'прежде чем'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'сущ. (ж.р.)',
  'phrase_de': 'Wien ist eine schöne [Stadt].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вин ист айне шуне штат',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вена - красивый [город].',
  'value_de': 'Stadt',
  'value_de_trans': 'штат',
  'value_ru': 'город'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'сущ. (с.р.)',
  'phrase_de': 'Jeder hat das [Recht] auf Arbeit.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'еда хат дас рехт ауф арбайт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Каждый имеет [право] на труд.',
  'value_de': 'Recht',
  'value_de_trans': 'рехт',
  'value_ru': 'право'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': '[Warte] bitte auf mich!',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'варте битте ауф мих',
  'phrase_ru': '[Подожди], пожалуйста, меня.',
  'value_de': 'warte',
  'value_de_trans': 'варте',
  'value_ru': 'подожди'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Was denken Sie [darüber]?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вас денкен зи дарюба',
  'phrase_ru': 'Что Вы думаете [об этом]?',
  'value_de': 'darüber',
  'value_de_trans': 'дарюба',
  'value_ru': 'об этом'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'сущ. (с.р.)',
  'phrase_de': 'Das ist das [Ende] meiner Geschichte.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас ист дас энде майна гешихте',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это [конец] моей истории (рассказа).',
  'value_de': 'Ende',
  'value_de_trans': 'энде',
  'value_ru': 'конец'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': '[Allein] zu Hause.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'аллайн цу хаузе',
  'phrase_ru': '[Один] дома.',
  'value_de': 'allein',
  'value_de_trans': 'аллайн',
  'value_ru': 'один'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Kommst du? - [Natürlich]!',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'комст ду натюрлих',
  'phrase_ru': 'Ты придёшь? - [Конечно]!',
  'value_de': 'natürlich',
  'value_de_trans': 'натюрлих',
  'value_ru': 'конечно'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'прил.',
  'phrase_de': 'Was ist deine [natürliche] Haarfarbe?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вас ист дайне натюрлихе хаафабе',
  'phrase_ru': 'Какой у тебя [натуральный] цвет волос?',
  'value_de': 'natürliche',
  'value_de_trans': 'натюрлихе',
  'value_ru': 'натуральный'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': 'eine Antwort [bekommen]',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'айне антворт бекоммен',
  'phrase_ru': '[получать] ответ',
  'value_de': 'bekommen',
  'value_de_trans': 'бекоммен',
  'value_ru': 'получать'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'сущ.',
  'phrase_de': '[Männer] weinen nicht.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'менна вайнен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': '[Мужчины] не плачут.',
  'value_de': 'Männer',
  'value_de_trans': 'менна',
  'value_ru': 'мужчины'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': 'den Namen [vergessen]',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ден намен феагессен',
  'phrase_ru': '[забывать] имя',
  'value_de': 'vergessen',
  'value_de_trans': 'феагессен',
  'value_ru': 'забывать'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich habe kein Geld [dazu].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе кайн гельд дацу',
  'phrase_ru': 'У меня нет денег [на это].',
  'value_de': 'dazu',
  'value_de_trans': 'дацу',
  'value_ru': 'на это'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich mache das [später].',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их махе дас шпита',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я сделаю это [позже].',
  'value_de': 'später',
  'value_de_trans': 'шпита',
  'value_ru': 'позже'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'гл.',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich [wusste], dass er log.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их вусте дасс иа лог',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я [знал], что он лгал.',
  'value_de': 'wusste',
  'value_de_trans': 'вусте',
  'value_ru': 'знал'},
 {'dict': '3',
  'dict_type': 'words',
  'part_of_speech': 'сущ. (с.р.)',
  'phrase_de': 'Die [Augen] sind der Spiegel der Seele.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ди ауген зинд диа шпигель диа зеле',
  'phrase_ru': '[Глаза] - зеркало души.',
  'value_de': 'Augen',
  'value_de_trans': 'ауген',
  'value_ru': 'глаза'}]

words_deutsch_numerals = [{'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [null] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет нулль ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [0] евро.',
  'value_de': 'null',
  'value_de_trans': 'нулль',
  'value_ru': '0'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [eins] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет айнс ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [1] евро.',
  'value_de': 'eins',
  'value_de_trans': 'айнс',
  'value_ru': '1'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [zwei] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет цвай ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [2] евро.',
  'value_de': 'zwei',
  'value_de_trans': 'цвай',
  'value_ru': '2'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [drei] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет драй ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [3] евро.',
  'value_de': 'drei',
  'value_de_trans': 'драй',
  'value_ru': '3'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [vier] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет фиа ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [4] евро.',
  'value_de': 'vier',
  'value_de_trans': 'фиа',
  'value_ru': '4'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [fünf] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет фюнф ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [5] евро.',
  'value_de': 'fünf',
  'value_de_trans': 'фюнф',
  'value_ru': '5'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [sechs] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет зекс ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [6] евро.',
  'value_de': 'sechs',
  'value_de_trans': 'зекс',
  'value_ru': '6'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [sieben] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет зибен ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [7] евро.',
  'value_de': 'sieben',
  'value_de_trans': 'зибен',
  'value_ru': '7'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [acht] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет ахт ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [8] евро.',
  'value_de': 'acht',
  'value_de_trans': 'ахт',
  'value_ru': '8'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [neun] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет нойн ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [9] евро.',
  'value_de': 'neun',
  'value_de_trans': 'нойн',
  'value_ru': '9'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [zehn] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет цин ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [10] евро.',
  'value_de': 'zehn',
  'value_de_trans': 'цин',
  'value_ru': '10'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [elf] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет эльф ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [11] евро.',
  'value_de': 'elf',
  'value_de_trans': 'эльф',
  'value_ru': '11'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [zwölf] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет цвёльф ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [12] евро.',
  'value_de': 'zwölf',
  'value_de_trans': 'цвёльф',
  'value_ru': '12'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [dreizehn] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет драйцин ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [13] евро.',
  'value_de': 'dreizehn',
  'value_de_trans': 'драйцин',
  'value_ru': '13'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [vierzehn] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет фиацин ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [14] евро.',
  'value_de': 'vierzehn',
  'value_de_trans': 'фиацин',
  'value_ru': '14'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [fünfzehn] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет фюнфцин ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [15] евро.',
  'value_de': 'fünfzehn',
  'value_de_trans': 'фюнфцин',
  'value_ru': '15'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [sechzehn] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет зехцин ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [16] евро.',
  'value_de': 'sechzehn',
  'value_de_trans': 'зехцин',
  'value_ru': '16'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [siebzehn] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет зибцин ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [17] евро.',
  'value_de': 'siebzehn',
  'value_de_trans': 'зибцин',
  'value_ru': '17'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [achtzehn] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет ахцин ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [18] евро.',
  'value_de': 'achtzehn',
  'value_de_trans': 'ахцин',
  'value_ru': '18'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [neunzehn] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет нойнцин ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [19] евро.',
  'value_de': 'neunzehn',
  'value_de_trans': 'нойнцин',
  'value_ru': '19'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [zwanzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет цванцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [20] евро.',
  'value_de': 'zwanzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'цванцих',
  'value_ru': '20'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [einundzwanzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет айнундцванцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [21] евро.',
  'value_de': 'einundzwanzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'айнундцванцих',
  'value_ru': '21'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [zweiundzwanzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет цвайундцванцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [22] евро.',
  'value_de': 'zweiundzwanzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'цвайундцванцих',
  'value_ru': '22'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [dreiundzwanzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет драйундцванцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [23] евро.',
  'value_de': 'dreiundzwanzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'драйундцванцих',
  'value_ru': '23'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [vierundzwanzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет фиаундцванцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [24] евро.',
  'value_de': 'vierundzwanzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'фиаундцванцих',
  'value_ru': '24'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [fünfundzwanzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет фюнфундцванцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [25] евро.',
  'value_de': 'fünfundzwanzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'фюнфундцванцих',
  'value_ru': '25'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [sechsundzwanzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет зексундцванцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [26] евро.',
  'value_de': 'sechsundzwanzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'зексундцванцих',
  'value_ru': '26'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [siebenundzwanzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет зибенундцванцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [27] евро.',
  'value_de': 'siebenundzwanzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'зибенундцванцих',
  'value_ru': '27'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [achtundzwanzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет ахтундцванцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [28] евро.',
  'value_de': 'achtundzwanzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'ахтундцванцих',
  'value_ru': '28'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [neunundzwanzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет нойнундцванцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [29] евро.',
  'value_de': 'neunundzwanzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'нойнундцванцих',
  'value_ru': '29'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [dreißig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет драйсих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [30] евро.',
  'value_de': 'dreißig',
  'value_de_trans': 'драйсих',
  'value_ru': '30'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [einunddreißig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет айнундрайсих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [31] евро.',
  'value_de': 'einunddreißig',
  'value_de_trans': 'айнундрайсих',
  'value_ru': '31'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [zweiunddreißig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет цвайундрайсих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [32] евро.',
  'value_de': 'zweiunddreißig',
  'value_de_trans': 'цвайундрайсих',
  'value_ru': '32'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [dreiunddreißig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет драйундрайсих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [33] евро.',
  'value_de': 'dreiunddreißig',
  'value_de_trans': 'драйундрайсих',
  'value_ru': '33'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [vierunddreißig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет фиаундрайсих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [34] евро.',
  'value_de': 'vierunddreißig',
  'value_de_trans': 'фиаундрайсих',
  'value_ru': '34'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [fünfunddreißig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет фюнфундрайсих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [35] евро.',
  'value_de': 'fünfunddreißig',
  'value_de_trans': 'фюнфундрайсих',
  'value_ru': '35'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [sechsunddreißig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет зексундрайсих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [36] евро.',
  'value_de': 'sechsunddreißig',
  'value_de_trans': 'зексундрайсих',
  'value_ru': '36'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [siebenunddreißig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет зибенундрайсих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [37] евро.',
  'value_de': 'siebenunddreißig',
  'value_de_trans': 'зибенундрайсих',
  'value_ru': '37'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [achtunddreißig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет ахтундрайсих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [38] евро.',
  'value_de': 'achtunddreißig',
  'value_de_trans': 'ахтундрайсих',
  'value_ru': '38'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [neununddreißig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет нойнундрайсих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [39] евро.',
  'value_de': 'neununddreißig',
  'value_de_trans': 'нойнундрайсих',
  'value_ru': '39'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [vierzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет фиацих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [40] евро.',
  'value_de': 'vierzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'фиацих',
  'value_ru': '40'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [einundvierzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет айнундфиацих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [41] евро.',
  'value_de': 'einundvierzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'айнундфиацих',
  'value_ru': '41'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [zweiundvierzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет цвайундфиацих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [42] евро.',
  'value_de': 'zweiundvierzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'цвайундфиацих',
  'value_ru': '42'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [dreiundvierzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет драйундфиацих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [43] евро.',
  'value_de': 'dreiundvierzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'драйундфиацих',
  'value_ru': '43'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [vierundvierzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет фирундфиацих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [44] евро.',
  'value_de': 'vierundvierzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'фирундфиацих',
  'value_ru': '44'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [fünfundvierzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет фюнфундфиацих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [45] евро.',
  'value_de': 'fünfundvierzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'фюнфундфиацих',
  'value_ru': '45'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [sechsundvierzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет зексундфиацих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [46] евро.',
  'value_de': 'sechsundvierzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'зексундфиацих',
  'value_ru': '46'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [siebenundvierzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет зибенундфиацих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [47] евро.',
  'value_de': 'siebenundvierzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'зибенундфиацих',
  'value_ru': '47'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [achtundvierzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет ахтундфиацих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [48] евро.',
  'value_de': 'achtundvierzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'ахтундфиацих',
  'value_ru': '48'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [neunundvierzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет нойнундфиацих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [49] евро.',
  'value_de': 'neunundvierzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'нойнундфиацих',
  'value_ru': '49'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [fünfzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет фюнфцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [50] евро.',
  'value_de': 'fünfzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'фюнфцих',
  'value_ru': '50'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [einundfünfzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет айнундфюнфцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [51] евро.',
  'value_de': 'einundfünfzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'айнундфюнфцих',
  'value_ru': '51'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [zweiundfünfzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет цвайундфюнфцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [52] евро.',
  'value_de': 'zweiundfünfzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'цвайундфюнфцих',
  'value_ru': '52'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [dreiundfünfzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет драйундфюнфцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [53] евро.',
  'value_de': 'dreiundfünfzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'драйундфюнфцих',
  'value_ru': '53'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [vierundfünfzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет фиаундфюнфцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [54] евро.',
  'value_de': 'vierundfünfzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'фиаундфюнфцих',
  'value_ru': '54'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [fünfundfünfzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет фюнфундфюнфцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [55] евро.',
  'value_de': 'fünfundfünfzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'фюнфундфюнфцих',
  'value_ru': '55'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [sechsundfünfzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет зексундфюнфцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [56] евро.',
  'value_de': 'sechsundfünfzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'зексундфюнфцих',
  'value_ru': '56'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [siebenundfünfzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет зибенундфюнфцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [57] евро.',
  'value_de': 'siebenundfünfzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'зибенундфюнфцих',
  'value_ru': '57'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [achtundfünfzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет ахтундфюнфцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [58] евро.',
  'value_de': 'achtundfünfzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'ахтундфюнфцих',
  'value_ru': '58'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [neunundfünfzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет нойнундфюнфцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [59] евро.',
  'value_de': 'neunundfünfzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'нойнундфюнфцих',
  'value_ru': '59'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [sechzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет зехцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [60] евро.',
  'value_de': 'sechzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'зехцих',
  'value_ru': '60'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [einundsechzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет айнундзехцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [61] евро.',
  'value_de': 'einundsechzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'айнундзехцих',
  'value_ru': '61'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [zweiundsechzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет цвайундзехцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [62] евро.',
  'value_de': 'zweiundsechzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'цвайундзехцих',
  'value_ru': '62'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [dreiundsechzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет драйундзехцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [63] евро.',
  'value_de': 'dreiundsechzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'драйундзехцих',
  'value_ru': '63'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [vierundsechzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет фиаундзехцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [64] евро.',
  'value_de': 'vierundsechzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'фиаундзехцих',
  'value_ru': '64'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [fünfundsechzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет фюнфундзехцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [65] евро.',
  'value_de': 'fünfundsechzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'фюнфундзехцих',
  'value_ru': '65'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [sechsundsechzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет зексундзехцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [66] евро.',
  'value_de': 'sechsundsechzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'зексундзехцих',
  'value_ru': '66'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [siebenundsechzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет зибенундзехцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [67] евро.',
  'value_de': 'siebenundsechzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'зибенундзехцих',
  'value_ru': '67'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [achtundsechzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет ахтундзехцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [68] евро.',
  'value_de': 'achtundsechzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'ахтундзехцих',
  'value_ru': '68'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [neunundsechzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет нойнундзехцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [69] евро.',
  'value_de': 'neunundsechzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'нойнундзехцих',
  'value_ru': '69'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [siebzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет зибцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [70] евро.',
  'value_de': 'siebzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'зибцих',
  'value_ru': '70'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [einundsiebzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет айнундзибцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [71] евро.',
  'value_de': 'einundsiebzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'айнундзибцих',
  'value_ru': '71'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [zweiundsiebzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет цвайундзибцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [72] евро.',
  'value_de': 'zweiundsiebzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'цвайундзибцих',
  'value_ru': '72'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [dreiundsiebzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет драйундзибцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [73] евро.',
  'value_de': 'dreiundsiebzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'драйундзибцих',
  'value_ru': '73'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [vierundsiebzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет фиаундзибцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [74] евро.',
  'value_de': 'vierundsiebzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'фиаундзибцих',
  'value_ru': '74'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [fünfundsiebzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет фюнфундзибцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [75] евро.',
  'value_de': 'fünfundsiebzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'фюнфундзибцих',
  'value_ru': '75'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [sechsundsiebzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет зексундзибцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [76] евро.',
  'value_de': 'sechsundsiebzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'зексундзибцих',
  'value_ru': '76'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [siebenundsiebzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет зибенундзибцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [77] евро.',
  'value_de': 'siebenundsiebzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'зибенундзибцих',
  'value_ru': '77'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [achtundsiebzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет ахтундзибцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [78] евро.',
  'value_de': 'achtundsiebzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'ахтундзибцих',
  'value_ru': '78'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [neunundsiebzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет нойнундзибцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [79] евро.',
  'value_de': 'neunundsiebzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'нойнундзибцих',
  'value_ru': '79'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [achtzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет ахцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [80] евро.',
  'value_de': 'achtzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'ахцих',
  'value_ru': '80'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [einundachtzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет айнундахцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [81] евро.',
  'value_de': 'einundachtzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'айнундахцих',
  'value_ru': '81'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [zweiundachtzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет цвайундахцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [82] евро.',
  'value_de': 'zweiundachtzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'цвайундахцих',
  'value_ru': '82'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [dreiundachtzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет драйундахцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [83] евро.',
  'value_de': 'dreiundachtzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'драйундахцих',
  'value_ru': '83'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [vierundachtzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет фиаундахцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [84] евро.',
  'value_de': 'vierundachtzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'фиаундахцих',
  'value_ru': '84'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [fünfundachtzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет фюнфундахцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [85] евро.',
  'value_de': 'fünfundachtzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'фюнфундахцих',
  'value_ru': '85'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [sechsundachtzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет зексундахцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [86] евро.',
  'value_de': 'sechsundachtzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'зексундахцих',
  'value_ru': '86'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [siebenundachtzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет зибенундахцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [87] евро.',
  'value_de': 'siebenundachtzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'зибенундахцих',
  'value_ru': '87'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [achtundachtzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет ахтундахцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [88] евро.',
  'value_de': 'achtundachtzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'ахтундахцих',
  'value_ru': '88'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [neunundachtzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет нойнундахцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [89] евро.',
  'value_de': 'neunundachtzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'нойнундахцих',
  'value_ru': '89'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [neunzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет нойнцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [90] евро.',
  'value_de': 'neunzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'нойнцих',
  'value_ru': '90'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [einundneunzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет айнунднойнцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [91] евро.',
  'value_de': 'einundneunzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'айнунднойнцих',
  'value_ru': '91'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [zweiundneunzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет цвайунднойнцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [92] евро.',
  'value_de': 'zweiundneunzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'цвайунднойнцих',
  'value_ru': '92'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [dreiundneunzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет драйунднойнцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [93] евро.',
  'value_de': 'dreiundneunzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'драйунднойнцих',
  'value_ru': '93'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [vierundneunzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет фиаунднойнцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [94] евро.',
  'value_de': 'vierundneunzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'фиаунднойнцих',
  'value_ru': '94'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [fünfundneunzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет фюнфунднойнцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [95] евро.',
  'value_de': 'fünfundneunzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'фюнфунднойнцих',
  'value_ru': '95'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [sechsundneunzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет зексунднойнцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [96] евро.',
  'value_de': 'sechsundneunzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'зексунднойнцих',
  'value_ru': '96'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [siebenundneunzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет зибенунднойнцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [97] евро.',
  'value_de': 'siebenundneunzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'зибенунднойнцих',
  'value_ru': '97'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [achtundneunzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет ахтунднойнцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [98] евро.',
  'value_de': 'achtundneunzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'ахтунднойнцих',
  'value_ru': '98'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [neunundneunzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет нойнунднойнцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [99] евро.',
  'value_de': 'neunundneunzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'нойнунднойнцих',
  'value_ru': '99'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [hundert] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет хундат ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [100] евро.',
  'value_de': 'hundert',
  'value_de_trans': 'хундат',
  'value_ru': '100'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [einhunderteins] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет айнхундатайнс ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [101] евро.',
  'value_de': 'einhunderteins',
  'value_de_trans': 'айнхундатайнс',
  'value_ru': '101'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [einhundertzwei] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет айнхундатцвай ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [102] евро.',
  'value_de': 'einhundertzwei',
  'value_de_trans': 'айнхундатцвай',
  'value_ru': '102'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [einhundertdreiundzwanzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет айнхундатдрайундцванцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [123] евро.',
  'value_de': 'einhundertdreiundzwanzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'айнхундатдрайундцванцих',
  'value_ru': '123'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [einhundertneunundsiebzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет айнхундатнойнундзибцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [179] евро.',
  'value_de': 'einhundertneunundsiebzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'айнхундатнойнундзибцих',
  'value_ru': '179'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [einhundertachtzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет айнхундатахцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [180] евро.',
  'value_de': 'einhundertachtzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'айнхундатахцих',
  'value_ru': '180'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [einhundertachtundachtzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет айнхундатахтундахцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [188] евро.',
  'value_de': 'einhundertachtundachtzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'айнхундатахтундахцих',
  'value_ru': '188'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [zweihundert] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет цвайхундат ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [200] евро.',
  'value_de': 'zweihundert',
  'value_de_trans': 'цвайхундат',
  'value_ru': '200'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [zweihunderteins] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет цвайхундатайнс ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [201] евро.',
  'value_de': 'zweihunderteins',
  'value_de_trans': 'цвайхундатайнс',
  'value_ru': '201'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [zweihundertzwei] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет цвайхундатцвай ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [202] евро.',
  'value_de': 'zweihundertzwei',
  'value_de_trans': 'цвайхундатцвай',
  'value_ru': '202'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [zweihundertvierzehn] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет цвайхундатфиацин ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [214] евро.',
  'value_de': 'zweihundertvierzehn',
  'value_de_trans': 'цвайхундатфиацин',
  'value_ru': '214'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [zweihundertachtzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет цвайхундатахцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [280] евро.',
  'value_de': 'zweihundertachtzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'цвайхундатахцих',
  'value_ru': '280'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [dreihundert] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет драйхундат ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [300] евро.',
  'value_de': 'dreihundert',
  'value_de_trans': 'драйхундат',
  'value_ru': '300'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [dreihundertdreißig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет драйхундатдрайсих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [330] евро.',
  'value_de': 'dreihundertdreißig',
  'value_de_trans': 'драйхундатдрайсих',
  'value_ru': '330'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [dreihundertachtzig] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет драйхундатахцих ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [380] евро.',
  'value_de': 'dreihundertachtzig',
  'value_de_trans': 'драйхундатахцих',
  'value_ru': '380'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [vierhundert] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет фиахундат ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [400] евро.',
  'value_de': 'vierhundert',
  'value_de_trans': 'фиахундат',
  'value_ru': '400'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [fünfhundert] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет фюнфхундат ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [500] евро.',
  'value_de': 'fünfhundert',
  'value_de_trans': 'фюнфхундат',
  'value_ru': '500'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [sechshundert] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет зексхундат ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [600] евро.',
  'value_de': 'sechshundert',
  'value_de_trans': 'зексхундат',
  'value_ru': '600'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [siebenhundert] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет зибенхундат ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [700] евро.',
  'value_de': 'siebenhundert',
  'value_de_trans': 'зибенхундат',
  'value_ru': '700'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [achthundert] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет ахтхундат ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [800] евро.',
  'value_de': 'achthundert',
  'value_de_trans': 'ахтхундат',
  'value_ru': '800'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [neunhundert] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет нойнхундат ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [900] евро.',
  'value_de': 'neunhundert',
  'value_de_trans': 'нойнхундат',
  'value_ru': '900'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [tausend] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет таузенд ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [1000] евро.',
  'value_de': 'tausend',
  'value_de_trans': 'таузенд',
  'value_ru': '1000'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [eintausendeins] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет айнтаузендайнс ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [1001] евро.',
  'value_de': 'eintausendeins',
  'value_de_trans': 'айнтаузендайнс',
  'value_ru': '1001'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [eintausendzwei] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет айнтаузендцвай ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [1002] евро.',
  'value_de': 'eintausendzwei',
  'value_de_trans': 'айнтаузендцвай',
  'value_ru': '1002'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [eintausenddrei] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет айнтаузендрай ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [1003] евро.',
  'value_de': 'eintausenddrei',
  'value_de_trans': 'айнтаузендрай',
  'value_ru': '1003'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [eintausendacht] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет айнтаузендахт ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [1008] евро.',
  'value_de': 'eintausendacht',
  'value_de_trans': 'айнтаузендахт',
  'value_ru': '1008'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [zweitausend] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет цвайтаузенд ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [2000] евро.',
  'value_de': 'zweitausend',
  'value_de_trans': 'цвайтаузенд',
  'value_ru': '2000'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [zehntausend] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет цинтаузенд ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [10000] евро.',
  'value_de': 'zehntausend',
  'value_de_trans': 'цинтаузенд',
  'value_ru': '10000'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [einhunderttausend] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет айнхундаттаузенд ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [100000] евро.',
  'value_de': 'einhunderttausend',
  'value_de_trans': 'айнхундаттаузенд',
  'value_ru': '100000'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [eine Million] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет айне мильён ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [1000000] евро.',
  'value_de': 'eine Million',
  'value_de_trans': 'айне мильён',
  'value_ru': '1000000'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [eine Million eins] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет айне мильён айнс ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [1000001] евро.',
  'value_de': 'eine Million eins',
  'value_de_trans': 'айне мильён айнс',
  'value_ru': '1000001'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [eine Milliarde] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет айне мильярде ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [1000000000] евро.',
  'value_de': 'eine Milliarde',
  'value_de_trans': 'айне мильярде',
  'value_ru': '1000000000'},
 {'dict': '4',
  'dict_type': 'numerals',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das kostet [zwei Milliarden] Euro.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас костет цвай мильярдн ойру',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это стоит [2000000000] евро.',
  'value_de': 'zwei Milliarden',
  'value_de_trans': 'цвай мильярдн',
  'value_ru': '2000000000'}]

words_deutsch_beginners = [{'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Guten Tag, Rolf!',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'гутен таг рольф',
  'phrase_ru': 'Добрый день, Рольф!',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Guten Morgen, Frau Stein!',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'гутен морген фрау штайн',
  'phrase_ru': 'Доброе утро, госпожа Штайн!',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Guten Abend, Paul!',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'гутен абенд пауль',
  'phrase_ru': 'Добрый вечер, Пауль!',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Wie heißen Sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ви хайсен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'Как Вас зовут?',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Sind Sie Freunde?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зинд зи фройнде',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы друзья?',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich warte auf dich.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их варте ауф дих',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я жду тебя.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich komme aus Russland.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их комме аус русланд',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я приехал из России.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Kommen Sie aus Moskau?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'коммен зи аус москау',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы приехали из Москвы?',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Wo wohnen Sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'во вонен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'Где вы живете?',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Sprechen Sie Deutsch?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'шпрехен зи дойч',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы говорите по-немецки?',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich spreche Deutsch.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их шпрехе дойч',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я говорю по-немецки.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Sprechen Sie Russisch?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'шпрехен зи руссиш',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы говорите по-русски?',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Verstehen Sie Russisch?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ферштейн зи руссиш',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы понимаете по-русски?',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das ist sehr schön!',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас ист зеа шун',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это очень хорошо!',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Wo arbeiten Sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'во арбайтен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'Где Вы работаете?',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ist das Ihre Familie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ист дас ире фамилие',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это Ваша семья?',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das ist meine Frau.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас ист майне фрау',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это моя жена.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ist das Ihr Mann?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ист дас иа ман',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это Ваш муж?',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das sind meine Kinder.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас зинд майне кинда',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это мои дети.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das ist mein Haus.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас ист майн хаус',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это мой дом.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Wie heißt Ihr Sohn?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ви хайст иа зун',
  'phrase_ru': 'Как зовут Вашего сына?',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ist das Ihre Schule?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ист дас ире шуле',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это Ваша школа?',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Wo wohnen Ihre Eltern?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'во вонен ире эльтан',
  'phrase_ru': 'Где живут Ваши родители?',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Wo arbeitet Ihr Vater?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'во арбайтет иа фата',
  'phrase_ru': 'Где работает Ваш отец?',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das ist meine Mutter.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас ист майне мутта',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это моя мать.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Sind das Ihre Brüder?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зинд дас ире брюда',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это Ваши братья?',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Wie heißt Ihre Schwester?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ви хайст ире швеста',
  'phrase_ru': 'Как зовут Вашу сестру?',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich liebe deine Schwester.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их либе дайне швеста',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я люблю твою сестру.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Wir gehen nach Hause.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа геен нах хаузе',
  'phrase_ru': 'Мы идем домой.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Fährst du nach Deutschland?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ферст ду нах дойчланд',
  'phrase_ru': 'Ты едешь в Германию?',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Leben Sie in Dresden?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'лебен зи ин дрисдн',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы живете в Дрездене?',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich lese dieses Buch.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их лезе дизес бух',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я читаю эту книгу.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich wohne mit meinen Eltern.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их воне мит майнен эльтан',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я живу с моими родителями.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Wo steht die Lampe?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'во штит ди лампе',
  'phrase_ru': 'Где стоит лампа?',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Wo liegt das Buch?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'во лигт дас бух',
  'phrase_ru': 'Где лежит книга?',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich stehe hier.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их штее хиа',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я стою здесь.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich verstehe dich nicht.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их ферштее дих нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я тебя не понимаю.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Du machst die Hausaufgabe.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду махст ди хаузауфгабе',
  'phrase_ru': 'Ты делаешь домашнее задание.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Kannst du mir helfen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'канст ду миа хельфен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Ты можешь мне помочь?',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich mag Eis.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их маг айс',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я люблю мороженое.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Gehen wir nach Hause?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'геен виа нах хаузе',
  'phrase_ru': 'Мы идем домой?',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Wo ist die Küche?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'во ист ди кюхе',
  'phrase_ru': 'Где кухня?',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich habe Hunger.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе хуна',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я голоден.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das ist mein Freund Werner.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас ист майн фройнд верна',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это мой друг Вернер.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich verstehe das.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их ферштее дас',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я понимаю это.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Wir wissen alles.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа виссен аллес',
  'phrase_ru': 'Мы всё знаем.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Sind Sie Herr Kunze?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зинд зи херр кунце',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы господин Кунце?',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Sind Sie Frau Müller?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зинд зи фрау мюла',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы госпожа Мюллер?',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich heiße Fred Neumann.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хайсе фред нойман',
  'phrase_ru': 'Меня зовут Фред Нойман.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Woher sind Sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вохеа зинд зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'Откуда Вы?',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Woher kommen Sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вохеа коммен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'Откуда Вы прибыли?',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Kommen Sie aus Dresden?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'коммен зи аус дрисдн',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы приехали из Дрездена?',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Kommen Sie auch aus Moskau?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'коммен зи аух аус москау',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы тоже приехали из Москвы?',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich verstehe etwas Deutsch.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их ферштее этвас дойч',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я немного понимаю по-немецки.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich wohne nicht in Dresden.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их воне нихт ин дрисдн',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я живу не в Дрездене.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich spreche etwas Englisch.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их шпрехе этвас энглиш',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я говорю немного по-английски.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Wer ist das? Das ist Monika.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа ист дас дас ист моника',
  'phrase_ru': 'Кто это? Это Моника.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Wie alt sind Sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ви альт зинд зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'Сколько вам лет?',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Max arbeitet in Dresden.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'макс арбайтет ин дрисдн',
  'phrase_ru': 'Макс работает в Дрездене.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Mein Vorname ist Michael.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'майн форнаме ист михаэль',
  'phrase_ru': 'Мое имя Михаэль.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Verstehen Sie alles?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ферштейн зи аллес',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы всё понимаете?',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ist das richtig?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ист дас рихтих',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это правильно?',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Haben Sie einen Bruder?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи айнен бруда',
  'phrase_ru': 'У вас есть брат?',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich komme morgen.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их комме морген',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я приду завтра.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich komme heute abend.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их комме хойте абенд',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я приду сегодня вечером.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Guten Appetit!',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'гутен аппетит',
  'phrase_ru': 'Приятного аппетита!',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Der Salat ist sehr gut.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'диа залат ист зеа гут',
  'phrase_ru': 'Салат очень хороший.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Möchten Sie Kaffee?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'мёхтен зи каффи',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы хотите кофе?',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich möchte gern Tee.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их мёхте герн ти',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я хотел бы чаю.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich bin glücklich.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их бин глюклих',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я счастлив.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das ist unser Hotel.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас ист унза хотель',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это наш отель.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Wo ist mein Zimmer?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'во ист майн цимма',
  'phrase_ru': 'Где моя комната?',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Alles ist in Ordnung.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'аллес ист ин орднун',
  'phrase_ru': 'Все в порядке.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Da ist Ihre Rechnung.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'да ист ире рехнун',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вот Ваш счет.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie spricht sehr schnell.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи шприхт зеа шнелль',
  'phrase_ru': 'Она говорит очень быстро.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Bitte ein Glas Wasser!',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'битте айн глас васса',
  'phrase_ru': 'Пожалуйста, стакан воды!',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ist das Ihr Buch?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ист дас иа бух',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это Ваша книга?',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Er versteht kein Wort.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа ферштейт кайн ворт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Он не понимает ни слова.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Kommen Sie allein?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'коммен зи аллайн',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы приехали один?',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Eins plus eins ist zwei.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'айнс плус айнс ист цвай',
  'phrase_ru': 'Один плюс один - два.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Drei minus eins ist zwei.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'драй минус айнс ист цвай',
  'phrase_ru': 'Три минус один - два.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Zwei mal zwei ist vier.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'цвай маль цвай ист фиа',
  'phrase_ru': 'Дважды два - четыре.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Zwei plus drei ist fünf.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'цвай плус драй ист фюнф',
  'phrase_ru': 'Два плюс три - пять.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Willkommen in Leipzig!',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виллькоммен ин лайпцих',
  'phrase_ru': 'Добро пожаловать в Лейпциг!',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Sind Sie Arzt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зинд зи ацт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы врач?',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich bin Lehrer.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их бин лира',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я учитель (преподаватель).',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Wann sind Sie geboren?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ванн зинд зи геборен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Когда Вы родились?',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Das ist für Sie.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дас ист фюа зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'Это для Вас.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich sehe nichts.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их зие нихтс',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я ничего не вижу.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Auf Wiedersehen! Gute Nacht!',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ауф видазеен гуте нахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'До свидания! Спокойной ночи!',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Haben Sie eine Wohnung?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи айне вонун',
  'phrase_ru': 'У Вас есть квартира?',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ist die Wohnung groß?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ист ди вонун грос',
  'phrase_ru': 'Квартира большая?',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Haben Sie einen Wagen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи айнен ваген',
  'phrase_ru': 'У Вас есть машина?',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich verstehe Deutsch. Und Sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их ферштее дойч унд зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я понимаю по-немецки. А Вы?',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ich komme aus der Schweiz.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их комме аус диа швайц',
  'phrase_ru': 'Я приехал из Швейцарии.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ja, wir kommen aus Berlin.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'я виа коммен аус белин',
  'phrase_ru': 'Да, мы приехали из Берлина.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ja, er wohnt in Leipzig.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'я иа вонт ин лайпцих',
  'phrase_ru': 'Да, он живет в Лейпциге.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Sind Sie allein? Ja.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зинд зи аллайн я',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы один? Да.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Er ist mein Kollege.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа ист майн коллеге',
  'phrase_ru': 'Он мой коллега.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '101',
  'dict_type': 'beginners',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Was sind Sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вас зинд зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'Кто Вы (по профессии)?',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''}]

words_deutsch_proverbs = [{'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Alle Flüsse fließen ins Meer.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'алле флюссе флисен инс миа',
  'phrase_ru': 'Все реки текут в море.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Aller Anfang ist schwer.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'аля анфанг ист швиа',
  'phrase_ru': 'Любое начало тяжело (первый блин комом).',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Aller guten Dinge sind drei.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'аля гутен дине зинд драй',
  'phrase_ru': 'Всех хороших вещей — по три (Бог троицу любит).',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Alte Liebe rostet nicht.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'альте либе ростет нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Старая любовь не ржавеет (старый друг лучше новых двух).',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Andere Länder, andere Sitten.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'андере ленда андере зиттен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Другие страны — другие обычаи (в чужой монастырь со своим '
               'уставом не ходят).',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Auch ein blindes Huhn findet mal ein Korn.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'аух айн блиндес хун финдет маль айн корн',
  'phrase_ru': 'Даже слепая курица иногда находит зёрнышко (чем чёрт не '
               'шутит).',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Besser spät als nie.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'бесса шпит альц ни',
  'phrase_ru': 'Лучше поздно, чем никогда.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Gebranntes Kind scheut das Feuer.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'гебрантес кинд шойт дас фоя',
  'phrase_ru': 'Обожжённый ребёнок боится огня (кто обжегся на молоке теперь '
               'на воду дует).',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Geduld bringt Rosen.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'гедульд брингт розен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Терпение приносит розы (терпение и труд все перетрут).',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Gute Saat, gute Ernte.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'гуте зат гуте эрнте',
  'phrase_ru': 'Хорошее семя — хороший урожай (что посеешь, то и пожнёшь).',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Glück und Glas, wie leicht bricht das.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'глюк унд глас ви лайхт брихт дас',
  'phrase_ru': 'Счастье и стекло, как же они бьются легко.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Der Appetit kommt beim Essen.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'диа аппетит комт байм эссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Аппетит приходит во время еды.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Die dümmsten Bauern haben die dicksten Kartoffeln.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ди дюмстен бауан хабен ди дикстен картоффельн',
  'phrase_ru': 'У самых глупых крестьян — самая большая картошка (дуракам '
               'везёт).',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Die Liebe geht durch den Magen.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ди либе гет дуих дин маген',
  'phrase_ru': 'Любовь приходит через желудок (путь к сердцу мужчины лежит '
               'через желудок).',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Durch Fehler wird man klug.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'дуих фила вёд ман клуг',
  'phrase_ru': 'Через ошибки становятся умным (на ошибках учатся).',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Eine Schwalbe macht noch keinen Sommer.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'айне швальбе махт нох кайнен зомма',
  'phrase_ru': 'Одна ласточка ещё не делает лета (одна ласточка весны не '
               'делает).',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ende gut, alles gut.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'энде гут аллес гут',
  'phrase_ru': 'Конец хорош — всё хорошо (всё хорошо, что хорошо кончается).',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Erst wägen, dann wagen.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'еаст веген данн ваген',
  'phrase_ru': 'Сперва обдумать, потом отважиться (семь раз отмерь, один '
               'отрежь).',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Es ist nicht alles Gold, was glänzt.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс ист нихт аллес гольд вас гленцт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Не всё то золото, что блестит.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Hochmut kommt vor dem Fall.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хохмут комт фоа дим фалль',
  'phrase_ru': 'Высокомерие приходит перед падением.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'In der Kürze liegt die Würze.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ин диа кюрце лигт ди вюрце',
  'phrase_ru': 'В краткости вся приправа (краткость — сестра таланта).',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Jedem das Seine.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'едем дас зайне',
  'phrase_ru': 'Каждому свое (о вкусах не спорят).',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Jeder ist seines Glückes Schmied.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'еда ист зайнес глюккес шмид',
  'phrase_ru': 'Каждый — кузнец своего счастья (всякий человек своему счастью '
               'кузнец).',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Kleider Machen Leute.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'клайда махен лойте',
  'phrase_ru': 'Одежда делает людей (встречают по одежке).',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Klein, aber fein.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'клайн аба файн',
  'phrase_ru': 'Маленький, но хороший (мал, да удал).',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Kommt Zeit, kommt Rat.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'комт цайт комт рат',
  'phrase_ru': 'Придет время, придет совет (утро вечера мудренее).',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Liebe macht blind.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'либе махт блинд',
  'phrase_ru': 'Любовь делает слепым (любовь зла — полюбишь и козла).',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Lügen haben kurze Beine.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'люген хабен курце байне',
  'phrase_ru': 'У лжи короткие ноги (всё тайное становится явным).',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Liebe duldet keinen Zwang.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'либе дульдет кайнен цванг',
  'phrase_ru': 'Любовь не терпит принуждения (насильно мил не будешь).',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Morgenstund hat Gold im Mund.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'моргенштунд хат гольд им мунд',
  'phrase_ru': 'У раннего часа золото в устах (кто рано встаёт, тому Бог '
               'даёт).',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Nach Faulheit folgt Krankheit.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'нах фаульхайт фольгт кранкхайт',
  'phrase_ru': 'За ленью следует болезнь (лень до добра не доводит).',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ohne Fleiß kein Preis.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'уне флайс кайн прайс',
  'phrase_ru': 'Без старания не бывает награды (без труда не вытащить и рыбки '
               'из пруда).',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Ost und West, daheim das Best.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ост унд вест дахайм дас бест',
  'phrase_ru': 'Восток ли, запад ли, а дома лучше (в гостях хорошо, а дома '
               'лучше).',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Papier ist geduldig.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'папир ист гедульдиг',
  'phrase_ru': 'Бумага терпелива (бумага всё стерпит).',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Reden ist Silber, Schweigen ist Gold.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'реден ист зильба швайген ист гольд',
  'phrase_ru': 'Говорить — серебро, молчание — золото (слово — серебро, '
               'молчание — золото).',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Samt am Kragen, Hunger im Magen.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'замт ам краген хуна им маген',
  'phrase_ru': 'Бархат на воротнике, голод в желудке (на брюхе шёлк, а в брюхе '
               'щёлк).',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Stille Wasser sind tief.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'штилле васса зинд тиф',
  'phrase_ru': 'Тихие воды глубоки (в тихом омуте черти водятся).',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Säge nicht an dem Ast, auf dem du sitzt.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зеге нихт ан дим аст ауф дим ду зицт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Не пили сук, на котором сидишь.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Schlafende Hunde soll man nicht wecken.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'шлафенде хунде золль ман нихт веккен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Лучше не будить спящих собак (не буди лихо, пока оно тихо).',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Schmiede das Eisen solange es glüht.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'шмиде дас айзен зулане эс глют',
  'phrase_ru': 'Куй железо, пока оно раскалено (куй железо, пока горячо).',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Seinem Schicksal kann niemand entgehen.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зайнем шиккзаль канн ниманд энтгеен',
  'phrase_ru': 'От своей судьбы никто не может уйти (от судьбы не уйдёшь).',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Übung macht den Meister.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'убун махт дин майста',
  'phrase_ru': 'Упражнение делает умельца (повторение — мать учения).',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Wer nicht wagt, der nicht gewinnt.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа нихт вагт диа нихт гевинт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Кто не отваживается, тот не выигрывает (кто не рискует, тот не '
               'пьёт шампанское).',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Wer will haben, der muss graben.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа вилль хабен диа мусс грабен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Кто хочет иметь, тот должен и копать (любишь кататься, люби и '
               'саночки возить).',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Wer Wind sät, wird Sturm ernten.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа винд зет вёд штурм еантн',
  'phrase_ru': 'Кто посеет ветер, пожнёт бурю.',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Wes Brot ich ess, des Lied ich sing.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вес брут их эсс дес лид их зинг',
  'phrase_ru': 'Чей хлеб я ем, того песню я и пою (кто платит, тот и '
               'заказывает музыку).',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Wie eine Made im Speck leben.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ви айне маде им шпек лебен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Жить как червяк в сале (кататься как сыр в масле).',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Wie ein Schwein vor dem Uhrwerk stehen.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ви айн швайн фоа дим уаверк штеен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Стоять как свинья перед часовым механизмом (глядеть как баран '
               'на новые ворота).',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Zu spät ist zu spät.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'цу шпит ист цу шпит',
  'phrase_ru': 'Слишком поздно есть слишком поздно (кто не успел — тот '
               'опоздал).',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''},
 {'dict': '102',
  'dict_type': 'proverbs',
  'part_of_speech': '',
  'phrase_de': 'Zu viele Köche verderben den Brei.',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'цу филе кёхе феадебен дин брай',
  'phrase_ru': 'Слишком много поваров только портят кашу (у семи нянек — дитя '
               'без глазу).',
  'value_de': '',
  'value_de_trans': '',
  'value_ru': ''}]

words_deutsch_phrases = [{'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich bin',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их бин',
  'phrase_ru': 'я есть',
  'prompt': 'sein — быть,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du bist',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду бист',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты есть',
  'prompt': 'sein — быть,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er ist',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа ист',
  'phrase_ru': 'он есть',
  'prompt': 'sein — быть,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie ist',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи ист',
  'phrase_ru': 'она есть',
  'prompt': 'sein — быть,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es ist',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс ист',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно есть',
  'prompt': 'sein — быть,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir sind',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа зинд',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы есть',
  'prompt': 'sein — быть,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr seid',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа зинд',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы есть (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'sein — быть,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie sind',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи зинд',
  'phrase_ru': 'они есть',
  'prompt': 'sein — быть,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie sind',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи зинд',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы есть (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'sein — быть,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich bin nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их бин нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не есть',
  'prompt': 'sein — быть,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du bist nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду бист нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не есть',
  'prompt': 'sein — быть,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er ist nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа ист нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не есть',
  'prompt': 'sein — быть,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie ist nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи ист нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не есть',
  'prompt': 'sein — быть,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es ist nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс ист нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не есть',
  'prompt': 'sein — быть,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir sind nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа зинд нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не есть',
  'prompt': 'sein — быть,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr seid nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа зинд нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не есть (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'sein — быть,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie sind nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи зинд нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не есть',
  'prompt': 'sein — быть,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie sind nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи зинд нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не есть (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'sein — быть,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich spreche',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их шпрехе',
  'phrase_ru': 'я говорю',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du sprichst',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду шприхст',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты говоришь',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er spricht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа шприхт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он говорит',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie spricht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи шприхт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она говорит',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es spricht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс шприхт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно говорит',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir sprechen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа шпрехен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы говорим',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr sprecht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа шпрехт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы говорите (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie sprechen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи шпрехен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они говорят',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie sprechen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи шпрехен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы говорите (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich spreche nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их шпрехе нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не говорю',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du sprichst nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду шприхст нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не говоришь',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er spricht nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа шприхт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не говорит',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie spricht nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи шприхт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не говорит',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es spricht nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс шприхт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не говорит',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir sprechen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа шпрехен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не говорим',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr sprecht nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа шпрехт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не говорите (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie sprechen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи шпрехен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не говорят',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie sprechen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи шпрехен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не говорите (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'spreche ich?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'шпрехе их',
  'phrase_ru': 'я говорю?',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sprichst du?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'шприхст ду',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты говоришь?',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'spricht er?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'шприхт иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'он говорит?',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'spricht sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'шприхт зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'она говорит?',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'spricht es?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'шприхт эс',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно говорит?',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sprechen wir?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'шпрехен виа',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы говорим?',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sprecht ihr?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'шпрехт иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы говорите? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sprechen sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'шпрехен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'они говорят?',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sprechen Sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'шпрехен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы говорите? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe gesprochen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе гешпрохен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я говорил',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast gesprochen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст гешпрохен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты говорил',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat gesprochen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат гешпрохен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он говорил',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat gesprochen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат гешпрохен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она говорила',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat gesprochen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат гешпрохен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно говорило',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben gesprochen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен гешпрохен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы говорили',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt gesprochen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт гешпрохен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы говорили (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben gesprochen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен гешпрохен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они говорили',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben gesprochen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен гешпрохен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы говорили (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe nicht gesprochen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе нихт гешпрохен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не говорил',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast nicht gesprochen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст нихт гешпрохен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не говорил',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat nicht gesprochen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат нихт гешпрохен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не говорил',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat nicht gesprochen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат нихт гешпрохен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не говорила',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat nicht gesprochen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат нихт гешпрохен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не говорило',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben nicht gesprochen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен нихт гешпрохен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не говорили',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt nicht gesprochen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт нихт гешпрохен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не говорили (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben nicht gesprochen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт гешпрохен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не говорили',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben nicht gesprochen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт гешпрохен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не говорили (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habe ich gesprochen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабе их гешпрохен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я говорил?',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hast du gesprochen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хаст ду гешпрохен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты говорил?',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat er gesprochen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат иа гешпрохен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он говорил?',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat sie gesprochen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат зи гешпрохен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она говорила?',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat es gesprochen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат эс гешпрохен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно говорило?',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben wir gesprochen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен виа гешпрохен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы говорили?',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habt ihr gesprochen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабт иа гешпрохен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы говорили? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben sie gesprochen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи гешпрохен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они говорили?',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben Sie gesprochen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи гешпрохен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы говорили? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde sprechen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде шпрехен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я буду говорить',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst sprechen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст шпрехен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты будешь говорить',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird sprechen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд шпрехен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он будет говорить',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird sprechen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд шпрехен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она будет говорить',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird sprechen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд шпрехен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно будет говорить',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden sprechen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн шпрехен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы будем говорить',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet sprechen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет шпрехен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы будете говорить (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden sprechen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн шпрехен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они будут говорить',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden sprechen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн шпрехен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы будете говорить (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde nicht sprechen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде нихт шпрехен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не буду говорить',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst nicht sprechen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст нихт шпрехен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не будешь говорить',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird nicht sprechen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд нихт шпрехен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не будет говорить',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird nicht sprechen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд нихт шпрехен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не будет говорить',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird nicht sprechen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд нихт шпрехен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не будет говорить',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden nicht sprechen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн нихт шпрехен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не будем говорить',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet nicht sprechen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет нихт шпрехен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не будете говорить (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden nicht sprechen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт шпрехен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не будут говорить',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden nicht sprechen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт шпрехен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не будете говорить (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werde ich sprechen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веаде их шпрехен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я буду говорить?',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wirst du sprechen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вирст ду шпрехен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты будешь говорить?',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird er sprechen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд иа шпрехен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он будет говорить?',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird sie sprechen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд зи шпрехен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она будет говорить?',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird es sprechen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд эс шпрехен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно будет говорить?',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden wir sprechen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн виа шпрехен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы будем говорить?',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werdet ihr sprechen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадет иа шпрехен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы будете говорить? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden sie sprechen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи шпрехен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они будут говорить?',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden Sie sprechen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи шпрехен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы будете говорить? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'sprechen — говорить,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich mache',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их махе',
  'phrase_ru': 'я делаю',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du machst',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду махст',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты делаешь',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er macht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа махт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он делает',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie macht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи махт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она делает',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es macht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс махт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно делает',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir machen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа махен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы делаем',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr macht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа махт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы делаете (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie machen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи махен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они делают',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie machen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи махен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы делаете (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich mache nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их махе нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не делаю',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du machst nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду махст нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не делаешь',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er macht nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа махт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не делает',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie macht nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи махт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не делает',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es macht nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс махт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не делает',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir machen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа махен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не делаем',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr macht nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа махт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не делаете (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie machen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи махен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не делают',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie machen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи махен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не делаете (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'mache ich?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'махе их',
  'phrase_ru': 'я делаю?',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'machst du?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'махст ду',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты делаешь?',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'macht er?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'махт иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'он делает?',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'macht sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'махт зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'она делает?',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'macht es?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'махт эс',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно делает?',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'machen wir?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'махен виа',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы делаем?',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'macht ihr?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'махт иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы делаете? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'machen sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'махен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'они делают?',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'machen Sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'махен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы делаете? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe gemacht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе гемахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я делал',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast gemacht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст гемахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты делал',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat gemacht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат гемахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он делал',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat gemacht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат гемахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она делала',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat gemacht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат гемахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно делало',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben gemacht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен гемахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы делали',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt gemacht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт гемахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы делали (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben gemacht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен гемахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они делали',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben gemacht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен гемахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы делали (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe nicht gemacht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе нихт гемахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не делал',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast nicht gemacht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст нихт гемахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не делал',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat nicht gemacht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат нихт гемахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не делал',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat nicht gemacht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат нихт гемахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не делала',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat nicht gemacht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат нихт гемахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не делало',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben nicht gemacht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен нихт гемахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не делали',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt nicht gemacht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт нихт гемахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не делали (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben nicht gemacht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт гемахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не делали',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben nicht gemacht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт гемахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не делали (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habe ich gemacht?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабе их гемахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я делал?',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hast du gemacht?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хаст ду гемахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты делал?',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat er gemacht?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат иа гемахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он делал?',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat sie gemacht?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат зи гемахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она делала?',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat es gemacht?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат эс гемахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно делало?',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben wir gemacht?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен виа гемахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы делали?',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habt ihr gemacht?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабт иа гемахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы делали? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben sie gemacht?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи гемахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они делали?',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben Sie gemacht?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи гемахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы делали? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde machen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде махен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я буду делать',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst machen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст махен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты будешь делать',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird machen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд махен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он будет делать',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird machen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд махен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она будет делать',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird machen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд махен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно будет делать',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden machen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн махен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы будем делать',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet machen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет махен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы будете делать (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden machen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн махен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они будут делать',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden machen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн махен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы будете делать (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde nicht machen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде нихт махен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не буду делать',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst nicht machen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст нихт махен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не будешь делать',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird nicht machen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд нихт махен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не будет делать',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird nicht machen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд нихт махен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не будет делать',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird nicht machen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд нихт махен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не будет делать',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden nicht machen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн нихт махен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не будем делать',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet nicht machen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет нихт махен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не будете делать (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden nicht machen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт махен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не будут делать',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden nicht machen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт махен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не будете делать (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werde ich machen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веаде их махен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я буду делать?',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wirst du machen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вирст ду махен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты будешь делать?',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird er machen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд иа махен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он будет делать?',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird sie machen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд зи махен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она будет делать?',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird es machen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд эс махен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно будет делать?',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden wir machen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн виа махен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы будем делать?',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werdet ihr machen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадет иа махен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы будете делать? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden sie machen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи махен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они будут делать?',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden Sie machen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи махен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы будете делать? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'machen — делать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich denke',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их денке',
  'phrase_ru': 'я думаю',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du denkst',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду денкст',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты думаешь',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er denkt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа денкт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он думает',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie denkt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи денкт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она думает',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es denkt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс денкт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно думает',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir denken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа денкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы думаем',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr denkt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа денкт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы думаете (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie denken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи денкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они думают',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie denken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи денкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы думаете (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich denke nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их денке нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не думаю',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du denkst nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду денкст нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не думаешь',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er denkt nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа денкт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не думает',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie denkt nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи денкт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не думает',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es denkt nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс денкт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не думает',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir denken nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа денкен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не думаем',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr denkt nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа денкт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не думаете (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie denken nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи денкен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не думают',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie denken nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи денкен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не думаете (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'denke ich?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'денке их',
  'phrase_ru': 'я думаю?',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'denkst du?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'денкст ду',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты думаешь?',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'denkt er?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'денкт иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'он думает?',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'denkt sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'денкт зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'она думает?',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'denkt es?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'денкт эс',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно думает?',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'denken wir?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'денкен виа',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы думаем?',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'denkt ihr?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'денкт иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы думаете? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'denken sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'денкен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'они думают?',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'denken Sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'денкен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы думаете? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe gedacht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе гедахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я думал',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast gedacht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст гедахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты думал',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat gedacht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат гедахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он думал',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat gedacht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат гедахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она думала',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat gedacht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат гедахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно думало',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben gedacht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен гедахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы думали',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt gedacht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт гедахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы думали (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben gedacht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен гедахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они думали',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben gedacht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен гедахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы думали (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe nicht gedacht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе нихт гедахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не думал',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast nicht gedacht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст нихт гедахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не думал',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat nicht gedacht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат нихт гедахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не думал',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat nicht gedacht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат нихт гедахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не думала',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat nicht gedacht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат нихт гедахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не думало',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben nicht gedacht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен нихт гедахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не думали',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt nicht gedacht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт нихт гедахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не думали (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben nicht gedacht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт гедахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не думали',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben nicht gedacht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт гедахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не думали (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habe ich gedacht?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабе их гедахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я думал?',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hast du gedacht?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хаст ду гедахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты думал?',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat er gedacht?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат иа гедахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он думал?',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat sie gedacht?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат зи гедахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она думала?',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat es gedacht?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат эс гедахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно думало?',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben wir gedacht?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен виа гедахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы думали?',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habt ihr gedacht?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабт иа гедахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы думали? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben sie gedacht?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи гедахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они думали?',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben Sie gedacht?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи гедахт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы думали? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde denken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде денкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я буду думать',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst denken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст денкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты будешь думать',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird denken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд денкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он будет думать',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird denken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд денкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она будет думать',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird denken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд денкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно будет думать',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden denken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн денкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы будем думать',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet denken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет денкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы будете думать (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden denken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн денкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они будут думать',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden denken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн денкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы будете думать (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde nicht denken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде нихт денкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не буду думать',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst nicht denken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст нихт денкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не будешь думать',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird nicht denken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд нихт денкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не будет думать',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird nicht denken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд нихт денкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не будет думать',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird nicht denken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд нихт денкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не будет думать',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden nicht denken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн нихт денкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не будем думать',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet nicht denken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет нихт денкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не будете думать (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden nicht denken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт денкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не будут думать',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden nicht denken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт денкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не будете думать (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werde ich denken?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веаде их денкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я буду думать?',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wirst du denken?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вирст ду денкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты будешь думать?',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird er denken?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд иа денкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он будет думать?',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird sie denken?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд зи денкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она будет думать?',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird es denken?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд эс денкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно будет думать?',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden wir denken?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн виа денкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы будем думать?',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werdet ihr denken?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадет иа денкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы будете думать? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden sie denken?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи денкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они будут думать?',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden Sie denken?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи денкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы будете думать? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'denken — думать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich kaufe',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их кауфе',
  'phrase_ru': 'я покупаю',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du kaufst',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду кауфст',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты покупаешь',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er kauft',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа кауфт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он покупает',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie kauft',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи кауфт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она покупает',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es kauft',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс кауфт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно покупает',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir kaufen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа кауфен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы покупаем',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr kauft',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа кауфт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы покупаете (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie kaufen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи кауфен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они покупают',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie kaufen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи кауфен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы покупаете (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich kaufe nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их кауфе нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не покупаю',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du kaufst nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду кауфст нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не покупаешь',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er kauft nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа кауфт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не покупает',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie kauft nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи кауфт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не покупает',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es kauft nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс кауфт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не покупает',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir kaufen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа кауфен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не покупаем',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr kauft nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа кауфт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не покупаете (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie kaufen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи кауфен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не покупают',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie kaufen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи кауфен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не покупаете (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'kaufe ich?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'кауфе их',
  'phrase_ru': 'я покупаю?',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'kaufst du?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'кауфст ду',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты покупаешь?',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'kauft er?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'кауфт иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'он покупает?',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'kauft sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'кауфт зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'она покупает?',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'kauft es?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'кауфт эс',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно покупает?',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'kaufen wir?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'кауфен виа',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы покупаем?',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'kauft ihr?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'кауфт иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы покупаете? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'kaufen sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'кауфен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'они покупают?',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'kaufen Sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'кауфен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы покупаете? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe gekauft',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе гекауфт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я купил',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast gekauft',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст гекауфт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты купил',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat gekauft',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат гекауфт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он купил',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat gekauft',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат гекауфт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она купила',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat gekauft',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат гекауфт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно купило',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben gekauft',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен гекауфт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы купили',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt gekauft',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт гекауфт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы купили (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben gekauft',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен гекауфт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они купили',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben gekauft',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен гекауфт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы купили (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe nicht gekauft',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе нихт гекауфт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не купил',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast nicht gekauft',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст нихт гекауфт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не купил',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat nicht gekauft',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат нихт гекауфт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не купил',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat nicht gekauft',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат нихт гекауфт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не купила',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat nicht gekauft',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат нихт гекауфт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не купило',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben nicht gekauft',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен нихт гекауфт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не купили',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt nicht gekauft',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт нихт гекауфт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не купили (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben nicht gekauft',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт гекауфт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не купили',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben nicht gekauft',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт гекауфт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не купили (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habe ich gekauft?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабе их гекауфт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я купил?',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hast du gekauft?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хаст ду гекауфт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты купил?',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat er gekauft?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат иа гекауфт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он купил?',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat sie gekauft?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат зи гекауфт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она купила?',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat es gekauft?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат эс гекауфт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно купило?',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben wir gekauft?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен виа гекауфт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы купили?',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habt ihr gekauft?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабт иа гекауфт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы купили? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben sie gekauft?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи гекауфт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они купили?',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben Sie gekauft?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи гекауфт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы купили? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde kaufen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде кауфен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я буду покупать',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst kaufen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст кауфен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты будешь покупать',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird kaufen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд кауфен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он будет покупать',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird kaufen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд кауфен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она будет покупать',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird kaufen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд кауфен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно будет покупать',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden kaufen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн кауфен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы будем покупать',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet kaufen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет кауфен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы будете покупать (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden kaufen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн кауфен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они будут покупать',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden kaufen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн кауфен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы будете покупать (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde nicht kaufen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде нихт кауфен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не буду покупать',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst nicht kaufen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст нихт кауфен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не будешь покупать',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird nicht kaufen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд нихт кауфен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не будет покупать',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird nicht kaufen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд нихт кауфен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не будет покупать',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird nicht kaufen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд нихт кауфен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не будет покупать',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden nicht kaufen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн нихт кауфен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не будем покупать',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet nicht kaufen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет нихт кауфен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не будете покупать (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden nicht kaufen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт кауфен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не будут покупать',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden nicht kaufen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт кауфен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не будете покупать (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werde ich kaufen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веаде их кауфен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я буду покупать?',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wirst du kaufen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вирст ду кауфен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты будешь покупать?',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird er kaufen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд иа кауфен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он будет покупать?',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird sie kaufen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд зи кауфен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она будет покупать?',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird es kaufen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд эс кауфен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно будет покупать?',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden wir kaufen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн виа кауфен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы будем покупать?',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werdet ihr kaufen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадет иа кауфен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы будете покупать? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden sie kaufen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи кауфен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они будут покупать?',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden Sie kaufen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи кауфен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы будете покупать? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'kaufen — покупать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich sehe',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их зие',
  'phrase_ru': 'я вижу',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du siehst',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду зист',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты видишь',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er sieht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа зит',
  'phrase_ru': 'он видит',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie sieht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи зит',
  'phrase_ru': 'она видит',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es sieht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс зит',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно видит',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir sehen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа зиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы видим',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr seht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа зит',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы видите (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie sehen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи зиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они видят',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie sehen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи зиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы видите (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich sehe nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их зие нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не вижу',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du siehst nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду зист нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не видишь',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er sieht nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа зит нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не видит',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie sieht nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи зит нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не видит',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es sieht nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс зит нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не видит',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir sehen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа зиен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не видим',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr seht nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа зит нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не видите (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie sehen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи зиен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не видят',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie sehen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи зиен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не видите (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sehe ich?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зие их',
  'phrase_ru': 'я вижу?',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'siehst du?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зист ду',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты видишь?',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sieht er?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зит иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'он видит?',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sieht sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зит зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'она видит?',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sieht es?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зит эс',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно видит?',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sehen wir?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зиен виа',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы видим?',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'seht ihr?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зит иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы видите? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sehen sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зиен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'они видят?',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sehen Sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зиен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы видите? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe gesehen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе гезиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я видел',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast gesehen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст гезиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты видел',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat gesehen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат гезиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он видел',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat gesehen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат гезиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она видела',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat gesehen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат гезиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно видело',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben gesehen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен гезиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы видели',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt gesehen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт гезиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы видели (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben gesehen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен гезиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они видели',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben gesehen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен гезиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы видели (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe nicht gesehen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе нихт гезиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не видел',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast nicht gesehen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст нихт гезиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не видел',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat nicht gesehen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат нихт гезиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не видел',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat nicht gesehen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат нихт гезиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не видела',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat nicht gesehen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат нихт гезиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не видело',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben nicht gesehen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен нихт гезиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не видели',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt nicht gesehen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт нихт гезиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не видели (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben nicht gesehen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт гезиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не видели',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben nicht gesehen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт гезиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не видели (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habe ich gesehen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабе их гезиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я видел?',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hast du gesehen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хаст ду гезиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты видел?',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat er gesehen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат иа гезиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он видел?',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat sie gesehen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат зи гезиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она видела?',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat es gesehen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат эс гезиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно видело?',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben wir gesehen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен виа гезиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы видели?',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habt ihr gesehen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабт иа гезиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы видели? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben sie gesehen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи гезиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они видели?',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben Sie gesehen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи гезиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы видели? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde sehen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде зиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я увижу',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst sehen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст зиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты увидишь',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird sehen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд зиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он увидит',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird sehen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд зиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она увидит',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird sehen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд зиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно увидит',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden sehen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн зиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы увидим',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet sehen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет зиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы увидите (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden sehen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн зиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они увидят',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden sehen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн зиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы увидите (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde nicht sehen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде нихт зиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не увижу',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst nicht sehen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст нихт зиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не увидишь',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird nicht sehen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд нихт зиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не увидит',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird nicht sehen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд нихт зиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не увидит',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird nicht sehen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд нихт зиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не увидит',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden nicht sehen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн нихт зиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не увидим',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet nicht sehen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет нихт зиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не увидите (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden nicht sehen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт зиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не увидят',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden nicht sehen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт зиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не увидите (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werde ich sehen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веаде их зиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я увижу?',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wirst du sehen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вирст ду зиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты увидишь?',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird er sehen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд иа зиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он увидит?',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird sie sehen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд зи зиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она увидит?',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird es sehen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд эс зиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно увидит?',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden wir sehen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн виа зиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы увидим?',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werdet ihr sehen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадет иа зиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы увидите? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden sie sehen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи зиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они увидят?',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden Sie sehen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи зиен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы увидите? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'sehen — видеть,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich will',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их вилль',
  'phrase_ru': 'я хочу',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du willst',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вилльст',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты хочешь',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er will',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вилль',
  'phrase_ru': 'он хочет',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie will',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вилль',
  'phrase_ru': 'она хочет',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es will',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вилль',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно хочет',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir wollen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа воллен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы хотим',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr wollt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа волльт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы хотите (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wollen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи воллен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они хотят',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie wollen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи воллен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы хотите (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich will nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их вилль нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не хочу',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du willst nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вилльст нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не хочешь',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er will nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вилль нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не хочет',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie will nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вилль нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не хочет',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es will nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вилль нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не хочет',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir wollen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа воллен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не хотим',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr wollt nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа волльт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не хотите (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wollen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи воллен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не хотят',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie wollen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи воллен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не хотите (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'will ich?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вилль их',
  'phrase_ru': 'я хочу?',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'willst du?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вилльст ду',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты хочешь?',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'will er?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вилль иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'он хочет?',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'will sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вилль зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'она хочет?',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'will es?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вилль эс',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно хочет?',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wollen wir?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'воллен виа',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы хотим?',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wollt ihr?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'волльт иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы хотите? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wollen sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'воллен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'они хотят?',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wollen Sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'воллен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы хотите? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe gewollt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе геволльт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я хотел',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast gewollt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст геволльт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты хотел',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat gewollt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат геволльт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он хотел',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat gewollt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат геволльт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она хотела',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat gewollt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат геволльт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно хотело',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben gewollt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен геволльт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы хотели',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt gewollt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт геволльт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы хотели (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben gewollt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен геволльт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они хотели',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben gewollt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен геволльт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы хотели (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe nicht gewollt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе нихт геволльт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не хотел',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast nicht gewollt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст нихт геволльт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не хотел',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat nicht gewollt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат нихт геволльт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не хотел',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat nicht gewollt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат нихт геволльт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не хотела',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat nicht gewollt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат нихт геволльт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не хотело',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben nicht gewollt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен нихт геволльт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не хотели',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt nicht gewollt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт нихт геволльт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не хотели (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben nicht gewollt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт геволльт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не хотели',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben nicht gewollt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт геволльт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не хотели (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habe ich gewollt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабе их геволльт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я хотел?',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hast du gewollt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хаст ду геволльт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты хотел?',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat er gewollt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат иа геволльт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он хотел?',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat sie gewollt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат зи геволльт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она хотела?',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat es gewollt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат эс геволльт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно хотело?',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben wir gewollt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен виа геволльт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы хотели?',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habt ihr gewollt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабт иа геволльт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы хотели? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben sie gewollt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи геволльт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они хотели?',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben Sie gewollt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи геволльт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы хотели? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde wollen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде воллен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я захочу',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst wollen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст воллен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты захочешь',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird wollen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд воллен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он захочет',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird wollen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд воллен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она захочет',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird wollen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд воллен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно захочет',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden wollen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн воллен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы захотим',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet wollen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет воллен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы захотите (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden wollen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн воллен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они захотят',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden wollen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн воллен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы захотите (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde nicht wollen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде нихт воллен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не захочу',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst nicht wollen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст нихт воллен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не захочешь',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird nicht wollen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд нихт воллен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не захочет',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird nicht wollen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд нихт воллен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не захочет',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird nicht wollen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд нихт воллен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не захочет',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden nicht wollen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн нихт воллен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не захотим',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet nicht wollen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет нихт воллен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не захотите (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden nicht wollen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт воллен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не захотят',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden nicht wollen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт воллен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не захотите (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werde ich wollen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веаде их воллен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я захочу?',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wirst du wollen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вирст ду воллен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты захочешь?',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird er wollen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд иа воллен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он захочет?',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird sie wollen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд зи воллен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она захочет?',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird es wollen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд эс воллен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно захочет?',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden wir wollen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн виа воллен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы захотим?',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werdet ihr wollen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадет иа воллен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы захотите? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden sie wollen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи воллен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они захотят?',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden Sie wollen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи воллен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы захотите? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'wollen — хотеть,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich lese',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их лезе',
  'phrase_ru': 'я читаю',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du liest',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду лист',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты читаешь',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er liest',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа лист',
  'phrase_ru': 'он читает',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie liest',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи лист',
  'phrase_ru': 'она читает',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es liest',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс лист',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно читает',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir lesen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа лизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы читаем',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr lest',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа лист',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы читаете (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie lesen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи лизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они читают',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie lesen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи лизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы читаете (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich lese nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их лезе нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не читаю',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du liest nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду лист нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не читаешь',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er liest nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа лист нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не читает',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie liest nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи лист нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не читает',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es liest nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс лист нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не читает',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir lesen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа лизен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не читаем',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr lest nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа лист нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не читаете (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie lesen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи лизен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не читают',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie lesen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи лизен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не читаете (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'lese ich?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'лезе их',
  'phrase_ru': 'я читаю?',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'liest du?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'лист ду',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты читаешь?',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'liest er?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'лист иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'он читает?',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'liest sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'лист зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'она читает?',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'liest es?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'лист эс',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно читает?',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'lesen wir?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'лизен виа',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы читаем?',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'lest ihr?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'лист иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы читаете? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'lesen sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'лизен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'они читают?',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'lesen Sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'лизен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы читаете? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe gelesen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе гелизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я читал',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast gelesen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст гелизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты читал',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat gelesen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат гелизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он читал',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat gelesen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат гелизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она читала',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat gelesen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат гелизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно читало',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben gelesen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен гелизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы читали',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt gelesen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт гелизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы читали (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben gelesen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен гелизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они читали',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben gelesen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен гелизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы читали (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe nicht gelesen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе нихт гелизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не читал',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast nicht gelesen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст нихт гелизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не читал',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat nicht gelesen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат нихт гелизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не читал',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat nicht gelesen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат нихт гелизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не читала',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat nicht gelesen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат нихт гелизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не читало',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben nicht gelesen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен нихт гелизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не читали',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt nicht gelesen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт нихт гелизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не читали (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben nicht gelesen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт гелизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не читали',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben nicht gelesen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт гелизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не читали (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habe ich gelesen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабе их гелизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я читал?',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hast du gelesen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хаст ду гелизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты читал?',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat er gelesen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат иа гелизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он читал?',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat sie gelesen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат зи гелизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она читала?',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat es gelesen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат эс гелизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно читало?',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben wir gelesen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен виа гелизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы читали?',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habt ihr gelesen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабт иа гелизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы читали? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben sie gelesen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи гелизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они читали?',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben Sie gelesen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи гелизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы читали? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde lesen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде лизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я буду читать',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst lesen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст лизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты будешь читать',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird lesen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд лизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он будет читать',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird lesen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд лизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она будет читать',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird lesen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд лизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно будет читать',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden lesen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн лизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы будем читать',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet lesen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет лизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы будете читать (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden lesen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн лизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они будут читать',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden lesen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн лизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы будете читать (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde nicht lesen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде нихт лизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не буду читать',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst nicht lesen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст нихт лизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не будешь читать',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird nicht lesen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд нихт лизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не будет читать',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird nicht lesen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд нихт лизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не будет читать',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird nicht lesen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд нихт лизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не будет читать',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden nicht lesen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн нихт лизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не будем читать',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet nicht lesen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет нихт лизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не будете читать (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden nicht lesen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт лизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не будут читать',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden nicht lesen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт лизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не будете читать (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werde ich lesen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веаде их лизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я буду читать?',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wirst du lesen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вирст ду лизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты будешь читать?',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird er lesen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд иа лизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он будет читать?',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird sie lesen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд зи лизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она будет читать?',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird es lesen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд эс лизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно будет читать?',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden wir lesen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн виа лизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы будем читать?',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werdet ihr lesen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадет иа лизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы будете читать? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden sie lesen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи лизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они будут читать?',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden Sie lesen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи лизен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы будете читать? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'lesen — читать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich schreibe',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их шрайбе',
  'phrase_ru': 'я пишу',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du schreibst',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду шрайбст',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты пишешь',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er schreibt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа шрайбт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он пишет',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie schreibt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи шрайбт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она пишет',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es schreibt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс шрайбт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно пишет',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir schreiben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа шрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы пишем',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr schreibt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа шрайбт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы пишете (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie schreiben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи шрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они пишут',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie schreiben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи шрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы пишете (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich schreibe nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их шрайбе нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не пишу',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du schreibst nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду шрайбст нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не пишешь',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er schreibt nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа шрайбт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не пишет',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie schreibt nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи шрайбт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не пишет',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es schreibt nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс шрайбт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не пишет',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir schreiben nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа шрайбен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не пишем',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr schreibt nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа шрайбт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не пишете (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie schreiben nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи шрайбен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не пишут',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie schreiben nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи шрайбен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не пишете (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'schreibe ich?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'шрайбе их',
  'phrase_ru': 'я пишу?',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'schreibst du?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'шрайбст ду',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты пишешь?',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'schreibt er?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'шрайбт иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'он пишет?',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'schreibt sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'шрайбт зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'она пишет?',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'schreibt es?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'шрайбт эс',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно пишет?',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'schreiben wir?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'шрайбен виа',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы пишем?',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'schreibt ihr?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'шрайбт иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы пишете? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'schreiben sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'шрайбен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'они пишут?',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'schreiben Sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'шрайбен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы пишете? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe geschrieben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе гешрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я писал',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast geschrieben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст гешрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты писал',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat geschrieben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат гешрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он писал',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat geschrieben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат гешрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она писала',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat geschrieben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат гешрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно писало',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben geschrieben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен гешрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы писали',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt geschrieben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт гешрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы писали (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben geschrieben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен гешрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они писали',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben geschrieben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен гешрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы писали (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe nicht geschrieben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе нихт гешрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не писал',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast nicht geschrieben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст нихт гешрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не писал',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat nicht geschrieben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат нихт гешрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не писал',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat nicht geschrieben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат нихт гешрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не писала',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat nicht geschrieben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат нихт гешрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не писало',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben nicht geschrieben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен нихт гешрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не писали',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt nicht geschrieben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт нихт гешрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не писали (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben nicht geschrieben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт гешрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не писали',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben nicht geschrieben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт гешрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не писали (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habe ich geschrieben?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабе их гешрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я писал?',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hast du geschrieben?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хаст ду гешрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты писал?',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat er geschrieben?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат иа гешрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он писал?',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat sie geschrieben?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат зи гешрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она писала?',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat es geschrieben?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат эс гешрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно писало?',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben wir geschrieben?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен виа гешрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы писали?',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habt ihr geschrieben?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабт иа гешрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы писали? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben sie geschrieben?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи гешрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они писали?',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben Sie geschrieben?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи гешрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы писали? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde schreiben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде шрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я буду писать',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst schreiben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст шрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты будешь писать',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird schreiben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд шрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он будет писать',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird schreiben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд шрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она будет писать',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird schreiben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд шрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно будет писать',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden schreiben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн шрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы будем писать',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet schreiben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет шрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы будете писать (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden schreiben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн шрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они будут писать',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden schreiben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн шрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы будете писать (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde nicht schreiben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде нихт шрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не буду писать',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst nicht schreiben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст нихт шрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не будешь писать',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird nicht schreiben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд нихт шрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не будет писать',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird nicht schreiben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд нихт шрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не будет писать',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird nicht schreiben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд нихт шрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не будет писать',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden nicht schreiben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн нихт шрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не будем писать',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet nicht schreiben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет нихт шрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не будете писать (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden nicht schreiben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт шрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не будут писать',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden nicht schreiben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт шрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не будете писать (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werde ich schreiben?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веаде их шрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я буду писать?',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wirst du schreiben?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вирст ду шрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты будешь писать?',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird er schreiben?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд иа шрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он будет писать?',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird sie schreiben?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд зи шрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она будет писать?',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird es schreiben?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд эс шрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно будет писать?',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden wir schreiben?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн виа шрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы будем писать?',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werdet ihr schreiben?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадет иа шрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы будете писать? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden sie schreiben?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи шрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они будут писать?',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden Sie schreiben?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи шрайбен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы будете писать? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'schreiben — писать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich esse',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их эссе',
  'phrase_ru': 'я ем',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du isst',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду ист',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты ешь',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er isst',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа ист',
  'phrase_ru': 'он ест',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie isst',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи ист',
  'phrase_ru': 'она ест',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es isst',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс ист',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно ест',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir essen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа эссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы едИм',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr esst',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа ист',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы едИте (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie essen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи эссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они едят',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie essen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи эссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы едИте (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich esse nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их эссе нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не ем',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du isst nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду ист нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не ешь',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er isst nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа ист нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не ест',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie isst nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи ист нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не ест',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es isst nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс ист нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не ест',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir essen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа эссен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не едИм',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr esst nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа ист нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не едИте (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie essen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи эссен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не едят',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie essen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи эссен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не едИте (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'esse ich?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эссе их',
  'phrase_ru': 'я ем?',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'isst du?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ист ду',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты ешь?',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'isst er?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ист иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'он ест?',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'isst sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ист зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'она ест?',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'isst es?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ист эс',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно ест?',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'essen wir?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эссен виа',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы едИм?',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'esst ihr?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ист иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы едИте? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'essen sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эссен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'они едят?',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'essen Sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эссен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы едИте? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe gegessen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе гегессен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я ел',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast gegessen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст гегессен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты ел',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat gegessen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат гегессен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он ел',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat gegessen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат гегессен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она ела',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat gegessen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат гегессен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно ело',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben gegessen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен гегессен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы ели',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt gegessen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт гегессен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы ели (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben gegessen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен гегессен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они ели',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben gegessen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен гегессен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы ели (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe nicht gegessen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе нихт гегессен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не ел',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast nicht gegessen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст нихт гегессен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не ел',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat nicht gegessen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат нихт гегессен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не ел',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat nicht gegessen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат нихт гегессен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не ела',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat nicht gegessen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат нихт гегессен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не ело',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben nicht gegessen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен нихт гегессен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не ели',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt nicht gegessen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт нихт гегессен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не ели (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben nicht gegessen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт гегессен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не ели',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben nicht gegessen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт гегессен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не ели (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habe ich gegessen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабе их гегессен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я ел?',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hast du gegessen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хаст ду гегессен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты ел?',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat er gegessen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат иа гегессен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он ел?',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat sie gegessen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат зи гегессен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она ела?',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat es gegessen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат эс гегессен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно ело?',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben wir gegessen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен виа гегессен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы ели?',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habt ihr gegessen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабт иа гегессен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы ели? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben sie gegessen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи гегессен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они ели?',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben Sie gegessen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи гегессен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы ели? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde essen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде эссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я буду кушать',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst essen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст эссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты будешь кушать',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird essen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд эссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он будет кушать',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird essen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд эссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она будет кушать',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird essen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд эссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно будет кушать',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden essen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн эссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы будем кушать',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet essen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет эссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы будете кушать (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden essen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн эссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они будут кушать',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden essen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн эссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы будете кушать (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde nicht essen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде нихт эссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не буду кушать',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst nicht essen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст нихт эссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не будешь кушать',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird nicht essen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд нихт эссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не будет кушать',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird nicht essen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд нихт эссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не будет кушать',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird nicht essen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд нихт эссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не будет кушать',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden nicht essen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн нихт эссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не будем кушать',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet nicht essen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет нихт эссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не будете кушать (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden nicht essen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт эссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не будут кушать',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden nicht essen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт эссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не будете кушать (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werde ich essen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веаде их эссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я буду кушать?',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wirst du essen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вирст ду эссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты будешь кушать?',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird er essen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд иа эссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он будет кушать?',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird sie essen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд зи эссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она будет кушать?',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird es essen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд эс эссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно будет кушать?',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden wir essen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн виа эссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы будем кушать?',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werdet ihr essen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадет иа эссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы будете кушать? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden sie essen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи эссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они будут кушать?',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden Sie essen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи эссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы будете кушать? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'essen — кушать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich trinke',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их тринке',
  'phrase_ru': 'я пью',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du trinkst',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду тринкст',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты пьешь',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er trinkt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа тринкт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он пьет',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie trinkt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи тринкт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она пьет',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es trinkt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс тринкт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно пьет',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir trinken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа тринкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы пьем',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr trinkt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа тринкт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы пьете (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie trinken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи тринкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они пьют',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie trinken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи тринкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы пьете (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich trinke nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их тринке нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не пью',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du trinkst nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду тринкст нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не пьешь',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er trinkt nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа тринкт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не пьет',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie trinkt nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи тринкт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не пьет',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es trinkt nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс тринкт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не пьет',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir trinken nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа тринкен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не пьем',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr trinkt nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа тринкт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не пьете (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie trinken nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи тринкен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не пьют',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie trinken nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи тринкен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не пьете (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'trinke ich?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'тринке их',
  'phrase_ru': 'я пью?',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'trinkst du?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'тринкст ду',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты пьешь?',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'trinkt er?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'тринкт иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'он пьет?',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'trinkt sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'тринкт зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'она пьет?',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'trinkt es?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'тринкт эс',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно пьет?',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'trinken wir?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'тринкен виа',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы пьем?',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'trinkt ihr?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'тринкт иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы пьете? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'trinken sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'тринкен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'они пьют?',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'trinken Sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'тринкен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы пьете? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe getrunken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе гетрункен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я пил',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast getrunken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст гетрункен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты пил',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat getrunken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат гетрункен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он пил',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat getrunken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат гетрункен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она пила',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat getrunken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат гетрункен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно пило',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben getrunken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен гетрункен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы пили',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt getrunken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт гетрункен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы пили (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben getrunken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен гетрункен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они пили',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben getrunken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен гетрункен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы пили (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe nicht getrunken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе нихт гетрункен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не пил',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast nicht getrunken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст нихт гетрункен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не пил',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat nicht getrunken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат нихт гетрункен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не пил',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat nicht getrunken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат нихт гетрункен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не пила',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat nicht getrunken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат нихт гетрункен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не пило',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben nicht getrunken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен нихт гетрункен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не пили',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt nicht getrunken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт нихт гетрункен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не пили (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben nicht getrunken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт гетрункен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не пили',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben nicht getrunken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт гетрункен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не пили (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habe ich getrunken?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабе их гетрункен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я пил?',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hast du getrunken?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хаст ду гетрункен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты пил?',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat er getrunken?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат иа гетрункен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он пил?',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat sie getrunken?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат зи гетрункен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она пила?',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat es getrunken?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат эс гетрункен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно пило?',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben wir getrunken?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен виа гетрункен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы пили?',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habt ihr getrunken?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабт иа гетрункен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы пили? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben sie getrunken?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи гетрункен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они пили?',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben Sie getrunken?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи гетрункен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы пили? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde trinken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде тринкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я буду пить',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst trinken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст тринкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты будешь пить',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird trinken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд тринкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он будет пить',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird trinken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд тринкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она будет пить',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird trinken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд тринкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно будет пить',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden trinken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн тринкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы будем пить',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet trinken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет тринкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы будете пить (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden trinken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн тринкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они будут пить',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden trinken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн тринкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы будете пить (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde nicht trinken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде нихт тринкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не буду пить',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst nicht trinken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст нихт тринкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не будешь пить',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird nicht trinken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд нихт тринкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не будет пить',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird nicht trinken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд нихт тринкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не будет пить',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird nicht trinken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд нихт тринкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не будет пить',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden nicht trinken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн нихт тринкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не будем пить',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet nicht trinken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет нихт тринкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не будете пить (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden nicht trinken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт тринкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не будут пить',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden nicht trinken',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт тринкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не будете пить (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werde ich trinken?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веаде их тринкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я буду пить?',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wirst du trinken?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вирст ду тринкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты будешь пить?',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird er trinken?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд иа тринкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он будет пить?',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird sie trinken?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд зи тринкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она будет пить?',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird es trinken?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд эс тринкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно будет пить?',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden wir trinken?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн виа тринкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы будем пить?',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werdet ihr trinken?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадет иа тринкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы будете пить? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden sie trinken?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи тринкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они будут пить?',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden Sie trinken?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи тринкен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы будете пить? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'trinken — пить,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich arbeite',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их арбайте',
  'phrase_ru': 'я работаю',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du arbeitest',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду арбайтест',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты работаешь',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er arbeitet',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа арбайтет',
  'phrase_ru': 'он работает',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie arbeitet',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи арбайтет',
  'phrase_ru': 'она работает',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es arbeitet',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс арбайтет',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно работает',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir arbeiten',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа арбайтен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы работаем',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr arbeitet',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа арбайтет',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы работаете (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie arbeiten',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи арбайтен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они работают',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie arbeiten',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи арбайтен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы работаете (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich arbeite nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их арбайте нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не работаю',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du arbeitest nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду арбайтест нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не работаешь',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er arbeitet nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа арбайтет нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не работает',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie arbeitet nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи арбайтет нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не работает',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es arbeitet nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс арбайтет нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не работает',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir arbeiten nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа арбайтен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не работаем',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr arbeitet nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа арбайтет нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не работаете (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie arbeiten nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи арбайтен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не работают',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie arbeiten nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи арбайтен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не работаете (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'arbeite ich?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'арбайте их',
  'phrase_ru': 'я работаю?',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'arbeitest du?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'арбайтест ду',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты работаешь?',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'arbeitet er?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'арбайтет иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'он работает?',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'arbeitet sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'арбайтет зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'она работает?',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'arbeitet es?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'арбайтет эс',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно работает?',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'arbeiten wir?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'арбайтен виа',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы работаем?',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'arbeitet ihr?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'арбайтет иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы работаете (множественное число)?',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'arbeiten sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'арбайтен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'они работают?',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'arbeiten Sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'арбайтен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы работаете (вежливая форма)?',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe gearbeitet',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе геарбайтет',
  'phrase_ru': 'я работал',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast gearbeitet',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст геарбайтет',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты работал',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat gearbeitet',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат геарбайтет',
  'phrase_ru': 'он работал',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat gearbeitet',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат геарбайтет',
  'phrase_ru': 'она работала',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat gearbeitet',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат геарбайтет',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно работало',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben gearbeitet',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен геарбайтет',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы работали',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt gearbeitet',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт геарбайтет',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы работали (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben gearbeitet',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен геарбайтет',
  'phrase_ru': 'они работали',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben gearbeitet',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен геарбайтет',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы работали (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe nicht gearbeitet',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе нихт геарбайтет',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не работал',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast nicht gearbeitet',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст нихт геарбайтет',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не работал',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat nicht gearbeitet',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат нихт геарбайтет',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не работал',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat nicht gearbeitet',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат нихт геарбайтет',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не работала',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat nicht gearbeitet',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат нихт геарбайтет',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не работало',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben nicht gearbeitet',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен нихт геарбайтет',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не работали',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt nicht gearbeitet',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт нихт геарбайтет',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не работали (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben nicht gearbeitet',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт геарбайтет',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не работали',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben nicht gearbeitet',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт геарбайтет',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не работали (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habe ich gearbeitet?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабе их геарбайтет',
  'phrase_ru': 'я работал?',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hast du gearbeitet?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хаст ду геарбайтет',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты работал?',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat er gearbeitet?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат иа геарбайтет',
  'phrase_ru': 'он работал?',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat sie gearbeitet?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат зи геарбайтет',
  'phrase_ru': 'она работала?',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat es gearbeitet?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат эс геарбайтет',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно работало?',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben wir gearbeitet?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен виа геарбайтет',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы работали?',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habt ihr gearbeitet?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабт иа геарбайтет',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы работали? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben sie gearbeitet?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи геарбайтет',
  'phrase_ru': 'они работали?',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben Sie gearbeitet?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи геарбайтет',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы работали? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde arbeiten',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде арбайтен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я буду работать',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst arbeiten',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст арбайтен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты будешь работать',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird arbeiten',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд арбайтен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он будет работать',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird arbeiten',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд арбайтен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она будет работать',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird arbeiten',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд арбайтен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно будет работать',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden arbeiten',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн арбайтен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы будем работать',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet arbeiten',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет арбайтен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы будете работать (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden arbeiten',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн арбайтен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они будут работать',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden arbeiten',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн арбайтен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы будете работать (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde nicht arbeiten',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде нихт арбайтен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не буду работать',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst nicht arbeiten',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст нихт арбайтен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не будешь работать',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird nicht arbeiten',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд нихт арбайтен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не будет работать',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird nicht arbeiten',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд нихт арбайтен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не будет работать',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird nicht arbeiten',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд нихт арбайтен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не будет работать',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden nicht arbeiten',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн нихт арбайтен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не будем работать',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet nicht arbeiten',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет нихт арбайтен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не будете работать (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden nicht arbeiten',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт арбайтен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не будут работать',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden nicht arbeiten',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт арбайтен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не будете работать (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werde ich arbeiten?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веаде их арбайтен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я буду работать?',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wirst du arbeiten?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вирст ду арбайтен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты будешь работать?',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird er arbeiten?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд иа арбайтен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он будет работать?',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird sie arbeiten?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд зи арбайтен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она будет работать?',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird es arbeiten?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд эс арбайтен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно будет работать?',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden wir arbeiten?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн виа арбайтен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы будем работать?',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werdet ihr arbeiten?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадет иа арбайтен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы будете работать? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden sie arbeiten?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи арбайтен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они будут работать?',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden Sie arbeiten?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи арбайтен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы будете работать? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'arbeiten — работать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich lerne',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их леане',
  'phrase_ru': 'я изучаю',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du lernst',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду леанст',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты изучаешь',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er lernt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа леант',
  'phrase_ru': 'он изучает',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie lernt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи леант',
  'phrase_ru': 'она изучает',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es lernt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс леант',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно изучает',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir lernen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа леанен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы изучаем',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr lernt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа леант',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы изучаете (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie lernen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи леанен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они изучают',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie lernen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи леанен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы изучаете (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich lerne nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их леане нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не изучаю',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du lernst nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду леанст нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не изучаешь',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er lernt nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа леант нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не изучает',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie lernt nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи леант нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не изучает',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es lernt nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс леант нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не изучает',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir lernen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа леанен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не изучаем',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr lernt nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа леант нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не изучаете (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie lernen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи леанен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не изучают',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie lernen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи леанен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не изучаете (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'lerne ich?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'леане их',
  'phrase_ru': 'я изучаю?',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'lernst du?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'леанст ду',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты изучаешь?',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'lernt er?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'леант иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'он изучает?',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'lernt sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'леант зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'она изучает?',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'lernt es?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'леант эс',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно изучает?',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'lernen wir?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'леанен виа',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы изучаем?',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'lernt ihr?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'леант иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы изучаете (множественное число)?',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'lernen sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'леанен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'они изучают?',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'lernen Sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'леанен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы изучаете (вежливая форма)?',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe gelernt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе гелеант',
  'phrase_ru': 'я изучал',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast gelernt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст гелеант',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты изучал',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat gelernt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат гелеант',
  'phrase_ru': 'он изучал',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat gelernt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат гелеант',
  'phrase_ru': 'она изучала',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat gelernt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат гелеант',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно изучало',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben gelernt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен гелеант',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы изучали',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt gelernt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт гелеант',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы изучали (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben gelernt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен гелеант',
  'phrase_ru': 'они изучали',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben gelernt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен гелеант',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы изучали (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe nicht gelernt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе нихт гелеант',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не изучал',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast nicht gelernt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст нихт гелеант',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не изучал',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat nicht gelernt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат нихт гелеант',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не изучал',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat nicht gelernt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат нихт гелеант',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не изучала',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat nicht gelernt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат нихт гелеант',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не изучало',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben nicht gelernt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен нихт гелеант',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не изучали',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt nicht gelernt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт нихт гелеант',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не изучали (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben nicht gelernt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт гелеант',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не изучали',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben nicht gelernt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт гелеант',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не изучали (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habe ich gelernt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабе их гелеант',
  'phrase_ru': 'я изучал?',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hast du gelernt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хаст ду гелеант',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты изучал?',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat er gelernt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат иа гелеант',
  'phrase_ru': 'он изучал?',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat sie gelernt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат зи гелеант',
  'phrase_ru': 'она изучала?',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat es gelernt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат эс гелеант',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно изучало?',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben wir gelernt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен виа гелеант',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы изучали?',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habt ihr gelernt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабт иа гелеант',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы изучали? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben sie gelernt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи гелеант',
  'phrase_ru': 'они изучали?',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben Sie gelernt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи гелеант',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы изучали? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde lernen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде леанен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я буду изучать',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst lernen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст леанен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты будешь изучать',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird lernen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд леанен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он будет изучать',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird lernen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд леанен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она будет изучать',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird lernen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд леанен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно будет изучать',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden lernen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн леанен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы будем изучать',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet lernen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет леанен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы будете изучать (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden lernen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн леанен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они будут изучать',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden lernen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн леанен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы будете изучать (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde nicht lernen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде нихт леанен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не буду изучать',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst nicht lernen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст нихт леанен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не будешь изучать',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird nicht lernen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд нихт леанен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не будет изучать',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird nicht lernen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд нихт леанен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не будет изучать',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird nicht lernen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд нихт леанен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не будет изучать',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden nicht lernen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн нихт леанен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не будем изучать',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet nicht lernen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет нихт леанен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не будете изучать (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden nicht lernen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт леанен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не будут изучать',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden nicht lernen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт леанен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не будете изучать (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werde ich lernen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веаде их леанен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я буду изучать?',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wirst du lernen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вирст ду леанен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты будешь изучать?',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird er lernen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд иа леанен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он будет изучать?',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird sie lernen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд зи леанен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она будет изучать?',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird es lernen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд эс леанен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно будет изучать?',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden wir lernen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн виа леанен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы будем изучать?',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werdet ihr lernen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадет иа леанен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы будете изучать? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden sie lernen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи леанен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они будут изучать?',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden Sie lernen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи леанен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы будете изучать? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'lernen — изучать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich weiß',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их вайс',
  'phrase_ru': 'я знаю',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du weißt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вайст',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты знаешь',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er weiß',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вайс',
  'phrase_ru': 'он знает',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie weiß',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вайс',
  'phrase_ru': 'она знает',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es weiß',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вайс',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно знает',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir wissen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа виссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы знаем',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr wisst',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вист',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы знаете (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wissen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи виссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они знают',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie wissen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи виссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы знаете (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich weiß nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их вайс нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не знаю',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du weißt nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вайст нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не знаешь',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er weiß nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вайс нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не знает',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie weiß nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вайс нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не знает',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es weiß nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вайс нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не знает',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir wissen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа виссен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не знаем',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr wisst nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вист нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не знаете (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wissen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи виссен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не знают',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie wissen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи виссен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не знаете (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'weiß ich?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вайс их',
  'phrase_ru': 'я знаю?',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'weißt du?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вайст ду',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты знаешь?',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'weiß er?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вайс иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'он знает?',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'weiß sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вайс зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'она знает?',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'weiß es?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вайс эс',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно знает?',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wissen wir?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виссен виа',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы знаем?',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wisst ihr?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вист иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы знаете? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wissen sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виссен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'они знают?',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wissen Sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виссен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы знаете? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe gewusst',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе гевуст',
  'phrase_ru': 'я знал',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast gewusst',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст гевуст',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты знал',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat gewusst',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат гевуст',
  'phrase_ru': 'он знал',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat gewusst',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат гевуст',
  'phrase_ru': 'она знала',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat gewusst',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат гевуст',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно знало',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben gewusst',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен гевуст',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы знали',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt gewusst',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт гевуст',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы знали (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben gewusst',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен гевуст',
  'phrase_ru': 'они знали',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben gewusst',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен гевуст',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы знали (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe nicht gewusst',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе нихт гевуст',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не знал',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast nicht gewusst',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст нихт гевуст',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не знал',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat nicht gewusst',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат нихт гевуст',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не знал',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat nicht gewusst',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат нихт гевуст',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не знала',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat nicht gewusst',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат нихт гевуст',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не знало',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben nicht gewusst',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен нихт гевуст',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не знали',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt nicht gewusst',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт нихт гевуст',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не знали (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben nicht gewusst',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт гевуст',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не знали',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben nicht gewusst',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт гевуст',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не знали (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habe ich gewusst?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабе их гевуст',
  'phrase_ru': 'я знал?',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hast du gewusst?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хаст ду гевуст',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты знал?',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat er gewusst?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат иа гевуст',
  'phrase_ru': 'он знал?',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat sie gewusst?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат зи гевуст',
  'phrase_ru': 'она знала?',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat es gewusst?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат эс гевуст',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно знало?',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben wir gewusst?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен виа гевуст',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы знали?',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habt ihr gewusst?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабт иа гевуст',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы знали? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben sie gewusst?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи гевуст',
  'phrase_ru': 'они знали?',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben Sie gewusst?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи гевуст',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы знали? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde wissen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде виссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я буду знать',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst wissen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст виссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты будешь знать',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird wissen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд виссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он будет знать',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird wissen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд виссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она будет знать',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird wissen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд виссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно будет знать',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden wissen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн виссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы будем знать',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet wissen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет виссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы будете знать (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden wissen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн виссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они будут знать',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden wissen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн виссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы будете знать (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde nicht wissen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде нихт виссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не буду знать',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst nicht wissen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст нихт виссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не будешь знать',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird nicht wissen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд нихт виссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не будет знать',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird nicht wissen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд нихт виссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не будет знать',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird nicht wissen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд нихт виссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не будет знать',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden nicht wissen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн нихт виссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не будем знать',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet nicht wissen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет нихт виссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не будете знать (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden nicht wissen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт виссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не будут знать',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden nicht wissen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт виссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не будете знать (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werde ich wissen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веаде их виссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я буду знать?',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wirst du wissen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вирст ду виссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты будешь знать?',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird er wissen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд иа виссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он будет знать?',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird sie wissen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд зи виссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она будет знать?',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird es wissen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд эс виссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно будет знать?',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden wir wissen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн виа виссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы будем знать?',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werdet ihr wissen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадет иа виссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы будете знать? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden sie wissen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи виссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они будут знать?',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden Sie wissen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи виссен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы будете знать? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'wissen — знать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich spiele',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их шпиле',
  'phrase_ru': 'я играю',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du spielst',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду шпильст',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты играешь',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er spielt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа шпильт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он играет',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie spielt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи шпильт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она играет',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es spielt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс шпильт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно играет',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir spielen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа шпилен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы играем',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr spielt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа шпильт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы играете (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie spielen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи шпилен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они играют',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie spielen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи шпилен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы играете (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich spiele nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их шпиле нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не играю',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du spielst nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду шпильст нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не играешь',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er spielt nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа шпильт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не играет',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie spielt nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи шпильт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не играет',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es spielt nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс шпильт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не играет',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir spielen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа шпилен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не играем',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr spielt nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа шпильт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не играете (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie spielen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи шпилен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не играют',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie spielen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи шпилен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не играете (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'spiele ich?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'шпиле их',
  'phrase_ru': 'я играю?',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'spielst du?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'шпильст ду',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты играешь?',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'spielt er?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'шпильт иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'он играет?',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'spielt sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'шпильт зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'она играет?',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'spielt es?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'шпильт эс',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно играет?',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'spielen wir?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'шпилен виа',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы играем?',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'spielt ihr?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'шпильт иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы играете? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'spielen sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'шпилен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'они играют?',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'spielen Sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'шпилен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы играете? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe gespielt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе гешпильт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я играл',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast gespielt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст гешпильт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты играл',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat gespielt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат гешпильт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он играл',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat gespielt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат гешпильт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она играла',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat gespielt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат гешпильт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно играло',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben gespielt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен гешпильт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы играли',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt gespielt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт гешпильт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы играли (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben gespielt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен гешпильт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они играли',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben gespielt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен гешпильт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы играли (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe nicht gespielt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе нихт гешпильт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не играл',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast nicht gespielt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст нихт гешпильт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не играл',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat nicht gespielt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат нихт гешпильт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не играл',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat nicht gespielt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат нихт гешпильт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не играла',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat nicht gespielt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат нихт гешпильт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не играло',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben nicht gespielt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен нихт гешпильт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не играли',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt nicht gespielt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт нихт гешпильт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не играли (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben nicht gespielt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт гешпильт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не играли',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben nicht gespielt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт гешпильт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не играли (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habe ich gespielt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабе их гешпильт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я играл?',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hast du gespielt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хаст ду гешпильт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты играл?',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat er gespielt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат иа гешпильт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он играл?',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat sie gespielt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат зи гешпильт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она играла?',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat es gespielt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат эс гешпильт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно играло?',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben wir gespielt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен виа гешпильт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы играли?',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habt ihr gespielt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабт иа гешпильт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы играли? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben sie gespielt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи гешпильт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они играли?',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben Sie gespielt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи гешпильт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы играли? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde spielen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде шпилен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я буду играть',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst spielen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст шпилен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты будешь играть',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird spielen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд шпилен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он будет играть',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird spielen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд шпилен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она будет играть',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird spielen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд шпилен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно будет играть',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden spielen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн шпилен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы будем играть',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet spielen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет шпилен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы будете играть (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden spielen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн шпилен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они будут играть',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden spielen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн шпилен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы будете играть (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde nicht spielen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде нихт шпилен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не буду играть',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst nicht spielen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст нихт шпилен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не будешь играть',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird nicht spielen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд нихт шпилен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не будет играть',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird nicht spielen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд нихт шпилен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не будет играть',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird nicht spielen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд нихт шпилен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не будет играть',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden nicht spielen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн нихт шпилен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не будем играть',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet nicht spielen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет нихт шпилен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не будете играть (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden nicht spielen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт шпилен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не будут играть',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden nicht spielen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт шпилен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не будете играть (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werde ich spielen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веаде их шпилен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я буду играть?',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wirst du spielen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вирст ду шпилен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты будешь играть?',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird er spielen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд иа шпилен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он будет играть?',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird sie spielen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд зи шпилен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она будет играть?',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird es spielen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд эс шпилен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно будет играть?',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden wir spielen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн виа шпилен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы будем играть?',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werdet ihr spielen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадет иа шпилен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы будете играть? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden sie spielen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи шпилен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они будут играть?',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden Sie spielen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи шпилен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы будете играть? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'spielen — играть,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich frage',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их фраге',
  'phrase_ru': 'я спрашиваю',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du fragst',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду фрагст',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты спрашиваешь',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er fragt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа фрагт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он спрашивает',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie fragt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи фрагт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она спрашивает',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es fragt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс фрагт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно спрашивает',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir fragen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа фраген',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы спрашиваем',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr fragt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа фрагт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы спрашиваете (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie fragen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи фраген',
  'phrase_ru': 'они спрашивают',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie fragen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи фраген',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы спрашиваете (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich frage nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их фраге нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не спрашиваю',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du fragst nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду фрагст нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не спрашиваешь',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er fragt nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа фрагт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не спрашивает',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie fragt nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи фрагт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не спрашивает',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es fragt nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс фрагт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не спрашивает',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir fragen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа фраген нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не спрашиваем',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr fragt nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа фрагт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не спрашиваете (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie fragen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи фраген нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не спрашивают',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie fragen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи фраген нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не спрашиваете (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'frage ich?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'фраге их',
  'phrase_ru': 'я спрашиваю?',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'fragst du?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'фрагст ду',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты спрашиваешь?',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'fragt er?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'фрагт иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'он спрашивает?',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'fragt sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'фрагт зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'она спрашивает?',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'fragt es?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'фрагт эс',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно спрашивает?',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'fragen wir?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'фраген виа',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы спрашиваем?',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'fragt ihr?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'фрагт иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы спрашиваете? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'fragen sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'фраген зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'они спрашивают?',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'fragen Sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'фраген зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы спрашиваете? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe gefragt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе гефрагт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я спрашивал',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast gefragt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст гефрагт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты спрашивал',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat gefragt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат гефрагт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он спрашивал',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat gefragt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат гефрагт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она спрашивала',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat gefragt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат гефрагт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно спрашивало',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben gefragt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен гефрагт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы спрашивали',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt gefragt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт гефрагт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы спрашивали (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben gefragt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен гефрагт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они спрашивали',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben gefragt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен гефрагт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы спрашивали (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe nicht gefragt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе нихт гефрагт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не спрашивал',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast nicht gefragt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст нихт гефрагт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не спрашивал',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat nicht gefragt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат нихт гефрагт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не спрашивал',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat nicht gefragt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат нихт гефрагт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не спрашивала',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat nicht gefragt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат нихт гефрагт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не спрашивало',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben nicht gefragt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен нихт гефрагт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не спрашивали',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt nicht gefragt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт нихт гефрагт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не спрашивали (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben nicht gefragt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт гефрагт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не спрашивали',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben nicht gefragt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт гефрагт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не спрашивали (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habe ich gefragt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабе их гефрагт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я спрашивал?',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hast du gefragt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хаст ду гефрагт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты спрашивал?',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat er gefragt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат иа гефрагт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он спрашивал?',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat sie gefragt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат зи гефрагт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она спрашивала?',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat es gefragt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат эс гефрагт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно спрашивало?',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben wir gefragt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен виа гефрагт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы спрашивали?',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habt ihr gefragt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабт иа гефрагт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы спрашивали? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben sie gefragt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи гефрагт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они спрашивали?',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben Sie gefragt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи гефрагт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы спрашивали? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde fragen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде фраген',
  'phrase_ru': 'я спрошу',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst fragen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст фраген',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты спросишь',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird fragen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд фраген',
  'phrase_ru': 'он спросит',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird fragen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд фраген',
  'phrase_ru': 'она спросит',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird fragen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд фраген',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно спросит',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden fragen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн фраген',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы спросим',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet fragen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет фраген',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы спросите (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden fragen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн фраген',
  'phrase_ru': 'они спросят',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden fragen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн фраген',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы спросите (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde nicht fragen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде нихт фраген',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не спрошу',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst nicht fragen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст нихт фраген',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не спросишь',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird nicht fragen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд нихт фраген',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не спросит',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird nicht fragen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд нихт фраген',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не спросит',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird nicht fragen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд нихт фраген',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не спросит',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden nicht fragen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн нихт фраген',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не спросим',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet nicht fragen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет нихт фраген',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не спросите (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden nicht fragen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт фраген',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не спросят',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden nicht fragen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт фраген',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не спросите (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werde ich fragen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веаде их фраген',
  'phrase_ru': 'я спрошу?',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wirst du fragen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вирст ду фраген',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты спросишь?',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird er fragen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд иа фраген',
  'phrase_ru': 'он спросит?',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird sie fragen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд зи фраген',
  'phrase_ru': 'она спросит?',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird es fragen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд эс фраген',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно спросит?',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden wir fragen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн виа фраген',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы спросим?',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werdet ihr fragen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадет иа фраген',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы спросите? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden sie fragen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи фраген',
  'phrase_ru': 'они спросят?',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden Sie fragen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи фраген',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы спросите? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'fragen — спрашивать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich schlafe',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их шлафе',
  'phrase_ru': 'я сплю',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du schläfst',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду шлифст',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты спишь',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er schläft',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа шлифт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он спит',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie schläft',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи шлифт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она спит',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es schläft',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс шлифт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно спит',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir schlafen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа шлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы спим',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr schlaft',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа шлафт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы спите (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie schlafen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи шлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они спят',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie schlafen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи шлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы спите (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich schlafe nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их шлафе нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не сплю',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du schläfst nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду шлифст нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не спишь',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er schläft nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа шлифт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не спит',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie schläft nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи шлифт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не спит',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es schläft nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс шлифт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не спит',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir schlafen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа шлафен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не спим',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr schlaft nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа шлафт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не спите (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie schlafen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи шлафен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не спят',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie schlafen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи шлафен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не спите (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'schlafe ich?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'шлафе их',
  'phrase_ru': 'я сплю?',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'schläfst du?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'шлифст ду',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты спишь?',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'schläft er?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'шлифт иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'он спит?',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'schläft sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'шлифт зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'она спит?',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'schläft es?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'шлифт эс',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно спит?',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'schlafen wir?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'шлафен виа',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы спим?',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'schlaft ihr?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'шлафт иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы спите? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'schlafen sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'шлафен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'они спят?',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'schlafen Sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'шлафен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы спите? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe geschlafen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе гешлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я спал',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast geschlafen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст гешлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты спал',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat geschlafen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат гешлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он спал',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat geschlafen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат гешлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она спала',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat geschlafen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат гешлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно спало',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben geschlafen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен гешлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы спали',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt geschlafen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт гешлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы спали (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben geschlafen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен гешлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они спали',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben geschlafen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен гешлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы спали (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe nicht geschlafen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе нихт гешлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не спал',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast nicht geschlafen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст нихт гешлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не спал',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat nicht geschlafen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат нихт гешлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не спал',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat nicht geschlafen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат нихт гешлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не спала',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat nicht geschlafen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат нихт гешлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не спало',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben nicht geschlafen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен нихт гешлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не спали',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt nicht geschlafen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт нихт гешлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не спали (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben nicht geschlafen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт гешлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не спали',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben nicht geschlafen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт гешлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не спали (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habe ich geschlafen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабе их гешлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я спал?',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hast du geschlafen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хаст ду гешлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты спал?',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat er geschlafen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат иа гешлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он спал?',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat sie geschlafen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат зи гешлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она спала?',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat es geschlafen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат эс гешлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно спало?',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben wir geschlafen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен виа гешлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы спали?',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habt ihr geschlafen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабт иа гешлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы спали? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben sie geschlafen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи гешлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они спали?',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben Sie geschlafen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи гешлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы спали? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde schlafen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде шлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я буду спать',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst schlafen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст шлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты будешь спать',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird schlafen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд шлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он будет спать',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird schlafen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд шлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она будет спать',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird schlafen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд шлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно будет спать',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden schlafen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн шлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы будем спать',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet schlafen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет шлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы будете спать (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden schlafen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн шлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они будут спать',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden schlafen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн шлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы будете спать (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde nicht schlafen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде нихт шлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не буду спать',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst nicht schlafen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст нихт шлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не будешь спать',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird nicht schlafen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд нихт шлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не будет спать',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird nicht schlafen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд нихт шлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не будет спать',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird nicht schlafen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд нихт шлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не будет спать',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden nicht schlafen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн нихт шлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не будем спать',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet nicht schlafen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет нихт шлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не будете спать (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden nicht schlafen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт шлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не будут спать',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden nicht schlafen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт шлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не будете спать (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werde ich schlafen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веаде их шлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я буду спать?',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wirst du schlafen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вирст ду шлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты будешь спать?',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird er schlafen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд иа шлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он будет спать?',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird sie schlafen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд зи шлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она будет спать?',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird es schlafen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд эс шлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно будет спать?',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden wir schlafen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн виа шлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы будем спать?',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werdet ihr schlafen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадет иа шлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы будете спать? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden sie schlafen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи шлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они будут спать?',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden Sie schlafen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи шлафен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы будете спать? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'schlafen — спать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich höre',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хёре',
  'phrase_ru': 'я слышу',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du hörst',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хёрст',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты слышишь',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er hört',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хёрт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он слышит',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hört',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хёрт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она слышит',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es hört',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хёрт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно слышит',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir hören',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хёрен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы слышим',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr hört',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хёрт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы слышите (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hören',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хёрен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они слышат',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie hören',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хёрен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы слышите (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich höre nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хёре нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не слышу',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du hörst nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хёрст нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не слышишь',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er hört nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хёрт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не слышит',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hört nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хёрт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не слышит',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es hört nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хёрт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не слышит',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir hören nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хёрен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не слышим',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr hört nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хёрт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не слышите (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hören nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хёрен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не слышат',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie hören nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хёрен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не слышите (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'höre ich?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хёре их',
  'phrase_ru': 'я слышу?',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'hörst du?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хёрст ду',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты слышишь?',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'hört er?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хёрт иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'он слышит?',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'hört sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хёрт зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'она слышит?',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'hört es?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хёрт эс',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно слышит?',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'hören wir?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хёрен виа',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы слышим?',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'hört ihr?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хёрт иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы слышите? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'hören sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хёрен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'они слышат?',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'hören Sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хёрен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы слышите? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe gehört',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе гехёрт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я слышал',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast gehört',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст гехёрт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты слышал',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat gehört',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат гехёрт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он слышал',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat gehört',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат гехёрт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она слышала',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat gehört',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат гехёрт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно слышало',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben gehört',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен гехёрт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы слышали',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt gehört',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт гехёрт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы слышали (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben gehört',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен гехёрт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они слышали',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben gehört',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен гехёрт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы слышали (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe nicht gehört',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе нихт гехёрт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не слышал',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast nicht gehört',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст нихт гехёрт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не слышал',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat nicht gehört',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат нихт гехёрт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не слышал',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat nicht gehört',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат нихт гехёрт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не слышала',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat nicht gehört',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат нихт гехёрт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не слышало',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben nicht gehört',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен нихт гехёрт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не слышали',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt nicht gehört',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт нихт гехёрт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не слышали (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben nicht gehört',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт гехёрт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не слышали',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben nicht gehört',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт гехёрт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не слышали (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habe ich gehört?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабе их гехёрт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я слышал?',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hast du gehört?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хаст ду гехёрт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты слышал?',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat er gehört?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат иа гехёрт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он слышал?',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat sie gehört?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат зи гехёрт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она слышала?',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat es gehört?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат эс гехёрт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно слышало?',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben wir gehört?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен виа гехёрт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы слышали?',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habt ihr gehört?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабт иа гехёрт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы слышали? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben sie gehört?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи гехёрт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они слышали?',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben Sie gehört?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи гехёрт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы слышали? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde hören',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде хёрен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я услышу',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst hören',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст хёрен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты услышишь',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird hören',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд хёрен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он услышит',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird hören',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд хёрен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она услышит',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird hören',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд хёрен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно услышит',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden hören',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн хёрен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы услышим',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet hören',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет хёрен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы услышите (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden hören',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн хёрен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они услышат',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden hören',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн хёрен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы услышите (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde nicht hören',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде нихт хёрен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не услышу',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst nicht hören',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст нихт хёрен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не услышишь',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird nicht hören',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд нихт хёрен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не услышит',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird nicht hören',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд нихт хёрен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не услышит',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird nicht hören',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд нихт хёрен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не услышит',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden nicht hören',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн нихт хёрен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не услышим',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet nicht hören',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет нихт хёрен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не услышите (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden nicht hören',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт хёрен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не услышат',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden nicht hören',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт хёрен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не услышите (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werde ich hören?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веаде их хёрен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я услышу?',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wirst du hören?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вирст ду хёрен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты услышишь?',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird er hören?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд иа хёрен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он услышит?',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird sie hören?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд зи хёрен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она услышит?',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird es hören?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд эс хёрен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно услышит?',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden wir hören?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн виа хёрен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы услышим?',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werdet ihr hören?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадет иа хёрен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы услышите? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden sie hören?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи хёрен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они услышат?',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden Sie hören?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи хёрен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы услышите? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'hören — слушать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich probiere',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их пробире',
  'phrase_ru': 'я пробую',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du probierst',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду пробирст',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты пробуешь',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er probiert',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа пробирт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он пробует',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie probiert',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи пробирт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она пробует',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es probiert',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс пробирт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно пробует',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir probieren',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа пробирен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы пробуем',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr probiert',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа пробирт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы пробуете (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie probieren',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи пробирен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они пробуют',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie probieren',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи пробирен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы пробуете (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich probiere nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их пробире нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не пробую',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du probierst nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду пробирст нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не пробуешь',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er probiert nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа пробирт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не пробует',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie probiert nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи пробирт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не пробует',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es probiert nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс пробирт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не пробует',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir probieren nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа пробирен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не пробуем',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr probiert nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа пробирт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не пробуете (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie probieren nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи пробирен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не пробуют',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie probieren nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи пробирен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не пробуете (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'probiere ich?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'пробире их',
  'phrase_ru': 'я пробую?',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'probierst du?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'пробирст ду',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты пробуешь?',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'probiert er?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'пробирт иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'он пробует?',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'probiert sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'пробирт зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'она пробует?',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'probiert es?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'пробирт эс',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно пробует?',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'probieren wir?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'пробирен виа',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы пробуем?',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'probiert ihr?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'пробирт иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы пробуете? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'probieren sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'пробирен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'они пробуют?',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'probieren Sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'пробирен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы пробуете? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe probiert',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе пробирт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я пробовал',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast probiert',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст пробирт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты пробовал',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat probiert',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат пробирт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он пробовал',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat probiert',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат пробирт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она пробовала',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat probiert',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат пробирт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно пробовало',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben probiert',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен пробирт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы пробовали',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt probiert',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт пробирт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы пробовали (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben probiert',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен пробирт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они пробовали',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben probiert',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен пробирт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы пробовали (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe nicht probiert',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе нихт пробирт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не пробовал',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast nicht probiert',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст нихт пробирт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не пробовал',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat nicht probiert',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат нихт пробирт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не пробовал',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat nicht probiert',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат нихт пробирт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не пробовала',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat nicht probiert',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат нихт пробирт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не пробовало',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben nicht probiert',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен нихт пробирт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не пробовали',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt nicht probiert',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт нихт пробирт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не пробовали (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben nicht probiert',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт пробирт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не пробовали',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben nicht probiert',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт пробирт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не пробовали (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habe ich probiert?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабе их пробирт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я пробовал?',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hast du probiert?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хаст ду пробирт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты пробовал?',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat er probiert?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат иа пробирт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он пробовал?',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat sie probiert?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат зи пробирт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она пробовала?',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat es probiert?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат эс пробирт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно пробовало?',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben wir probiert?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен виа пробирт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы пробовали?',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habt ihr probiert?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабт иа пробирт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы пробовали? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben sie probiert?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи пробирт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они пробовали?',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben Sie probiert?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи пробирт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы пробовали? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde probieren',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде пробирен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я буду пробовать',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst probieren',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст пробирен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты будешь пробовать',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird probieren',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд пробирен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он будет пробовать',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird probieren',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд пробирен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она будет пробовать',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird probieren',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд пробирен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно будет пробовать',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden probieren',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн пробирен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы будем пробовать',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet probieren',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет пробирен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы будете пробовать (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden probieren',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн пробирен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они будут пробовать',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden probieren',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн пробирен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы будете пробовать (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde nicht probieren',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде нихт пробирен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не буду пробовать',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst nicht probieren',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст нихт пробирен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не будешь пробовать',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird nicht probieren',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд нихт пробирен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не будет пробовать',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird nicht probieren',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд нихт пробирен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не будет пробовать',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird nicht probieren',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд нихт пробирен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не будет пробовать',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden nicht probieren',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн нихт пробирен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не будем пробовать',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet nicht probieren',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет нихт пробирен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не будете пробовать (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden nicht probieren',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт пробирен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не будут пробовать',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden nicht probieren',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт пробирен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не будете пробовать (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werde ich probieren?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веаде их пробирен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я буду пробовать?',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wirst du probieren?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вирст ду пробирен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты будешь пробовать?',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird er probieren?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд иа пробирен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он будет пробовать?',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird sie probieren?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд зи пробирен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она будет пробовать?',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird es probieren?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд эс пробирен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно будет пробовать?',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden wir probieren?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн виа пробирен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы будем пробовать?',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werdet ihr probieren?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадет иа пробирен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы будете пробовать? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden sie probieren?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи пробирен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они будут пробовать?',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden Sie probieren?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи пробирен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы будете пробовать? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'probieren — пробовать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich wohne',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их воне',
  'phrase_ru': 'я живу',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du wohnst',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вонст',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты живешь',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er wohnt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вонт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он живет',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wohnt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вонт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она живет',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es wohnt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вонт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно живет',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir wohnen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа вонен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы живем',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr wohnt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вонт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы живете (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wohnen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вонен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они живут',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie wohnen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вонен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы живете (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich wohne nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их воне нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не живу',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du wohnst nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вонст нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не живешь',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er wohnt nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вонт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не живет',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wohnt nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вонт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не живет',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es wohnt nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вонт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не живет',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir wohnen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа вонен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не живем',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr wohnt nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вонт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не живете (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wohnen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вонен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не живут',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie wohnen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вонен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не живете (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wohne ich?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'воне их',
  'phrase_ru': 'я живу?',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wohnst du?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вонст ду',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты живешь?',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wohnt er?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вонт иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'он живет?',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wohnt sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вонт зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'она живет?',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wohnt es?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вонт эс',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно живет?',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wohnen wir?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вонен виа',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы живем?',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wohnt ihr?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вонт иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы живете? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wohnen sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вонен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'они живут?',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wohnen Sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вонен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы живете? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe gewohnt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе гевонт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я жил',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast gewohnt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст гевонт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты жил',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat gewohnt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат гевонт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он жил',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat gewohnt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат гевонт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она жила',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat gewohnt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат гевонт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно жило',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben gewohnt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен гевонт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы жили',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt gewohnt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт гевонт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы жили (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben gewohnt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен гевонт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они жили',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben gewohnt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен гевонт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы жили (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe nicht gewohnt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе нихт гевонт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не жил',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast nicht gewohnt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст нихт гевонт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не жил',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat nicht gewohnt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат нихт гевонт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не жил',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat nicht gewohnt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат нихт гевонт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не жила',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat nicht gewohnt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат нихт гевонт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не жило',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben nicht gewohnt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен нихт гевонт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не жили',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt nicht gewohnt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт нихт гевонт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не жили (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben nicht gewohnt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт гевонт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не жили',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben nicht gewohnt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт гевонт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не жили (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habe ich gewohnt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабе их гевонт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я жил?',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hast du gewohnt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хаст ду гевонт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты жил?',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat er gewohnt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат иа гевонт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он жил?',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat sie gewohnt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат зи гевонт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она жила?',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat es gewohnt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат эс гевонт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно жило?',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben wir gewohnt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен виа гевонт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы жили?',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habt ihr gewohnt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабт иа гевонт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы жили? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben sie gewohnt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи гевонт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они жили?',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben Sie gewohnt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи гевонт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы жили? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde wohnen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде вонен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я буду жить',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst wohnen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст вонен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты будешь жить',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird wohnen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд вонен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он будет жить',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird wohnen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд вонен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она будет жить',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird wohnen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд вонен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно будет жить',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden wohnen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн вонен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы будем жить',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet wohnen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет вонен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы будете жить (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden wohnen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн вонен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они будут жить',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden wohnen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн вонен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы будете жить (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde nicht wohnen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде нихт вонен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не буду жить',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst nicht wohnen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст нихт вонен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не будешь жить',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird nicht wohnen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд нихт вонен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не будет жить',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird nicht wohnen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд нихт вонен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не будет жить',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird nicht wohnen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд нихт вонен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не будет жить',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden nicht wohnen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн нихт вонен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не будем жить',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet nicht wohnen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет нихт вонен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не будете жить (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden nicht wohnen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт вонен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не будут жить',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden nicht wohnen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт вонен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не будете жить (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werde ich wohnen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веаде их вонен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я буду жить?',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wirst du wohnen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вирст ду вонен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты будешь жить?',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird er wohnen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд иа вонен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он будет жить?',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird sie wohnen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд зи вонен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она будет жить?',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird es wohnen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд эс вонен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно будет жить?',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden wir wohnen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн виа вонен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы будем жить?',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werdet ihr wohnen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадет иа вонен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы будете жить? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden sie wohnen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи вонен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они будут жить?',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden Sie wohnen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи вонен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы будете жить? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'wohnen — жить,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich liebe',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их либе',
  'phrase_ru': 'я люблю',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du liebst',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду либст',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты любишь',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er liebt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа либт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он любит',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie liebt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи либт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она любит',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es liebt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс либт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно любит',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir lieben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа либен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы любим',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr liebt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа либт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы любите (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie lieben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи либен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они любят',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie lieben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи либен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы любите (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich liebe nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их либе нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не люблю',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du liebst nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду либст нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не любишь',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er liebt nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа либт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не любит',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie liebt nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи либт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не любит',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es liebt nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс либт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не любит',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir lieben nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа либен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не любим',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr liebt nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа либт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не любите (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie lieben nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи либен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не любят',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie lieben nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи либен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не любите (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'liebe ich?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'либе их',
  'phrase_ru': 'я люблю?',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'liebst du?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'либст ду',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты любишь?',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'liebt er?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'либт иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'он любит?',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'liebt sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'либт зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'она любит?',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'liebt es?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'либт эс',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно любит?',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'lieben wir?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'либен виа',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы любим?',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'liebt ihr?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'либт иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы любите (множественное число)?',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'lieben sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'либен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'они любят?',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'lieben Sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'либен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы любите (вежливая форма)?',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe geliebt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе гелибт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я любил',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast geliebt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст гелибт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты любил',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat geliebt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат гелибт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он любил',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat geliebt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат гелибт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она любила',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat geliebt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат гелибт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно любило',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben geliebt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен гелибт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы любили',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt geliebt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт гелибт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы любили (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben geliebt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен гелибт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они любили',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben geliebt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен гелибт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы любили (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe nicht geliebt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе нихт гелибт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не любил',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast nicht geliebt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст нихт гелибт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не любил',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat nicht geliebt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат нихт гелибт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не любил',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat nicht geliebt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат нихт гелибт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не любила',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat nicht geliebt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат нихт гелибт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не любило',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben nicht geliebt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен нихт гелибт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не любили',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt nicht geliebt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт нихт гелибт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не любили (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben nicht geliebt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт гелибт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не любили',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben nicht geliebt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт гелибт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не любили (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habe ich geliebt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабе их гелибт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я любил?',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hast du geliebt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хаст ду гелибт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты любил?',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat er geliebt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат иа гелибт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он любил?',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat sie geliebt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат зи гелибт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она любила?',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat es geliebt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат эс гелибт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно любило?',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben wir geliebt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен виа гелибт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы любили?',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habt ihr geliebt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабт иа гелибт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы любили? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben sie geliebt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи гелибт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они любили?',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben Sie geliebt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи гелибт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы любили? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde lieben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде либен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я буду любить',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst lieben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст либен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты будешь любить',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird lieben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд либен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он будет любить',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird lieben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд либен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она будет любить',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird lieben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд либен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно будет любить',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden lieben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн либен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы будем любить',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet lieben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет либен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы будете любить (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden lieben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн либен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они будут любить',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden lieben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн либен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы будете любить (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde nicht lieben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде нихт либен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не буду любить',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst nicht lieben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст нихт либен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не будешь любить',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird nicht lieben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд нихт либен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не будет любить',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird nicht lieben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд нихт либен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не будет любить',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird nicht lieben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд нихт либен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не будет любить',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden nicht lieben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн нихт либен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не будем любить',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet nicht lieben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет нихт либен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не будете любить (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden nicht lieben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт либен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не будут любить',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden nicht lieben',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт либен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не будете любить (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werde ich lieben?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веаде их либен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я буду любить?',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wirst du lieben?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вирст ду либен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты будешь любить?',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird er lieben?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд иа либен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он будет любить?',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird sie lieben?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд зи либен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она будет любить?',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird es lieben?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд эс либен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно будет любить?',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden wir lieben?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн виа либен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы будем любить?',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werdet ihr lieben?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадет иа либен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы будете любить? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden sie lieben?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи либен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они будут любить?',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden Sie lieben?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи либен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы будете любить? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'lieben — любить,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich zähle',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их целе',
  'phrase_ru': 'я считаю',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du zählst',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду цельст',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты считаешь',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er zählt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа цельт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он считает',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie zählt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи цельт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она считает',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es zählt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс цельт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно считает',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir zählen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа целен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы считаем',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr zählt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа цельт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы считаете (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie zählen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи целен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они считают',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie zählen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи целен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы считаете (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich zähle nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их целе нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не считаю',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du zählst nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду цельст нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не считаешь',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er zählt nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа цельт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не считает',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie zählt nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи цельт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не считает',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es zählt nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс цельт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не считает',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir zählen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа целен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не считаем',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr zählt nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа цельт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не считаете (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie zählen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи целен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не считают',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie zählen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи целен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не считаете (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'zähle ich?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'целе их',
  'phrase_ru': 'я считаю?',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'zählst du?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'цельст ду',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты считаешь?',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'zählt er?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'цельт иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'он считает?',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'zählt sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'цельт зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'она считает?',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'zählt es?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'цельт эс',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно считает?',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'zählen wir?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'целен виа',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы считаем?',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'zählt ihr?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'цельт иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы считаете? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'zählen sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'целен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'они считают?',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'zählen Sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'целен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы считаете? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe gezählt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе гецельт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я считал',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast gezählt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст гецельт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты считал',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat gezählt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат гецельт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он считал',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat gezählt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат гецельт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она считала',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat gezählt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат гецельт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно считало',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben gezählt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен гецельт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы считали',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt gezählt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт гецельт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы считали (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben gezählt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен гецельт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они считали',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben gezählt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен гецельт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы считали (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe nicht gezählt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе нихт гецельт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не считал',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast nicht gezählt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст нихт гецельт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не считал',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat nicht gezählt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат нихт гецельт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не считал',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat nicht gezählt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат нихт гецельт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не считала',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat nicht gezählt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат нихт гецельт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не считало',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben nicht gezählt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен нихт гецельт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не считали',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt nicht gezählt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт нихт гецельт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не считали (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben nicht gezählt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт гецельт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не считали',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben nicht gezählt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт гецельт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не считали (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habe ich gezählt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабе их гецельт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я считал?',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hast du gezählt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хаст ду гецельт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты считал?',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat er gezählt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат иа гецельт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он считал?',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat sie gezählt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат зи гецельт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она считала?',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat es gezählt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат эс гецельт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно считало?',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben wir gezählt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен виа гецельт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы считали?',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habt ihr gezählt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабт иа гецельт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы считали? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben sie gezählt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи гецельт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они считали?',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben Sie gezählt?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи гецельт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы считали? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde zählen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде целен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я буду считать',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst zählen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст целен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты будешь считать',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird zählen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд целен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он будет считать',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird zählen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд целен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она будет считать',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird zählen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд целен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно будет считать',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden zählen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн целен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы будем считать',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet zählen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет целен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы будете считать (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden zählen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн целен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они будут считать',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden zählen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн целен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы будете считать (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde nicht zählen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде нихт целен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не буду считать',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst nicht zählen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст нихт целен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не будешь считать',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird nicht zählen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд нихт целен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не будет считать',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird nicht zählen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд нихт целен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не будет считать',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird nicht zählen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд нихт целен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не будет считать',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden nicht zählen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн нихт целен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не будем считать',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet nicht zählen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет нихт целен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не будете считать (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden nicht zählen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт целен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не будут считать',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden nicht zählen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт целен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не будете считать (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werde ich zählen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веаде их целен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я буду считать?',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wirst du zählen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вирст ду целен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты будешь считать?',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird er zählen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд иа целен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он будет считать?',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird sie zählen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд зи целен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она будет считать?',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird es zählen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд эс целен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно будет считать?',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden wir zählen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн виа целен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы будем считать?',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werdet ihr zählen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадет иа целен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы будете считать? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden sie zählen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи целен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они будут считать?',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden Sie zählen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи целен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы будете считать? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'zählen — считать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich suche',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их зухе',
  'phrase_ru': 'я ищу',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du suchst',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду зухст',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты ищешь',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er sucht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа зухт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он ищет',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie sucht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи зухт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она ищет',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es sucht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс зухт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно ищет',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir suchen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа зухен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы ищем',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr sucht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа зухт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы ищете (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie suchen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи зухен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они ищут',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie suchen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи зухен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы ищете (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich suche nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их зухе нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не ищу',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du suchst nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду зухст нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не ищешь',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er sucht nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа зухт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не ищет',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie sucht nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи зухт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не ищет',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es sucht nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс зухт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не ищет',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir suchen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа зухен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не ищем',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr sucht nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа зухт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не ищете (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie suchen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи зухен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не ищут',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie suchen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи зухен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не ищете (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'suche ich?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зухе их',
  'phrase_ru': 'я ищу?',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'suchst du?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зухст ду',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты ищешь?',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sucht er?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зухт иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'он ищет?',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sucht sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зухт зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'она ищет?',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sucht es?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зухт эс',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно ищет?',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'suchen wir?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зухен виа',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы ищем?',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sucht ihr?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зухт иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы ищете? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'suchen sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зухен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'они ищут?',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'suchen Sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зухен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы ищете? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe gesucht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе гезухт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я искал',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast gesucht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст гезухт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты искал',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat gesucht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат гезухт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он искал',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat gesucht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат гезухт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она искала',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat gesucht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат гезухт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно искало',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben gesucht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен гезухт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы искали',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt gesucht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт гезухт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы искали (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben gesucht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен гезухт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они искали',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben gesucht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен гезухт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы искали (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe nicht gesucht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе нихт гезухт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не искал',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast nicht gesucht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст нихт гезухт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не искал',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat nicht gesucht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат нихт гезухт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не искал',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat nicht gesucht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат нихт гезухт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не искала',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat nicht gesucht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат нихт гезухт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не искало',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben nicht gesucht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен нихт гезухт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не искали',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt nicht gesucht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт нихт гезухт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не искали (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben nicht gesucht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт гезухт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не искали',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben nicht gesucht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт гезухт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не искали (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habe ich gesucht?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабе их гезухт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я искал?',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hast du gesucht?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хаст ду гезухт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты искал?',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat er gesucht?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат иа гезухт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он искал?',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat sie gesucht?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат зи гезухт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она искала?',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat es gesucht?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат эс гезухт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно искало?',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben wir gesucht?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен виа гезухт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы искали?',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habt ihr gesucht?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабт иа гезухт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы искали? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben sie gesucht?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи гезухт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они искали?',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben Sie gesucht?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи гезухт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы искали? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde suchen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде зухен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я буду искать',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst suchen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст зухен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты будешь искать',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird suchen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд зухен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он будет искать',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird suchen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд зухен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она будет искать',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird suchen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд зухен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно будет искать',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden suchen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн зухен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы будем искать',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet suchen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет зухен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы будете искать (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden suchen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн зухен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они будут искать',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden suchen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн зухен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы будете искать (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde nicht suchen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде нихт зухен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не буду искать',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst nicht suchen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст нихт зухен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не будешь искать',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird nicht suchen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд нихт зухен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не будет искать',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird nicht suchen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд нихт зухен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не будет искать',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird nicht suchen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд нихт зухен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не будет искать',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden nicht suchen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн нихт зухен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не будем искать',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet nicht suchen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет нихт зухен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не будете искать (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden nicht suchen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт зухен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не будут искать',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden nicht suchen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт зухен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не будете искать (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werde ich suchen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веаде их зухен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я буду искать?',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wirst du suchen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вирст ду зухен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты будешь искать?',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird er suchen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд иа зухен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он будет искать?',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird sie suchen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд зи зухен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она будет искать?',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird es suchen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд эс зухен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно будет искать?',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden wir suchen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн виа зухен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы будем искать?',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werdet ihr suchen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадет иа зухен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы будете искать? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden sie suchen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи зухен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они будут искать?',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden Sie suchen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи зухен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы будете искать? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'suchen — искать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich singe',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их зинге',
  'phrase_ru': 'я пою',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du singst',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду зингст',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты поёшь',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er singt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа зингт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он поёт',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie singt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи зингт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она поёт',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es singt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс зингт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно поёт',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir singen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа зинген',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы поём',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr singt',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа зингт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы поёте (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie singen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи зинген',
  'phrase_ru': 'они поют',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie singen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи зинген',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы поёте (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich singe nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их зинге нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не пою',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du singst nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду зингст нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не поёшь',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er singt nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа зингт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не поёт',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie singt nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи зингт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не поёт',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es singt nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс зингт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не поёт',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir singen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа зинген нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не поём',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr singt nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа зингт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не поёте (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie singen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи зинген нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не поют',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie singen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи зинген нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не поёте (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'singe ich?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зинге их',
  'phrase_ru': 'я пою?',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'singst du?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зингст ду',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты поёшь?',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'singt er?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зингт иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'он поёт?',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'singt sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зингт зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'она поёт?',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'singt es?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зингт эс',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно поёт?',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'singen wir?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зинген виа',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы поём?',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'singt ihr?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зингт иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы поёте? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'singen sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зинген зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'они поют?',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'singen Sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зинген зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы поёте? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe gesungen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе гезунген',
  'phrase_ru': 'я пел',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast gesungen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст гезунген',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты пел',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat gesungen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат гезунген',
  'phrase_ru': 'он пел',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat gesungen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат гезунген',
  'phrase_ru': 'она пела',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat gesungen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат гезунген',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно пело',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben gesungen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен гезунген',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы пели',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt gesungen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт гезунген',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы пели (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben gesungen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен гезунген',
  'phrase_ru': 'они пели',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben gesungen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен гезунген',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы пели (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe nicht gesungen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе нихт гезунген',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не пел',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast nicht gesungen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст нихт гезунген',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не пел',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat nicht gesungen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат нихт гезунген',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не пел',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat nicht gesungen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат нихт гезунген',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не пела',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat nicht gesungen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат нихт гезунген',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не пело',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben nicht gesungen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен нихт гезунген',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не пели',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt nicht gesungen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт нихт гезунген',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не пели (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben nicht gesungen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт гезунген',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не пели',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben nicht gesungen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт гезунген',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не пели (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habe ich gesungen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабе их гезунген',
  'phrase_ru': 'я пел?',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hast du gesungen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хаст ду гезунген',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты пел?',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat er gesungen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат иа гезунген',
  'phrase_ru': 'он пел?',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat sie gesungen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат зи гезунген',
  'phrase_ru': 'она пела?',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat es gesungen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат эс гезунген',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно пело?',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben wir gesungen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен виа гезунген',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы пели?',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habt ihr gesungen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабт иа гезунген',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы пели? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben sie gesungen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи гезунген',
  'phrase_ru': 'они пели?',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben Sie gesungen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи гезунген',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы пели? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde singen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде зинген',
  'phrase_ru': 'я буду петь',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst singen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст зинген',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты будешь петь',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird singen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд зинген',
  'phrase_ru': 'он будет петь',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird singen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд зинген',
  'phrase_ru': 'она будет петь',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird singen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд зинген',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно будет петь',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden singen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн зинген',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы будем петь',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet singen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет зинген',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы будете петь (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden singen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн зинген',
  'phrase_ru': 'они будут петь',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden singen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн зинген',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы будете петь (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde nicht singen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде нихт зинген',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не буду петь',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst nicht singen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст нихт зинген',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не будешь петь',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird nicht singen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд нихт зинген',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не будет петь',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird nicht singen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд нихт зинген',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не будет петь',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird nicht singen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд нихт зинген',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не будет петь',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden nicht singen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн нихт зинген',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не будем петь',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet nicht singen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет нихт зинген',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не будете петь (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden nicht singen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт зинген',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не будут петь',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden nicht singen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт зинген',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не будете петь (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werde ich singen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веаде их зинген',
  'phrase_ru': 'я буду петь?',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wirst du singen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вирст ду зинген',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты будешь петь?',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird er singen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд иа зинген',
  'phrase_ru': 'он будет петь?',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird sie singen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд зи зинген',
  'phrase_ru': 'она будет петь?',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird es singen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд эс зинген',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно будет петь?',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden wir singen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн виа зинген',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы будем петь?',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werdet ihr singen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадет иа зинген',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы будете петь? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden sie singen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи зинген',
  'phrase_ru': 'они будут петь?',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden Sie singen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи зинген',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы будете петь? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'singen — петь,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich ruhe',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их руе',
  'phrase_ru': 'я отдыхаю',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du ruhst',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду руст',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты отдыхаешь',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er ruht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа рут',
  'phrase_ru': 'он отдыхает',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie ruht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи рут',
  'phrase_ru': 'она отдыхает',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es ruht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс рут',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно отдыхает',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir ruhen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа руен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы отдыхаем',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr ruht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа рут',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы отдыхаете (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie ruhen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи руен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они отдыхают',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie ruhen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи руен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы отдыхаете (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich ruhe nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их руе нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не отдыхаю',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du ruhst nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду руст нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не отдыхаешь',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er ruht nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа рут нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не отдыхает',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie ruht nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи рут нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не отдыхает',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es ruht nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс рут нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не отдыхает',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir ruhen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа руен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не отдыхаем',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr ruht nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа рут нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не отдыхаете (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie ruhen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи руен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не отдыхают',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie ruhen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи руен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не отдыхаете (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ruhe ich?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'руе их',
  'phrase_ru': 'я отдыхаю?',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ruhst du?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'руст ду',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты отдыхаешь?',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ruht er?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'рут иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'он отдыхает?',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ruht sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'рут зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'она отдыхает?',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ruht es?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'рут эс',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно отдыхает?',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ruhen wir?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'руен виа',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы отдыхаем?',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ruht ihr?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'рут иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы отдыхаете? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ruhen sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'руен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'они отдыхают?',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ruhen Sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'руен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы отдыхаете? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe geruht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе герут',
  'phrase_ru': 'я отдыхал',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast geruht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст герут',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты отдыхал',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat geruht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат герут',
  'phrase_ru': 'он отдыхал',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat geruht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат герут',
  'phrase_ru': 'она отдыхала',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat geruht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат герут',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно отдыхало',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben geruht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен герут',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы отдыхали',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt geruht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт герут',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы отдыхали (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben geruht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен герут',
  'phrase_ru': 'они отдыхали',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben geruht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен герут',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы отдыхали (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe nicht geruht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе нихт герут',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не отдыхал',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast nicht geruht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст нихт герут',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не отдыхал',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat nicht geruht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат нихт герут',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не отдыхал',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat nicht geruht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат нихт герут',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не отдыхала',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat nicht geruht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат нихт герут',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не отдыхало',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben nicht geruht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен нихт герут',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не отдыхали',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt nicht geruht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт нихт герут',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не отдыхали (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben nicht geruht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт герут',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не отдыхали',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben nicht geruht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт герут',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не отдыхали (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habe ich geruht?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабе их герут',
  'phrase_ru': 'я отдыхал?',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hast du geruht?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хаст ду герут',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты отдыхал?',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat er geruht?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат иа герут',
  'phrase_ru': 'он отдыхал?',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat sie geruht?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат зи герут',
  'phrase_ru': 'она отдыхала?',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat es geruht?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат эс герут',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно отдыхало?',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben wir geruht?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен виа герут',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы отдыхали?',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habt ihr geruht?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабт иа герут',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы отдыхали? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben sie geruht?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи герут',
  'phrase_ru': 'они отдыхали?',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben Sie geruht?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи герут',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы отдыхали? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde ruhen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде руен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я буду отдыхать',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst ruhen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст руен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты будешь отдыхать',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird ruhen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд руен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он будет отдыхать',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird ruhen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд руен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она будет отдыхать',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird ruhen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд руен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно будет отдыхать',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden ruhen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн руен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы будем отдыхать',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet ruhen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет руен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы будете отдыхать (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden ruhen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн руен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они будут отдыхать',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden ruhen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн руен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы будете отдыхать (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde nicht ruhen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде нихт руен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не буду отдыхать',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst nicht ruhen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст нихт руен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не будешь отдыхать',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird nicht ruhen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд нихт руен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не будет отдыхать',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird nicht ruhen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд нихт руен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не будет отдыхать',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird nicht ruhen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд нихт руен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не будет отдыхать',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden nicht ruhen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн нихт руен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не будем отдыхать',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet nicht ruhen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет нихт руен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не будете отдыхать (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden nicht ruhen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт руен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не будут отдыхать',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden nicht ruhen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт руен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не будете отдыхать (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werde ich ruhen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веаде их руен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я буду отдыхать?',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wirst du ruhen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вирст ду руен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты будешь отдыхать?',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird er ruhen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд иа руен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он будет отдыхать?',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird sie ruhen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд зи руен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она будет отдыхать?',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird es ruhen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд эс руен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно будет отдыхать?',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden wir ruhen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн виа руен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы будем отдыхать?',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werdet ihr ruhen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадет иа руен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы будете отдыхать? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden sie ruhen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи руен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они будут отдыхать?',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden Sie ruhen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи руен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы будете отдыхать? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'ruhen — отдыхать,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich wasche',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их ваше',
  'phrase_ru': 'я мою',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du wäschst',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вешст',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты моешь',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er wäscht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вешт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он моет',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wäscht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вешт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она моет',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es wäscht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вешт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно моет',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir waschen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа вашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы моем',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr wascht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вешт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы моете (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie waschen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они моют',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie waschen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы моете (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Präsens (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ich wasche nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их ваше нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не мою',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'du wäschst nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вешст нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не моешь',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'er wäscht nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вешт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не моет',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wäscht nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вешт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не моет',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'es wäscht nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вешт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не моет',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'wir waschen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа вашен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не моем',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr wascht nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вешт нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не моете (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'sie waschen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вашен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не моют',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '1',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie waschen nicht',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вашен нихт',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не моете (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Präsens (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wasche ich?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ваше их',
  'phrase_ru': 'я мою?',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wäschst du?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вешст ду',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты моешь?',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wäscht er?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вешт иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'он моет?',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wäscht sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вешт зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'она моет?',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wäscht es?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вешт эс',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно моет?',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'waschen wir?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вашен виа',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы моем?',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wascht ihr?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вешт иа',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы моете? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'waschen sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вашен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'они моют?',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'waschen Sie?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вашен зи',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы моете? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Präsens (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe gewaschen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе гевашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я мыл',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast gewaschen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст гевашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты мыл',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat gewaschen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат гевашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он мыл',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat gewaschen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат гевашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она мыла',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat gewaschen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат гевашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно мыло',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben gewaschen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен гевашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы мыли',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt gewaschen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт гевашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы мыли (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben gewaschen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен гевашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они мыли',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben gewaschen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен гевашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы мыли (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Perfekt (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ich habe nicht gewaschen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их хабе нихт гевашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не мыл',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'du hast nicht gewaschen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду хаст нихт гевашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не мыл',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'er hat nicht gewaschen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хат нихт гевашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не мыл',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie hat nicht gewaschen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хат нихт гевашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не мыла',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'es hat nicht gewaschen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс хат нихт гевашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не мыло',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'wir haben nicht gewaschen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа хабен нихт гевашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не мыли',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr habt nicht gewaschen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа хабт нихт гевашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не мыли (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'sie haben nicht gewaschen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт гевашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не мыли',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '2',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie haben nicht gewaschen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи хабен нихт гевашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не мыли (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Perfekt (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habe ich gewaschen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабе их гевашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я мыл?',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hast du gewaschen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хаст ду гевашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты мыл?',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat er gewaschen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат иа гевашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он мыл?',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat sie gewaschen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат зи гевашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она мыла?',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'hat es gewaschen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хат эс гевашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно мыло?',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben wir gewaschen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен виа гевашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы мыли?',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'habt ihr gewaschen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабт иа гевашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы мыли? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben sie gewaschen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи гевашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они мыли?',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'haben Sie gewaschen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'хабен зи гевашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы мыли? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Perfekt (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde waschen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде вашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я буду мыть',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst waschen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст вашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты будешь мыть',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird waschen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд вашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он будет мыть',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird waschen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд вашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она будет мыть',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird waschen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд вашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно будет мыть',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden waschen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн вашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы будем мыть',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet waschen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет вашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы будете мыть (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden waschen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн вашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они будут мыть',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden waschen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн вашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы будете мыть (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Futur I (Positive)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ich werde nicht waschen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'их веаде нихт вашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я не буду мыть',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'du wirst nicht waschen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'ду вирст нихт вашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты не будешь мыть',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'er wird nicht waschen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа вёд нихт вашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он не будет мыть',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie wird nicht waschen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи вёд нихт вашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она не будет мыть',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'es wird nicht waschen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'эс вёд нихт вашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно не будет мыть',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wir werden nicht waschen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'виа веадн нихт вашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы не будем мыть',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'ihr werdet nicht waschen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'иа веадет нихт вашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы не будете мыть (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'sie werden nicht waschen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт вашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они не будут мыть',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'Sie werden nicht waschen',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'зи веадн нихт вашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы не будете мыть (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Futur I (Negation)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werde ich waschen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веаде их вашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'я буду мыть?',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wirst du waschen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вирст ду вашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'ты будешь мыть?',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird er waschen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд иа вашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'он будет мыть?',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird sie waschen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд зи вашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'она будет мыть?',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'wird es waschen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'вёд эс вашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'оно будет мыть?',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden wir waschen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн виа вашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'мы будем мыть?',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werdet ihr waschen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадет иа вашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'вы будете мыть? (множественное число)',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden sie waschen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи вашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'они будут мыть?',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Futur I (Fragesätze)'},
 {'dict': 'basis',
  'dict_type': 'phrases',
  'level': '3',
  'phrase_de': 'werden Sie waschen?',
  'phrase_de_trans': 'веадн зи вашен',
  'phrase_ru': 'Вы будете мыть? (вежливая форма)',
  'prompt': 'waschen — мыть,Futur I (Fragesätze)'}]
